I think a lot of people don't realize
我认为很多人都没有意识到这一点。
how massive the positive impact AI is
人工智能的积极影响有多大？
going to have on their life. Well, I
这将对他们的生活产生影响。嗯，我
would argue that the idea that this AI
有人会认为，人工智能的概念是错误的。
disruption doesn't lead us to human
颠覆并不会让我们走向人性化
catastrophe is optimistic. For example,
灾难也是乐观的。例如，
people are going to be unemployed in
人们将会失业
huge numbers. You agree with that, don't
数量巨大。你同意这一点，对吧？
you? Yes. If your job is as routine as
你？是的。如果你的工作像……一样单调乏味
it comes, it's gone in the next couple
它来了，接下来的几周就没了。
years. But it's going to create new
年。但这将创造新的
opportunities for wealth creation. Let
创造财富的机会。让
me put it to you this way. We have
我这么说吧。我们有
created a new species and nobody on
创造了一个新物种，而且没有人……
earth can predict what's going to
地球可以预测将会发生什么
happen. We are joined by three leading
发生。我们邀请到了三位领军人物。
voices to debate the most disruptive
参与辩论的最具破坏性的声音
shift in human history, the rise of AI.
人类历史的转折点，人工智能的崛起。
And they're answering the questions
他们正在回答这些问题。
you're most scared about. This
你最害怕的是什么？这
technology is going to get so much more
科技将会变得更加强大。
powerful. And yes, we're going to go
强大的。是的，我们要去
through a period of disruption. But at
经历了一段动荡时期。但是
the other end, we're going to create a
另一方面，我们将创建一个
fair world. It's enabling people to run
公平的世界。它使人们能够跑步
their businesses, make a lot of money,
他们的生意赚了很多钱，
and you can solve meaningful problems
你可以解决有意义的问题
such as the breakthroughs in global
例如全球范围内的突破
healthcare and education will be
医疗保健和教育将是
phenomenal. and you can live an
太棒了。你可以过上……
incredibly fulfilling existence. Well, I
无比充实的人生。嗯，我
would just say on that front, this has
就这一点而言，我只想说，这方面已经……
always been the fantasy of technologists
一直是技术人员的幻想
to do marvelous things with our spare
利用我们的闲置资金做些奇妙的事情
time, but we end up doom scrolling,
时间有限，但我们最终却陷入了无休止的负面信息滚动浏览。
loneliness epidemic, right? Falling
孤独症流行，对吧？坠落
birth rates. So, the potential for good
出生率。所以，善的潜力
here is infinite and the potential for
这里蕴藏着无限的可能
bad is 10 times. For example, there's
坏的程度是10倍。例如，有
war, undetectable beat fakes and scams.
战争，难以察觉的打击虚假和诈骗。
So, people don't understand how many
所以，人们不明白有多少
different ways they are going to be
它们将以不同的方式出现
robbed. Look, I don't think blaming
被抢劫了。你看，我不认为应该责怪别人。
technology for all of it is the right
对所有人来说，技术都是正确的。
thing. all these issues, they're already
事物。所有这些问题，它们都已经存在了。
here. You're all fathers here. So, what
这里。你们都是父亲。所以呢
are you saying to your children? Well,
你是对你的孩子说的吗？出色地，
first of all, this has always blown my
首先，这件事一直让我震惊不已。
mind a little bit. 53% of you that
稍微介意一下。 53% 的人
listen to this show regularly haven't
我以前经常听这个节目。
yet subscribed to the show. So, could I
但已订阅该节目。那么，我可以吗？
ask you for a favor before we start? If
开始之前，我能请你帮个忙吗？如果
you like the show and you like what we
你喜欢这个节目，也喜欢我们所做的一切。
do here and you want to support us, the
在这里做这件事，并且你想支持我们，
free simple way that you can do just
免费且简单的方法，您可以轻松做到
that is by hitting the subscribe button.
也就是点击订阅按钮。
And my commitment to you is if you do
我对你的承诺是，如果你这样做
that, then I'll do everything in my
那样的话，我就会做我的一切。
power, me and my team, to make sure that
我和我的团队拥有权力，以确保
this show is better for you every single
这个节目对你来说更好！
week. We'll listen to your feedback.
星期。我们会认真听取您的反馈意见。
We'll find the guest that you want me to
我们会找到您想让我邀请的客人。
speak to and we'll continue to do what
我们会继续沟通并执行相关程序。
we do. Thank you so
是的。非常感谢
[Music]
[音乐]
much. The reason why I wanted to have
很多。我想要拥有的原因是
this conversation with all of you is
与各位的这次谈话是
because the subject matter of AI, but
因为人工智能的主题是……
more specifically AI agents, has
更具体地说，人工智能代理拥有
occupied my free time for several weeks
占据了我好几个星期的空闲时间。
in a row. And actually amad when I
连续。实际上我很生气，当我
started using replet for me it was a
开始使用reple对我来说是一个
paradigm shift. There was two paradigm
范式转变。有两种范式
shifts in a row that happened about a
连续发生的几次换班大约在……
week apart. Chat GPT released their
相隔一周。 Chat GPT 发布了他们的
image generation model where you could
图像生成模型，您可以在其中……
create any image. It was incredibly
创建任意图像。真是太棒了
detailed with text and all those things.
包含详细的文字说明等等。
That was a huge paradigm shift. And then
那真是一次巨大的范式转变。进而
in the same week I finally gave in to
就在同一周，我最终屈服了
try and figure out what this term AI
试着弄明白“人工智能”这个词是什么意思。
agent was that I was hearing all over
经纪人就是我一直听到的那个人
the internet. I heard vibe coding. I
互联网。我听到了“氛围编码”这个词。我
heard AI agent. I was like I will give
听到了人工智能代理的声音。我当时想，我会给
it a shot. Mhm. And when I used Replet,
试一试。嗯。当我使用Replet时，
20 minutes in to using Replet, my mind
使用 Replet 20 分钟后，我的大脑
was blown. And I think that night I
被炸了。我想那天晚上我
stayed up till 3 or 4 a.m. in the
熬夜到凌晨三四点
morning. For anyone that doesn't know,
早晨。对于不了解的人来说，
Replet is a piece of software that
Replet 是一款软件，
allows you to create software. Mhm. And
允许您创建软件。嗯。和
pretty much any software you you want.
几乎任何你想要的软件。
So someone like me with absolutely no
所以像我这样完全没有
coding skills was able to build a
凭借编程技能，能够构建一个
website, build in Stripe, take payment,
网站，内置 Stripe，用于收款，
integrate AI into my website, add Google
将人工智能集成到我的网站，添加谷歌
login to the front of my website and do
登录到我的网站前端并执行以下操作
it within minutes. I then got the piece
几分钟内就能完成。然后我拿到了那块碎片。
of software that I had built with no
我开发的软件没有任何
coding skills, sent it to my friends,
我学会了编程，并把它发给了我的朋友们。
and one of my friends put his credit
我的一位朋友把他的信用额度存了进去。
card in and paid. Amazing. So I just
刷卡并付款。惊人的。所以我就
launched a SAS company with no coding
创办了一家SAS公司，但我没有任何编程经验。
skills.
技能。
to demonstrate an AI agent in a very
为了演示人工智能代理，非常
simple way. I used an online AI agent
简单方法。我使用了一个在线人工智能代理。
called operator to order us all some
打电话给接线员，让我们都点些东西。
water from a CVS around the corner. The
从街角的CVS便利店买了瓶水。这
AI agent did everything end to end and
AI代理完成了所有工作，从头到尾都一手包办。
people will be watching on the screen.
人们会通过屏幕观看。
It put my credit card details and it
它输入了我的信用卡信息，而且
picked the water for me. It gave the
她帮我挑了水。它给予了
person a tip. It put some delivery notes
给某人小费。它附上了一些送货单
in at some point a guy is going to walk
总有一天，会有人走进来。
in. He has not interacted with a human.
他从未与人类接触过。
He's interacted with my AI agent. And I
他与我的人工智能代理进行了互动。我
just the reason I use this as an example
我之所以用这个例子，就是因为这个原因。
is again it was a paradigm shift moment
这又是一个范式转变的时刻。
for me when I heard about agents. Mhm.
我第一次听说经纪人的时候就被他们吸引了。嗯。
about a month ago and I went on and I
大约一个月前，我继续前进，然后我
ordered a bottle of electrolytes and
点了一瓶电解质饮料，
when it when my doorbell rang I freaked
门铃响的时候我吓坏了
out. I freaked out. But am who are you
出去。我吓坏了。但我是谁？
and what are you doing? So uh I started
你在做什么？所以，呃，我开始了。
programming at a very young age. You
从小就开始编程。你
know I I built my first business when I
我知道，我创办第一家公司的时候……
was a teenager. I used to go to uh
当时他还是个十几岁的少年。我以前常去……
internet cafes and program there. And I
网吧和那里的程序。我
realized that they don't have software
意识到他们没有软件
to manage the business. I was like oh
管理业务。我当时就想：哦
why don't you create accounts? I don't
为什么不创建账户呢？我不
have a server. It took me two years to
拥有一台服务器。我花了两年时间
build that piece of software. And that's
开发那款软件。就是这样。
sort of embedded in my mind this idea
这个想法似乎已经深深地印在我的脑海里了。
that hey like you know there there's a
嘿，你知道，那里有个
lot of people in the world with really
世界上有很多人都非常
amazing ideas especially in the context
很棒的想法，尤其是在这种语境下。
where they live in that allows them to
他们居住的地方允许他们
build uh businesses. However, the main
创建企业。然而，主要
source of uh friction between an idea
摩擦的来源，一种想法
and software or call it an idea and
以及软件，或者称之为想法。
wealth creation is u infrastructure is
财富创造就是你的基础设施是
physical infrastructure is a meaning a
实体基础设施是指
computer in front of you. It is um an
你面前的电脑。嗯……
internet connection. It is the set of
互联网连接。这是一组
tools and skills that you need to build
你需要具备的工具和技能来构建
that. If we make it so that anyone who
那。如果我们规定任何人
has ideas who who wants to solve
有想法的人想要解决问题
problems will be able to do it. I mean
问题将能够做到这一点。我是说
imagine the kind of world that we we
想象一下我们所处的世界
could live in where no one can be anyone
可以生活在一个没有人能成为任何人的地方
who has merit anyone who can think
有才华的人，任何会思考的人。
clearly anyone who can generate a lot of
显然，任何能够产生大量收益的人
ideas can generate wealth. I mean that's
创意可以创造财富。我的意思是，那是
an amazing world to live in right
这是一个多么美好的世界啊！
anywhere in the world. So with with
世界任何地方。所以，用
Replet the company that I started in
重振我创办的公司
2016 the the idea was like okay coding
2016 年，这个想法就像是：好吧，开始编程。
is difficult how do we solve coding and
这是一个难题，我们如何解决编码问题？
um we built every part of the process
嗯，我们构建了流程的每一个环节。
the hosting the code editor the only
托管代码编辑器是唯一
missing thing was the you know the AI
缺失的部分是，你知道的，人工智能。
agent and so over the past two years
经纪人，以及过去两年
we've been working on this AI agent that
我们一直在研究这个人工智能代理，
you can just you know similar since chat
你知道，聊天也能让你明白类似的道理。
GPT you know this revolution with Genai
GPT，你知道这场与Genai相关的革命
and you can just uh speak your ideas
你可以畅所欲言，说出你的想法。
into existence. I mean this starts you
使其存在。我的意思是，这要从你开始。
know sounding religious like this is
知道这样听起来很宗教化
like the you know the gods you know that
就像你知道的，神明，你知道的。
the myths that that um that humans have
那些关于人类的迷思
created they used to imagine a world
他们创造了一个他们曾经用来想象的世界
where you can you can be everywhere and
只要你有时间，你就能无处不在。
anywhere at once that's sort of the
同时在任何地方，这有点像是
internet and you can also speak your
互联网，你也可以用它说话
ideas into into existence and um you
将想法变为现实，嗯，你
know it's it's still early I think uh
我知道现在还早，我觉得……
replet agent is is a fantastic tool and
补货代理是一个非常棒的工具，
I think this technology is going to get
我认为这项技术将会得到发展。
so much more powerful
威力大得多
specifically what is an AI agent. I've
具体来说，什么是人工智能代理？我已经
got this um graph actually here which I
我这里有一张图表，嗯……
don't need to pass to any of you for you
不需要传给你们任何人。
to be able to see the growth of AI
能够见证人工智能的发展
agents. But this graph is Google search
代理人。但这张图表来自谷歌搜索结果
trend data. This also resembles our
趋势数据。这也与我们的情况类似。
revenue too.
收入也是如此。
Oh, okay. Right. The the water has
哦好的。正确的。水有
arrived. Hello. Thank you. You can come
到达的。你好。谢谢。你可以来
on in. Can I have a go, please? Yes.
可以吗？是的。
It's
它是
3951. Great. Thank you so much. Thank
3951. 太好了。太感谢了。感谢
you. Thank you. I mean this is this is
你。谢谢。我的意思是，这就是这个
like a supernatural kind of power. You
就像一种超自然的力量。你
conjured water. I conjured water from my
变出水来。我从我的
mind. Yeah. And it's shown up here with
头脑。是的。它在这里也出现了
us and it clearly thinks we need a lot.
它显然认为我们需要很多东西。
But but just to define the term AI agent
但是，为了定义“人工智能代理”这个术语，我们先来谈谈它。
for someone that's never heard the term
对于从未听说过这个词的人来说
before. Yeah. Yeah. So uh I assume most
前。是的。是的。所以，呃，我假设大多数
of the audience now are familiar with
现在的观众都很熟悉
chat, right? You can go in and you can
聊天，对吧？你可以进去，而且你可以
talk to an AI. It can search the web for
与人工智能对话。它可以搜索网络
you. It has a limited amount of tools.
你。它拥有的工具数量有限。
Uh maybe it can call a calculator to do
嗯，或许它可以调用计算器来做这件事。
some addition subtraction for you, but
给你加一些减法，但是
that's about it. It's a request response
差不多就是这样。这是一个请求响应
style. Agents are when you give it a
风格。代理人就是当你给予它的时候
request and they can work indefinitely
提出请求后，他们可以无限期地工作。
until they achieve a goal or they run
直到他们达成目标或跑完为止
into an error and they need your help.
他们犯了一个错误，需要你的帮助。
It's an AI bot that has access to tools.
这是一个拥有工具访问权限的人工智能机器人。
Those tools are access to the to a web
这些工具可以访问网络
browser like operator, access to a
类似浏览器的运算符，访问
programming environment say like replet,
编程环境就像重复一样，
access to um you know credit cards. The
获取信用卡的使用权限。这
more tools you give the agent, the more
你给经纪人的工具越多，他们就越……
powerful it is. Of course there's all
它威力强大。当然，这一切都有。
these consideration around security and
这些关于安全性的考虑
safety and all of that stuff. But uh the
安全之类的东西。但是，呃……
the most important thing is the AI agent
最重要的是人工智能代理。
will determine when it finished
将决定何时结束
executing. Uh today AI agents can run
正在执行。嗯，如今人工智能代理可以运行
for anywhere between you know 30 seconds
大约30秒左右
to 30 minutes. Uh there's a recent paper
至30分钟。嗯，最近有一篇论文
that came out that's showing that every
这表明，每一个
7 months the number of minutes that the
7个月，分钟数
agent can run for is doubling. So we're
代理运行时间翻倍。所以我们是
at like 30 minutes now. In seven months
大概还有30分钟。七个月
we're going to be at an hour then you
我们到一小时后就到你那里了
know 2 hours. Pretty soon we're going to
知道2个小时。很快我们就要……
be at days. And at that point, you know,
几天后。到了那个时候，你知道，
AI agent is doing labor is doing kind of
AI代理正在执行某种劳动任务。
humanlike labor and actually uh OpenAI's
类似人类的劳动，实际上还有 OpenAI 的
new model 03 beat the expectation. So it
新款03型超出了预期。所以它
it sort of doubled coherence over long
它在某种程度上使连贯性在长期内提高了一倍。
horizon tasks in just three or four
只需三四个任务即可完成地平线任务
months. So we're in this massive and I
几个月。所以我们身处这个庞大的环境中，而且我
mean this looks this exponential graph,
这意味着它看起来像一个指数曲线图，
you know, that shows you the massive
你知道，这向你展示了巨大的
trend we're on.
我们正在追随的趋势。
Brett, give us a little bit of of your
布雷特，给我们讲讲你的一些事吧。
background, but also I saw you writing
背景，但我还看到你在写
some notes there. There was a couple of
这里有一些备注。有几个
words used there that I thought were
那里使用的词语，我认为是
quite interesting, especially
很有意思，尤其
considering what I know about you. The
考虑到我对你的了解。这
word God was used a few times.
“上帝”一词出现了几次。
Well, uh, let me just say I'm an
嗯，呃，我只想说我是一个
evolutionary biologist, and probably for
进化生物学家，而且很可能……
the purposes of this conversation, it
这次谈话的目的，它
would be best to think of me as a
最好把我当成一个……
complex systems theorist. One of the
复杂系统理论家。中的一个
things that I believe is true about AI
关于人工智能，我有一些真实的看法。
is that this is the first time that we
这是第一次
have built machines that have crossed
已经制造出能够跨越障碍的机器
the threshold from the highly
高度的阈值
complicated into the truly complex.
复杂到真正复杂。
And I will say I'm listening to this
我会说我正在听这个。
conversation with a um a a mixture of
与……的对话，嗯，混合了……
profound hope and dread
深切的希望与恐惧
because seems to me that it is obvious
因为在我看来，这显而易见。
that the potential good that can come
可能带来的潜在好处
from this technology is effectively
这项技术有效地
infinite. But I would say that the harm
无限的。但我认为，这种伤害是无害的。
is probably 10 times. It's a bigger
大概是10倍。它更大
infinity. And the question of how we are
无穷大。以及我们如何存在的问题
going to get to a place where we can
我们将到达一个我们可以……的地方
leverage the obvious power that is here
充分利用这里显而易见的力量
to do good and dodge the worst harms. I
行善避恶。我
have no idea. I I know we're not
完全没有头绪。我知道我们不是
prepared. So I hear you talking about
准备好了。我听你在谈论……
agents and I think um that's marvelous.
经纪人们，我觉得这太棒了。
We can all use such a thing right away
我们都可以立即使用这样的东西。
and the more powerful it is, the better.
而且功率越大越好。
The idea of something that can solve
能够解决问题的想法
problems on your behalf while you're
在您遇到问题时，我们会代表您处理这些问题。
doing something else is marvelous. But
做其他事情也很棒。但
of course, that is the precondition for
当然，这是前提条件。
absolute devastation to arise out of a
绝对的毁灭性后果源于
miscommunication, right? to have
是沟通误会吧？拥有
something acting autonomously to
某种自主行动的事物
accomplish a goal, you damn well better
要想达成目标，你最好
understand what the goal really is and
明白真正的目标是什么；
how to how to pull back the reins that
如何如何收回缰绳
it starts accomplishing something that
它开始完成某件事
wasn't the goal. The potential for abuse
这不是目标。滥用的可能性
is also utterly profound. You know, you
也极其深刻。你知道，你
can imagine, just pick your your dark
想象一下，只要选择你的黑暗系
mirror
镜子
uh fantasy dystopia where something has
呃，奇幻反乌托邦，其中有一些东西……
been told to hunt you down until you're
有人命令他们追捕你，直到你……
dead and it sees that as a, you know, a
死了，它把那看作是，你知道的，一个
technical challenge.
技术难题。
So, I don't know quite how
所以，我不太清楚该怎么做。
to balance a discussion about all of the
为了平衡对所有问题的讨论
things that can clearly come from this
由此显然可以产生以下结果
that are utterly transcendent. I mean, I
完全超凡脱俗的。我的意思是，我
do think it is not inappropriate to be
我认为这并不不合适
invoking God or biblical metaphors here.
这里援引了上帝或圣经中的比喻。
You know, you're uh producing water
你知道，你正在生产水。
seemingly from thin air. I believe that
仿佛凭空出现。我相信
does have an exact biblical parallel.
确实有完全对应的圣经版本。
Uh so, uh any case, the the power is
呃，总之，权力是
here, but so so too is the need for
这里，但对……的需求也是如此。
cautionary tales, which we don't have.
我们没有这样的警示故事。
That's the problem is that there's no
问题就在于没有
body of myth that will warn us properly
神话体系将正确地警示我们。
of this tool because we've just crossed
因为我们刚刚跨越了……，所以需要使用这个工具。
a threshold that is similar in its
一个类似的阈值
capacity to alter the world as the
改变世界的能力
invention of writing. I really think
文字的发明。我真的觉得
that's that's where we are. We're
这就是我们目前的处境。是
talking about something that is going to
谈论即将发生的事情
fundamentally alter what humans are with
从根本上改变人类的本质
no plan. You know, writing alters the
没有计划。你知道，写作会改变……
world slowly because the number of
世界缓慢发展，因为数量……
people who can do it is tiny at first
起初能做到这一点的人非常少。
and remain so for thousands of years.
并且数千年来一直如此。
This is changing things weakly and
这种改变微乎其微，而且
that's an awful lot of power to just
那可是相当大的权力啊。
simply have dumped on a system that
只是把东西倾倒在一个系统上
wasn't well regulated to begin with.
一开始就缺乏有效的监管。
Dan, yeah. So, I'm an I'm an
丹，是的。所以，我是一个……我是一个
entrepreneur. Um, I've been building
企业家。嗯，我一直在建造
businesses for the last 20 plus years.
过去二十多年来，我们一直是企业的重要力量。
I'm completely well positioned between
我处于非常有利的位置。
the two of you here. the excitement of
你们两个在这里。兴奋
the opportunity and the terror uh of
机遇与恐惧
what could go on. There's this image
会发生什么呢？有这样一张图片
that I saw of New York City in 1900 and
我于1900年看到的纽约市的景象
every single vehicle on the street is a
街上的每一辆车都是
horse and cart and then 13 years later
马车，然后是13年后
the same photo from the same vantage
同一角度拍摄的同一张照片
point and every single vehicle on the
这一点以及每辆车
street is a car. And in 13 years all the
街道就是一辆车。 13 年间所有
horses had been removed and cars had
马匹已被移走，汽车也已停运。
been put in place. And um if you had
已落实到位。嗯，如果你有
have interviewed the horses in 1900 and
1900年采访过这些马匹，
said uh how do you feel about your level
呃，你对自己的水平感觉如何？
of confidence uh in in the world? The
在世界上的自信？这
horses would have said well we've been
马儿们会说，好吧，我们已经……
part of uh humanity for you know horse
人类的一部分，你知道，马
and hoof hand and hoof for for many many
蹄子、手和蹄子，为了许多许多
years for for thousands of years.
数千年来。
There's one horse for every three
每三匹马中就有一匹。
humans. Like how bad could it be? You
人类。能有多糟糕呢？你
know we'll always have a special place.
我知道这里永远会有一个特别的地方。
will always be part of society. Um, and
将永远是社会的一部分。嗯，还有
little did the horses realize that that
马儿们丝毫没有意识到这一点。
was not the case. That the horses were
事实并非如此。这些马是
going to be put out of of uh business
即将倒闭
very very rapidly. And to reason through
非常非常快。并进行推理
analogy, you know, there's a lot of us
打个比方，你知道，我们人很多。
who are now sitting there going, "Hey,
现在坐在那里的人会说：“嘿，
wait a second. Does this make me a horse
稍等片刻。这岂不是让我成了一匹马？
in 1900?" I think a lot of people don't
1900年？我觉得很多人都不这么认为。
realize how massive these kind of
意识到这类事情有多么庞大
technologies are going to have as an
技术将作为一种……
impact.
影响。
You know, one minute we're ordering a
你知道，前一秒我们还在点餐……
water and that's cute and the next
水，这很可爱，下一个
minute it can run for days and in your
哪怕只有一分钟，它也能运行好几天，而且在你的
words uh it doesn't stop until it
呃，话到嘴边又说不完，直到它
achieves its goal and it comes up with
它实现了目标，并提出了
as many different ways as it could
以多种不同的方式
possibly come up with to achieve its
可能会想出办法来实现其目标
goal and in your words it better know
目标，用你的话说，最好知道
what that goal is. I'm thinking a lot as
这个目标是什么？我一直在思考……
Daniel's speaking about the vast
丹尼尔正在谈论广阔的
application of AI agents and where are
人工智能代理的应用及其应用领域
the bounds because if if this thing is
因为如果这个东西是
going to get incrementally smarter well
会逐渐变得更聪明
incrementally might be an understatement
逐步推进可能还不足以形容。
it's going to get incredibly smart
它会变得非常智能
incredibly quick and we're seeing this
速度快得惊人，我们已经看到了这一点。
AI race where all of these large
人工智能竞赛，所有这些大型项目
language models are competing for
语言模型正在竞争
intelligence with one another and if
彼此之间拥有智慧，如果
it's able to traverse the internet and
它能够浏览互联网，并且
click things and order things and write
点击、订购和写作
things and create things and all of our
事物，创造事物，以及我们所有的一切
lives run off the internet today. What
如今人们的生活离不开互联网。什么
can't it do? It's going to be smarter
它做不到吗？它会更智能
than me.
比我强。
No doubt it already is. And it's going
毫无疑问，它已经是这样了。而且它还在继续
to be able to take actions across the
能够采取跨领域的行动
internet, which is pretty much where
互联网，基本上就是……
most of my professional life operates.
我的大部分职业生涯都在从事相关工作。
It's like how I build my businesses.
这就像我创建自己企业的方式一样。
Even this podcast is an internet product
就连这个播客也是一种互联网产品。
at the end of the day because you can
归根结底，因为你可以
create we've done experiments now and I
我们已经做了一些实验，我
can show the graphs on my phone to make
我可以在手机上显示图表以进行制作
AI podcasts and they have we've just
人工智能播客，而且他们有，我们刚刚
managed to get it to have the same
设法让它拥有了同样的效果
retention as the dire CEO. Now with the
留任首席执行官一职。现在有了
image generation model retention as in
图像生成模型保留如
viewer retention the percentage of
观众留存率
people that get to one hour wow is the
能坚持一个小时的人，哇！
same now. So we can make the video, we
现在也是一样。所以我们可以制作视频，我们
can publish it, we can script it, you
可以发布，我们可以编写脚本，你
can synthesize my voice sounds like me.
可以合成出像我一样的声音。
So what what is it going to be able to
那么它究竟能做到什么呢？
do? Mhm. And can you give me the variety
做？嗯。你能给我提供各种各样的信息吗？
of use cases that the average person
普通人的使用案例
might not have intuitively conceived?
或许并非凭直觉就能想到的？
Yeah. So I I tend to be an an optimist
是的。所以我倾向于乐观。
and and part of the reason is because I
部分原因是因为我
try to understand the limits of the of
试着理解的局限性
the technology. What can it do is
这项技术。它能做什么？
anything that we can any sort of set of
任何我们能做的任何东西，任何类型的集合
human data that we can train it on. What
我们可以用来训练它的人类数据。什么
can it not do is anything that uh humans
它不能做的，就是人类能做的任何事情。
don't know what to do because we don't
不知道该怎么办，因为我们没有
have the training data. Of course, it's
拥有训练数据。当然，这是
super smart because it integrates
超级智能，因为它集成了
massive amount of knowledge that you
你拥有大量的知识
wouldn't be able to read, right? It also
应该不识字吧？它还
much faster. It can run through massive
速度快得多。它可以穿过巨大的
amount of computation that you know your
你知道你的计算量
brain you can't even comprehend because
你甚至无法理解的大脑，因为
all of that they're smart. They can take
他们都很聪明。他们可以拿走
actions but we know the limits of what
行动，但我们知道行动的限度
they can do because we trained them.
他们之所以能做到，是因为我们训练过他们。
They're able to simulate what a human
它们能够模拟人类的行为
can do. So the reason you were able to
可以做到。所以你能够……的原因
order the water there is because it was
点水，因为那里有水。
trained NSF data that includes clicking
训练过的 NSF 数据包括点击
on Door Dash and ordering water. I
在 DoorDash 上点水。我
applaud your optimism and I like the way
我赞赏你的乐观精神，我喜欢这种态度。
you think about these puzzles, but I
你思考这些谜题，但我
think I see you making a mistake that we
我觉得你犯了一个错误，我们
are about to discover is very common
即将发现的是，这非常常见
place. So we have several different
地方。所以我们有几个不同的
categories of systems. We have simple
系统分类。我们有简单的
systems, we have complicated systems, we
我们有复杂的系统，我们
have complex systems and then we have
拥有复杂的系统，然后我们……
complex adaptive systems.
复杂自适应系统。
And to most of us, a highly complicated
对我们大多数人来说，这是一个高度复杂的问题。
system appears like a complex system. We
该系统看起来像是一个复杂的系统。我们
don't understand the distinction.
不明白其中的区别。
Technologists often master highly
技术人员通常精通高超的技能
complicated systems and they know, you
复杂的系统，他们知道，你
know, for example, a computer is a
例如，要知道计算机是一种
perfectly predictable system inside.
内部系统完全可预测。
There's it's deterministic. Mhm. But to
它是决定性的。嗯。但是
most of us, it functions, it's it is
对我们大多数人来说，它运转正常，它就是这样。
mysterious enough that it feels like a
神秘得让人感觉像是一个
complex
复杂的
system. And if you're in the position of
系统。如果你处于以下位置：
having mastered highly complicated
掌握了极其复杂的技术
systems and you look at complex systems
系统，以及你研究的复杂系统
and you think it's a natural extension,
你认为这是自然而然的延伸，
you fail to
你未能
anticipate just how unpredictable they
预料到他们有多么难以预测。
are. So even if it is true that today
是。所以即使今天的情况属实。
there are limits to what these machines
这些机器的功能是有限的。
can do based on their training data, I
我可以根据他们的训练数据做到这一点。
think the problem
思考这个问题
is to see what's going to happen. You
就是看看接下来会发生什么。你
really want to start thinking of this as
真的想开始这样思考了。
the evolution of a new species that will
新物种的进化将
continue to evolve. It will partially be
持续发展。部分而言，
shaped by what we ask it to do, the
受我们要求它做的事情的影响，
direction we lead it, and it will
我们引领它的方向，它将
partially be shaped by things we don't
部分地受到我们无法控制的因素的影响
understand. So, how does this computer
理解。那么，这台电脑是如何工作的呢？
that that we have work? Well, one of the
我们有工作吗？嗯，其中一个
things that it does is we plug them into
它的作用就是我们把它们插到
each other using language. It's almost
彼此用语言交流。几乎
as if you've plugged an Ethernet cable
就像你插上了一根以太网线一样
in between human minds. And that means
在人类思想之间。这意味着
that the cognitive potential exceeds the
认知潜能超过了
sum of the individual minds in question.
相关个体思想的总和。
Your AIS are going to do that. And that
你的AIS系统会这样做。而那
means that our ability to say what they
这意味着我们有能力表达他们的想法。
are capable of does not come down to
能力并非取决于
well we didn't train it on that data. As
我们没有用那些数据进行训练。作为
they begin to interact that feedback is
他们开始互动，反馈是
going to take them to capabilities we
我们将带他们达到我们的能力水平
don't anticipate and may not even
不要预料到，甚至可能根本不会预料到。
recognize once they become present.
一旦它们出现，就要认出来。
That's one of my fears. This is an
这也是我担心的事之一。这是
evolving creature and it's not even an
正在进化的生物，而且它甚至还不是……
animal. If it were an animal, you could
动物。如果是动物的话，你可以
say something about what the limits of
请谈谈其局限性
that capability are. But this is a new
具备这种能力。但这是一种新的
type of biological creature and it will
生物体的一种类型，它将
become capable of things that we don't
能够做到我们不具备的能力。
even have names for. Even if it didn't
甚至还有名字。即使没有
do that, even if it just stayed within
即使它只是停留在……之内，也要这样做。
the boundaries that you're talking
你所说的界限
about, you mentioned about it having
关于，你提到过它有
median level intelligence. Well, that by
中等智力水平。嗯，就是这样。
definition means 50% of the people on
定义是指50%的人
the planet are less intelligent than uh
这个星球的智慧不如……
AI. uh you know to a degree it's almost
人工智能。呃，你知道，在某种程度上，几乎
as if we've just invented a new
就好像我们刚刚发明了一种新事物
continent of remote workers. Um there's
远程办公者的大陆。嗯，有
billions of them. They've all got a
其中数十亿。他们都有一个
masters or a PhD. They all speak all the
硕士或博士学位。他们都说了所有……
languages. Anything that you could call
语言。任何你可以称之为
someone or ask someone over the internet
通过互联网向某人或某人询问。
to do, they're there 24/7 and they're 25
为了完成这些工作，他们全天候24小时待命，而且他们有25岁。
cents an hour. Uh if that um so like if
每小时几美分。呃，如果那样的话，嗯，就像如果
that really happened like if we really
那真的发生过，就像我们真的
did just discover that there were a
刚刚发现有
billion extra people on the planet who
地球上多了十亿人
all had PhDs and were happy to work
他们都拥有博士学位，并且乐于工作。
almost for free that would have a
几乎免费，这将拥有
massive disruptive impact on society.
对社会造成巨大的破坏性影响。
Like society would have to rethink how
就像社会需要重新思考如何
everyone lives and works and gets
每个人都生活、工作并获得
meaning. Um so like and that's that's if
意义。嗯，所以，就像，就是这样，如果
it just stays at a median level of
它一直保持在中等水平
intelligence. Like it's it's pretty
智力。它很漂亮
profound. I still think it's it's a
深刻的。我仍然认为这是一个
tool. this is power that is there to be
工具。这就是存在的力量。
harnessed by entrepreneurs. You know, I
被企业家们所利用。你知道，我
I think that the world is gonna get
我认为世界将会变得
disrupted, right? Um and the the you
被打乱了，对吧？嗯，还有你
know, the this you know post-war world
你知道，这就是战后世界。
that we created where you go through
我们创建了您可以穿过的地方
life, you go through 12 years of
人生，你会经历12年的
education, you get to college and you
教育，你上了大学，然后你
just check the boxes, you get a job. We
只需勾选选项，就能找到工作。我们
can already see the fractures of that
已经可以看到其中的裂痕。
that it is, you know, this American
你知道，这就是美国人
dream is perhaps no longer there. And so
梦想或许已经消失了。所以
I think the world has already changed.
我认为世界已经发生了改变。
So but but like what are the
所以，但是，比如说，什么是……
opportunities? Obviously there are
机会？显然有
downsides. The opportunities is for the
缺点。机会属于……
first time access to opportunity is is
第一次获得机会是
equal. And I I do think there's going to
平等的。而且我确实认为将会出现
be more inequality. And the reason for
加剧不平等。原因在于
this inequality is because actually
这种不平等现象实际上是因为……
Steve Jobs uh you know made this
史蒂夫·乔布斯，你知道，创造了这个
analogy. It's like the the best taxi
类比。它就像最好的出租车
driver in New York is like 20% better
纽约的司机比其他地方的司机好20%左右。
than the you know the you know average
比你知道的平均值
taxi driver. the best programmer uh can
出租车司机。最好的程序员呃可以
be 10x better. You know, we call we say
比现在好十倍。你知道，我们称之为
the 10x engineer. Now, the variance will
10倍工程师。现在，方差将
be in the thousandx, right? Like the
应该在上千倍之内吧？就像
best the best entrepreneur that can
最优秀的企业家
leverage those agents could be better uh
利用这些代理人可能会更好。
could be a thousand times better than
可能比现在好一千倍
than someone who doesn't have the grit,
比那些缺乏毅力的人更有韧性。
doesn't have the skill, doesn't have the
不具备这项技能，也不具备
ambition. Right? So, so that that will
志向。正确的？所以，这样一来，就会
create a world. Yes, there's massive
创造一个世界。是的，数量非常庞大。
access to opportunity, but there are
获得机会的机会，但是……
people who will take seize it and then
那些会夺取它的人，然后
they'll seize it and then there'll be
他们会夺取它，然后就会……
people who don't. I imagine it almost
不这么做的人。我几乎能想象出来
like a um a marathon race and AI has two
就像马拉松比赛一样，人工智能有两个
superpowers. One superpower is to
超级大国。一个超级大国是
distract people um such as Tik Tok
分散人们的注意力，比如抖音
algorithm. That's right. And the other
算法。这是正确的。还有另一个
superpower is to make you hyper
超能力就是让你变得超强
creative. So you become a hyper consumer
有创造力的。于是你就成了个超级消费者。
or a hyper creator. And in this marathon
或者是一位超级创作者。在这场马拉松比赛中
race, the vast majority of people have
种族方面，绝大多数人都有
got their shoes tied together cuz AI is
他们的鞋带绑在一起，因为人工智能是
distracting them. Some people are
分散他们的注意力。有些人是
running traditional race. Some people
参加传统比赛。有些人
have got a bicycle and some people have
有些人有自行车，有些人有
got a Formula 1 vehicle. And it's going
获得了一辆一级方程式赛车。而且它还在继续
to be very confronting when the results
结果令人非常难以接受
go on the scoreboard and you see, oh,
查看记分牌，你会看到，哦，
wait a second. There's a few people who
稍等片刻。有几个人
finished this marathon in about 30
我大约用了30分钟完成了这场马拉松。
minutes. And there's a lot of us who
分钟。我们当中有很多人都是这样的人
finished in like 18 hours because we had
因为我们有，所以大概花了18个小时就完成了。
our shoes tied together. And I can't
我们的鞋子绑在一起了。我不能
understand if we've got equal
明白我们是否拥有平等
opportunity why there's so much
机会为何如此之多
disparity between how fast it you know
你知道的速度与你了解的速度之间的差异
and do, you know, I'm using an analogy,
你知道，我是在打比方。
but this idea that, you know, someone
但这种想法，你知道，就是有人
like a lot of people are going to start
就像很多人即将开始的那样
earning a million dollars a month and a
月入一百万美元
lot of people are going to say, "Hey, I
很多人会说：“嘿，我
can't even get a job for $15 an hour."
连时薪15美元的工作都找不到。
there's going to be this kind of
将会存在这种……
interesting wedge. Well, but I I hear in
有趣的楔形物。嗯，但我听说
what both of you are saying
你们俩说的话
a kind of assumption that this will all
一种假设，即这一切都将发生
be done on the up and up. And I do want
必须光明正大地完成。我确实想要
to just I am not a doomer. I agree that
我只是想说，我不是个悲观主义者。我同意。
the doomers are likely incorrect that
那些悲观论调很可能是错误的，
their fears are misplaced. But I do
他们的担忧毫无根据。但我确实
think we have a question of a related
我们认为我们有一个相关的问题。
rates problem.
利率问题。
You know I said the potential for good
你知道我说过，它有向善的潜力。
here is infinite and the potential for
这里蕴藏着无限的可能
bad is 10 times.
坏的程度是10倍。
Right? What I mean is there are lots of
正确的？我的意思是，有很多
ways in which this obviously empowers
这显然赋予了……权力。
people to do things that they were going
人们去做他们原本要做的事情
to be otherwise stuck in the mundane
否则就会陷入平凡之中
process of learning to code and then
学习编程的过程，然后
figuring out how to make the code work
弄清楚如何让代码运行起来
and bring it to market and all of that.
然后把它推向市场等等。
And this solves a lot of those problems
这样就能解决很多这类问题。
and that's obviously a good thing.
这显然是件好事。
really the what we should want is the
我们真正想要的其实是
wealth creation object as quickly as we
财富创造的目标就像我们一样迅速。
can get there. But the problem is you
可以到达那里。但问题在于你
know as much as it that hyper creative
知道这一点，就像知道它极具创造力一样。
individual is empowered to make wealth
个人有能力创造财富
the person who is interested in stealing
对偷窃感兴趣的人
may be even more empowered. And I'm
甚至可能拥有更大的权力。而我是
concerned about that at at a pretty high
对此的担忧程度相当高
level. the the abuse cases may outnumber
等级。虐待案件的数量可能超过其他案件。
the use cases and we don't have a plan
我们目前还没有具体的使用案例和计划。
for what to do about that. Um to can I
那么该如何应对呢？嗯，我可以吗？
can I give you a quick uh like
我可以简单地给你一个……呃……
introduction here like the optimistic
这里介绍一下乐观主义者
view? OpenAI invented uh GP the first
看法？ OpenAI发明了GP，第一个。
version GPT came out in 2019. 2020 was
GPT 版本于 2019 年发布。2020 年是
GPT2 and so OpenAI you know now they get
GPT2 和 OpenAI，你知道现在他们得到了
a lot of criticism and lawsuit from IL
来自伊利诺伊州的大量批评和诉讼
Musk that they're no longer open source
马斯克说他们不再是开源软件了。
right they used to be. The reason is in
没错，他们以前确实如此。原因在于
GPT2 they said we are we are no longer
GPT2 他们说我们是，我们不再是了
gonna uh open source this technology
我打算把这项技术开源。
because it's going to create um
因为它会造成……
opportunities for abuse such as you know
诸如此类的滥用机会，你也知道。
influencing elections um you know
影响选举，嗯，你知道的。
stealing you know grandma's credit card
偷你奶奶的信用卡
and so on so forth. Wouldn't you say
诸如此类。你不觉得吗？
Brett that it is kind of surprising how
布雷特说，这有点令人惊讶。
little abuse we've seen so far?
目前为止我们看到的虐待事件很少？
I don't know how much abuse we've seen
我不知道我们究竟目睹了多少虐待事件。
so far. I don't know how any of us do.
迄今为止。我不知道我们是怎么做到的。
And I also even the example that you
而且我甚至还举了你的例子。
suggest where chat GPT is no longer open
建议聊天 GPT 已关闭的地点
source to prevent abuse. I'm taking
防止滥用的来源。我正在服用
their word for it that that's the
他们用一句话来证明那就是
motivation. Where as a systems theorist,
动机。而作为一名系统理论家，
I would say, well, if you had a
我会说，嗯，如果你有一个
technology that was excellent at
这项技术非常出色
enhancing your capacity to wield power,
增强你运用权力的能力，
then open sourcing it is a failure to
那么，开源就是失败。
capitalize on that. and that the most
抓住这个机会。而且最
remunerative use is to keep it private
有利可图的用途是将其保密。
and then either sell the ability to
然后要么出售这种能力
manipulate elections to people who want
操纵选举，让那些想要的人得以参与。
to do so or sell the ability to have it
这样做，或者出售拥有这种能力。
kept off the table for people who don't.
留给那些不认同的人。
And I would expect that that's probably
我估计那很可能
what's going on. There's no if you have
这是怎么回事。没有“如果你有”这种说法。
a technology as transformative as this,
像这样具有变革意义的技术
giving it away for free is
免费赠送是
counterintuitive, which leaves those of
这与直觉相悖，这使得那些
us in the public more or less at the
我们在公众面前或多或少处于
mercy of the people who have it.
拥有这种能力的人的仁慈。
So I I don't see the reason for comfort
所以我看不出有什么理由感到舒适。
there. We are at the dawn of this
那里。我们正处于这一时期的黎明。
radical transformation of humans that by
人类的根本性转变
its very nature as a truly complex and
它本身的性质就是一个真正复杂且
emergent innovation. Nobody on earth can
新兴创新。地球上没有人能
predict what's going to happen. We can
预测将会发生什么。我们可以
we're on the event horizon of something.
我们正处于某个事件的事件视界上。
And the problem is you know we can talk
问题是，你知道我们可以谈论
about the obvious disruptions the job
关于工作中显而易见的干扰
disruption and that's going to be
颠覆，而且这将是
massive. And does that lead some group
大量的。这是否会引发某个群体？
of elites to decide, oh well, suddenly
由精英阶层决定，哦，好吧，突然
we have a lot of useless eaters and what
我们有很多没用的食客，还有什么？
are we going to do about that? Because
我们打算如何应对？因为
that conversation tends to lead
这种对话往往会引出
somewhere very dark very quickly. Um,
迅速进入一个非常黑暗的地方。嗯，
but I think that's just the beginning of
但我认为这仅仅是个开始。
the the various ways in which this could
这可以通过多种方式实现。
go wrong without the doomer scenarios
如果没有末日论调，事情就会出错
coming into play. This is an
开始发挥作用。这是
uncontrolled experiment in which all of
一项非对照实验，其中所有
humanity is downstream. Yeah. So I I was
人类处于下游。是的。所以，我当时
trying to make the point that OpenAI has
试图说明OpenAI已经
been sort of wrong about the uh the sort
我之前对那种情况有点误解了。
of uh how big of a potential for harm it
呃，它造成的潜在危害有多大？
is like you know I think we would have
就像你知道的，我觉得我们会有
heard about it in the news like uh the
我从新闻上听说过这件事，就像……
sort of how much harm it's done and
某种程度上来说，它造成了多大的伤害，以及
maybe you know some of it is working in
或许你知道其中一些方法正在奏效
the shadows but like the few incidents
阴影，但就像少数几起事件一样
that we've heard about where you know
我们听说过你所在的地区。
the cause of LLM's large language models
LLM大型语言模型的原因
the technology that's powering chat has
聊天所依赖的技术已经
been a huge headliners uh like New York
一直是像纽约这样的大牌明星。
Times talked about this kid that was,
《时代周刊》曾报道过这个孩子，
you know, perhaps goated by some kind of
你知道，或许是被某种山羊袭击了
chat software that, you know, helps
你知道，那种聊天软件可以帮助
teenagers to be less lonely into into
让青少年减少孤独感
suicide, which is which is tragic. And
自杀，这真是一场悲剧。和
obviously, these are the kind of safety
显然，这些都是安全措施。
and and abuse uh issues that we want to
以及滥用呃，我们想要解决的问题
we want to worry about. But these are
我们想担心的是。但这些是
kind of these isolated uh incidents and
这些孤立的事件
we do have open- source large language
我们确实有开源的大型语言
models. Obviously, the thing that
模型。显然，这件事
everyone talks about is DeepSeek.
大家都在谈论DeepSeek。
Deepseek is uh coming from China. So
Deepseek 呃，它来自中国。所以
what is Deepseek's incentive? You know
Deepseek的动机是什么？你知道
perhaps the incentive is to destroy the
或许其动机是为了摧毁
AI industry in the US. Uh you know when
美国人工智能产业。呃，你知道什么时候
they released Deepseek, you know the
他们发布了Deepseek，你知道的。
market tanked the market for Nvidia, the
市场崩盘导致英伟达的市场遭受重创。
market for AI and all of that. But there
人工智能市场等等。但是那里
is an incentive to open source. Meta is
这是对开源的一种激励。 Meta 是
open sourcing Llama. Llama is another AI
开源 Llama。 Llama是另一个人工智能
similar to Chat GPT. The reason they're
类似于聊天 GPT。他们之所以是
open sourcing Llama and Zuckerberg just
开源 Llama 和扎克伯格只是
says that out loud is basically they
大声说出来基本上就是他们
don't want to be beholden to open AI.
不想受制于开源人工智能。
They don't sell AI as a service. They
他们不把人工智能作为服务出售。他们
use it to build products. And there's
用它来打造产品。还有……
this concept in business called
商业中的这个概念叫做
commoditize your compliment because you
将你的赞美商品化，因为你
need AI as technology to run your
需要人工智能技术来运行你的
service. The best strategy to do is to
服务。最好的策略是……
open source it. So these market forces
开源它。因此，这些市场力量
are going to create conditions that I
将会创造我所处的条件
think are actually beneficial. So I'll
认为它们实际上是有益的。所以我会
give you a few few examples. One is
举几个例子。一是
first of all the AI companies are
首先，人工智能公司是
motivated to create AI that is safe so
致力于创造安全的人工智能
that they can sell it. Second there are
他们可以把它卖掉。其次，还有
security companies investing in AIs that
投资人工智能的安全公司
allows them to protect from the sort of
使他们能够保护自己免受此类侵害
malicious uh acting of of AI. And so you
人工智能的恶意行为。所以你
have the free market and we've always
我们拥有自由市场，而且我们一直
had that you know but generally as
你知道，我以前也遇到过这种情况，但通常来说……
humanity we've been able to leverage uh
我们一直以来都能够利用人类的……
the same technology to protect against
同样的科技也可用于防范
the abuse. So I I don't really
虐待。所以，我其实不太明白。
understand this and maybe this is
理解这一点，或许这就是
actually this is the exact discussion
实际上，这正是我们讨论的内容。
that you would expect between somebody
你会在某人之间期待的事情
at the frontier of the highly
在高度前沿
complicated staring at a complex system
凝视一个复杂的系统，感觉很复杂
and a biologist who comes from the land
还有一位来自乡村的生物学家
of the complex and is looking back at
该综合体正在回顾
highly complicated
高度复杂
systems. In game theory we have
系统。在博弈论中，我们有
something called a colle collective
一个叫做集体主义的东西
action problem. And in the market that
行动问题。而在这个市场中，
you're
你是
describing, an individual company has no
描述而言，单个公司没有
capacity to hold back the abuses of AI.
遏制人工智能滥用的能力。
The most you can do is not participate
你最多只能不参与。
in them. You can't stop other people
在它们之中。你无法阻止其他人
from programming LLMs in some dangerous
从一些危险的编程LLM中
way. And you can limit your own ability
方式。你可以限制自己的能力
to earn based on your own limitations of
在自身能力范围内赚取收入
what you're willing to do. And then
你愿意做什么。进而
effectively what happens is the
实际上发生的情况是
technology gets invented anyway. It just
技术无论如何都会被发明出来。就这么
that the dollars end up in somebody
这些美元最终会落入某人手中。
else's pocket. So the incentive is not
别人的口袋。所以激励机制并非如此。
to restrain yourself so that you can at
克制自己，以便你能……
least compete and participate in the
至少参与竞争和参与
market that's going to be opened. And
即将开放的市场。和
so the number of ways in which you can
所以，你可以采用的方法数量是……
abuse this technology. Let's take a
滥用这项技术。让我们来看一个
couple.
夫妻。
What is to stop somebody from training
有什么能阻止某人接受培训呢？
LLMs
法学硕士
on an
一个
individual's creative output and then
个人的创造性产出，然后
creating an LLM that can out compete
打造一个能够超越竞争对手的法学硕士项目
that individual can effectively not only
这个人不仅能够有效地
produce what they would naturally
它们自然而然地会产出它们本来就会产出的东西。
produce over the course of a lifetime
一生中产出的果实
but can extrapolate from it and can even
但可以从中推断，甚至可以
hybridize it with the insights of other
将其与其他人的见解相结合
people so that effectively those who
人们，因此有效地那些
have the LLM can train it on the
拥有LLM学位的人可以对其进行训练。
creativity ity of others, not cut them
尊重他人的创造力，而不是扼杀它们。
in on the use of that insight. You can
参与运用这一洞见。你可以
effectively end up putting yourself out
最终实际上是把自己置于不利地位
of business by putting your creative
通过发挥你的创造力来经营企业
ideas in the world where they get sucked
他们被吸入的世界里的想法
up as training data for future LLMs.
可作为未来LLM的训练数据。
That is unscrupulous, but it's
这虽然不道德，但却是……
effectively guaranteed. In fact, it's
有效保障。事实上，它是
already happening. So, that's a problem.
已经发生了。所以，这是个问题。
And likewise, what what would stop
同样，什么会阻止这一切呢？
somebody from interacting with an
某人避免与他人互动
individual and training an LLM to become
个人并接受培训以获得法学硕士学位
like a personalized con artist?
就像一个专门为你服务的骗子？
Something that would play exactly to
正好可以
your blind spot. That does happen. That
你的盲点。这种情况确实会发生。那
that is starting to happen. Um people
这种情况正在发生。嗯，人们
get phone calls and it sounds like their
接到电话，听起来像是他们的
daughter and I've I've lost my phone and
我和女儿……我的手机丢了……
I'm borrowing a friend's phone and all
我借用了朋友的手机等等
of that sort of stuff. What's what's
诸如此类的事情。到底是怎么回事？
interesting is that I I think you make a
有趣的是，我认为你做出了一个
a really good point.
说得很有道理。
I worry about the impact on society. And
我担心这会对社会造成影响。和
yet when I look at every single
然而，当我仔细审视每一个
individual who uses AI regularly, it
经常使用人工智能的人，它
almost has nothing but profoundly
几乎一无所有，但却意义深远
positive impact on their life. I look at
对他们的生活产生积极影响。我看着
people like um I was just spending some
像我这样的人，我只是花了一些时间
time with my parents-in-law um who are
和我的岳父母在一起的时光，嗯，他们是
in their 70s and early 80s and they use
他们七十多岁到八十岁出头，他们使用
AI regularly for all sorts of things
人工智能经常用于各种用途
that they find incredibly valuable and
他们认为这非常有价值，而且
that improves the quality of their life.
这将提高他们的生活质量。
I personally did a an M&amp;A a mergers and
我本人做过并购交易。
acquisitions deal where I bought a
我买入了一笔收购交易
company last year and the AI was so
公司去年，人工智能非常出色。
powerful at helping that process. The
能够有效地促进这一过程。这
conversations were transcribed and they
对话被转录下来，并且
were turned into letters of intent and
并转化为意向书。
then press releases and uh legal
然后是新闻稿和法律文件。
documents and we probably shaved
文件，我们可能刮了胡子
$100,000 worth of uh costs and and we
价值 10 万美元的费用，而且我们
sped up the whole process and it was
加快了整个过程，而且是
pretty magical to see how how it could
看到它如何运作，真是太神奇了。
happen. With that said, you know,
发生。话虽如此，你知道，
there's there's all of these like, well,
有很多这样的东西，比如，嗯，
$100,000 worth of lawyers didn't get
价值10万美元的律师费没能拿到。
paid, right? So, well, what I want to
已经付过钱了吧？所以，嗯，我想要的是
know, yeah,
知道，是的。
people upset about, but if we look back
人们对此感到不满，但如果我们回顾过去
at the invention of the cell phone or
在手机发明之时或
the invention of the social media
社交媒体的发明
platforms, there would be every reason
平台，完全有理由
to have the exactly the same
拥有完全相同的
perspective, right? I remember the
从另一个角度来看，对吧？我记得
beginning of Facebook and I remember the
Facebook 的创立之初，我还记得……
idea that suddenly the process that used
突然间，这个过程发生了改变。
to afflict people where you would just
去折磨那些你只会……的人
lose touch with most of the people who
与大多数人失去联系
had been important to you, that was not
对你来说很重要，那并非如此。
something that needed to happen anymore.
这件事已经没有必要再发生了。
You could just retain them permanently
你可以永久保留它们。
as a part of a diffuse
作为弥散的一部分
uh social grouping that just simply grew
呃，社交群体就这样自然而然地发展起来了。
and value was added. There's no end to
并增加了价值。没有尽头
how much good that did, but what it did
这样做究竟有多大好处，以及它做了什么。
to us was profound and not evident in
对我们来说，这意义深远，而且并不明显。
the first chapter. Say the same thing
第一章。意思一样。
about the cell phones and the dopamine
关于手机和多巴胺
traps and the way this has disconnected
陷阱以及由此造成的脱节
us from each other, the way it has
我们彼此疏远，就像它一直以来那样。
disconnected us from nature, the way it
它使我们与自然脱节，就像它
has altered the very patterns with which
改变了原有的模式
we think. It has altered every
我们认为。它改变了一切
classroom. Mhm. So, and those things I
课堂。嗯。所以，还有那些我
think are going to turn out to have been
认为最终会证明是
sort of minor foreshadowings of the
某种程度上算是对……的轻微预示
disruption that AI will produce. So, I
人工智能将带来的颠覆性影响。所以，我
agree with you today. The amount you can
今天我同意你的观点。你可以的金额
do with AI, there's a tremendous amount
与人工智能相关的领域非常广泛。
of good. There's a little bit of harm.
好的。会造成一些伤害。
Maybe that's something we need to worry
或许这是我们应该担心的事情。
about. But as this develops, as we get
关于。但随着事态发展，随着我们逐渐了解
to, you know, to peer over the edge of
你知道，就是从边缘往下看。
this cliff that we're headed to, I think
我想，我们正要前往的这个悬崖。
we're going to discover that we can't
我们将发现我们做不到
yet detect the nature of the alteration
但要检测出变化的性质
that's coming. So, I just wanted to add
那件事即将发生。所以，我只是想补充一点。
some context to that cuz Amjad, I I saw
需要一些背景信息，因为阿姆贾德，我看到
the interview you did in a newsletter in
你在新闻简报上接受的采访
2023 where you said, "I wouldn't prepare
2023年，你曾说过，“我不会为此做准备”。
for AGI in the same way that I wouldn't
对于通用人工智能（AGI），我不会采取同样的方式。
prepare for the end of days." It's
为世界末日做好准备。
effectively the end of days if the
实际上，如果……那就是世界末日。
vision of AGI that some of these
通用人工智能的愿景之一是，其中一些
companies have comes to bear because
公司之所以介入，是因为
it's called the singularity moment
它被称为奇点时刻
because you can't really predict what
因为你无法真正预测会发生什么
happens after that. And so like how
之后发生的事情。所以就像这样
would you even prepare for that and you
你甚至会为此做准备吗？
want to prepare for the more likely
想为更有可能发生的情况做好准备
world and that world that you can
世界，以及你可以的那个世界
actually predict is a world where yes
实际上预测的世界是这样的
there's like a massive improvements of
情况有了巨大的改善
technology and there's like insane
科技发展到如此程度，简直令人难以置信。
compounding effects of technology and
技术带来的复合效应
it's pretty hard to keep up. From that
很难跟上。从此
it appeared that in 2023 you were saying
看来你在2023年是这么说的。
a similar thing to Brett in terms of we
就我们而言，这和布雷特的情况类似。
can't see around the corner here because
这里看不到拐角处的情况，因为
it is a singularity.
这是一个奇点。
Sorry you also used AGI artificial
抱歉，您也使用了AGI人工技术。
general intelligence. It'd be
一般智力。那将是
interesting to know what your definition
很想知道你的定义是什么
of AGI is. say that. Yeah. So, so what
AGI 是。说出来。是的。所以，所以呢？
what I was saying there is even if I'm
我刚才说的意思是，即使我是
wrong that you can actually create a
错误，你实际上可以创造
unbounded seemingly conscious artificial
无界限的、看似有意识的人工
intelligence that can entirely replace
能够完全取代的智能
humans and can act autonomously in a way
人类可以以某种方式自主行动。
that even humans can't act and can
即使是人类也无法采取行动，而且
coordinate across different AIs,
协调不同人工智能之间的工作
different data centers to take over the
不同的数据中心接管
world. Even if if that's so so the
世界。即使情况真是如此
definition of AGI is artificial general
AGI的定义是人工通用
intelligence meaning that AI can acquire
智能意味着人工智能可以获取
new skills in efficiently in the same
在同一环境中高效掌握新技能
way that a humans can acquire skills.
人类获得技能的一种方式。
Right now AIs don't acquire skills
目前人工智能无法习得技能
efficiently you know they they require
高效地，你知道他们需要
massive amount of energy and compute
大量的能源和计算
entire data set of compute to acquire
获取整个计算数据集
these these skills and I think there's a
这些技能，我认为有……
again a limit on how general
再次强调，普遍程度存在限制。
intelligence can get I think for most of
我认为大多数人的智力都可以得到提升。
the time we're lagging in terms of what
我们在哪些方面落后了？
humans are are capable of doing the
人类有能力做到
singularity is based on this concept of
奇点是基于以下概念的：
intellig intelligence explosion so once
智能智力爆炸那么一次
Once you create an AGI, once you create
一旦您创建了 AGI，一旦您创建
an artificial general
人造将军
intelligence, that intelligence will be
情报，那份情报将是
able to modify its own source code and
能够修改自己的源代码
create the next version that is much
创建下一个版本，这将大大提升版本性能。
more intelligent. And the next version
更聪明。以及下一个版本
creates the next version and the next,
创建下一个版本，再下一个版本，
you know, for infinity, right? Within a
你知道，无限，对吧？在
week, within a week, perhaps within
一周内，或许在一周之内
milliseconds at some point. Yeah. Right.
在某个时刻，需要几毫秒的时间。是的。正确的。
Uh because it might invent new computing
呃，因为它可能会发明新的计算方式。
substrate and and and all of that.
基质以及所有这一切。
perhaps they'll use quantum computing
或许他们会使用量子计算
and and so then you have this
所以，然后你就有了这些
intelligence
智力
explosion in a way that it is impossible
以一种不可能的方式爆炸
to predict how the world is going to be
预测世界将如何发展
and what I'm saying is this is sort of
我的意思是，这有点像……
like an end of time story like how would
就像一个末日故事，会是什么样子呢？
you even prepare for that so if if
你甚至为此做好了准备，所以如果
that's coming like why would I spend my
那感觉就像，我为什么要浪费我的时间？
time preparing for I think it's unlikely
我觉得准备时间不太可能。
to happen can't see around the corner
即将发生的事情，无法预见。
yeah but I'd rather prepare
是啊，但我更愿意做好准备。
what I was saying there. I'd rather
我刚才说的就是这个意思。我宁愿
prepare for the more likely world in
为更可能到来的世界做好准备
which we have access to tremendous
我们拥有巨大的资源。
power, but the world's not ending and
权力，但世界末日并未到来。
humans are still uh important.
人类仍然很重要。
I don't I don't know why you say more
我不知道，我不知道你为什么说更多
likely. I mean, I I think the structure
有可能。我的意思是，我认为结构
of your argument is is sound. You would
你的论点是合理的。你会
prepare for the world that might happen
为可能发生的世界做好准备
for which you can prepare. There's
你可以为此做好准备。有
literally no point in trying to prepare
尝试准备完全没有意义。
for a world You can't predict it all.
对于这个世界来说，你不可能预测所有的事情。
The only thing you can do is just sort
你唯一能做的就是排序。
of upgrade your own skills and pay
提升自身技能并支付报酬
attention. But if I have one message for
注意力。但如果我有一条信息要传达
the technologists, it's that your
技术人员，就是你的
confidence about what this can and
对这方面的能力充满信心
cannot do is misplaced because you have
做不到这一点是错误的，因为你有
without noticing stepped into the realm
不知不觉间踏入了那个领域。
of the truly complex. In the truly
真正复杂的事物。真正
complex, your confidence should drop to
情况复杂时，你的信心应该会下降。
near zero. that you know what's going
接近于零。你知道发生了什么。
on. Are these things conscious? I don't
在。这些事物是有意识的吗？我不
know. But will they be highly likely
知道。但他们极有可能吗？
they will become conscious and that we
他们会觉醒，而我们
will not have a test to tell us whether
没有测试可以告诉我们是否
that has happened. Elon Musk predicts
这事已经发生了。埃隆·马斯克预测
that by
通过
2029 we will have AI with us AGI that
2029年，我们将拥有人工智能（AGI）。
surpasses the combined intelligence of
超越了……的总和
all
全部
humans. And Sam Alman actually wrote a
人类。而萨姆·阿尔曼实际上写了一本书
blog three months ago that I read where
三个月前我读过一篇博客，里面提到……
he said we are confident now Sam Alman
他说我们现在很有信心了，萨姆·阿尔曼
being the founder of open arrow which um
作为 Open Arrow 的创始人，嗯
created chatbt we are confident now that
创建了 chatbt，我们现在确信
we know how to build AGI as we have
我们知道如何构建通用人工智能（AGI），因为我们有
traditionally understood it. When I put
传统意义上的理解。当我放
these things together, I go back to the
这些事情综合起来，我又回到了……
central question of what role do humans
人类扮演什么角色，这是核心问题。
have in in this in the sort of
在这方面有所涉及
professional output in GDP creation. If
专业产出对GDP创造的影响。如果
it's smarter than all humans combined,
它比所有人类加起来都聪明。
if Elon Musk is correct there, and it's
如果埃隆·马斯克的说法是正确的，那就是
able to take actions across the internet
能够通过互联网采取行动
and continue to learn. This is like a
并继续学习。这就像……
central question that I'm hoping I can
我希望能够提出的中心问题是：
answer today, which is like where do we
今天就要回答这个问题，就像我们该去哪里一样。
go? Yeah. I I mean in my vision of the
去？是的。我的意思是，在我看来
world we are in the creative seat. We're
世界正处于我们创意的主导地位。是
sitting there where um we we are
我们坐在那里，嗯，我们现在在哪儿
controlling swarms of intelligent being
控制大量智能生物
to do our job. You know the way you run
做好我们的工作。你知道你跑步的方式
your business for example you're sitting
例如，在你的公司里，你正坐在那里。
at a computer you have an hour to work.
你在电脑前有一个小时的工作时间。
Yeah. and you're going to launch like a
是的。你将像……一样发射
thousand SDR you know sales uh you know
你知道，数千个SDR的销售额，呃，你知道
representative to go like grab as as
代表像抓住一样去
many leads as possible and you're
尽可能多地收集线索，你就是
generating new update on replet for for
正在为补给生成新的更新
your website here and then uh on this
你的网站在这里，然后是这个。
side you you you're actually you you
你这边，你，你其实是你，你
have an AI that's crunching data about
拥有一个人工智能，可以处理关于以下方面的数据：
your uh your existing business to to
你的，呃，你现有的业务到
figure out how to improve it and these
想办法改进它以及这些
AIs are kind of somehow all coordinating
人工智能似乎都在以某种方式进行协调。
together and I am trying to privilege
一起，我试图给予特权
the human like this is my my mission is
像这样的人是我的使命是
to uh build tools for people. I'm not
为人们开发工具。我不是
building tools for agents and agents are
为代理构建工具和代理是
a tool and so ultimately not only do I
工具，所以最终我不仅……
think that humans have a privileged
认为人类拥有特权
position in the in the world and in the
在世界上的地位
universe. We don't know where conscious
宇宙。我们不知道意识在哪里。
consciousness is coming from. We don't
意识源自何处？我们不
really have the science to explain it.
确实有科学依据来解释它。
Um I think humans are special. That's
嗯，我觉得人类很特别。那是
one side is is my belief that humans are
一方面是我相信人类是
are special in the world and another
在世界上是特殊的，还有另一个
side which I understand that the
我理解的一方是
technology today and I think for the
当今的科技，我认为对于
foreseeable future y is going to be a
在可预见的未来，y 将会是一个
function of us training data. So there
我们训练数据的功能。所以就是这样。
was this whole idea like what if chat
这个想法就像是“如果聊天会怎样”一样。
GPT generates uh pathogens. Well have
GPT会产生病原体。我们有
you trained it on pathogens? They were
你用病原体训练过它吗？他们是
doing that kind of stuff in Wuhan. know
在武汉做那种事。知道
I mean I mean a lot of the biotech
我的意思是，很多生物技术
companies are essentially using
公司本质上是在使用
artificial intelligence like I can think
人工智能就像我能思考的那样
of Abselera I think it's Abselera in
我认为是 Abselera 的 Abselera。
Canada their whole business is using AI
加拿大，他们的整个业务都在使用人工智能。
to create new vaccines using artificial
利用人工合成技术制造新型疫苗
intelligence and bigger data sets than
比以往更智能、拥有更大数据集
we've never have had before and I know
我们以前从未有过，我知道
cuz I was I was very close to one of the
因为我当时和其中一个人关系非常密切
founders of people involved in Absela so
Absela 的创始人及其团队成员
that that work is going on anyway and if
这项工作无论如何都会进行，而且如果
we think about Wuhan that's it's quite
我们想到武汉，就觉得它相当……
probably well known now that it came out
现在这件事可能已经广为人知了。
of a lab and people working in a lab and
实验室以及在实验室工作的人员
in that scenario that had a huge impact
在这种情况下，它产生了巨大的影响。
and shut down the world. What I'm the
并让世界停摆。我是什么
central question I'd love to answer
我最想回答的核心问题
before I throw it back open to the the
在我把它重新打开之前
room is what jobs because I know that
房间就是工作的地方，因为我知道这一点。
you have this perspective. What jobs are
你持有这种观点。哪些工作？
going to be made redundant in a world
在一个世界里，你将被淘汰。
where I am sat here as a CEO with a
我此刻作为首席执行官坐在这里……
thousand AI agents, right? I was
一千个人工智能代理，对吧？我当时
thinking of all the names of my of the
想着我所有名字的
people in my company who are currently
我公司目前
doing those jobs. I was thinking about
做这些工作。我一直在想……
my CFO when you talked about processing
我的首席财务官，你谈到处理的时候，我正好在谈论这个。
business data, my graphic designers, my
商业数据、我的平面设计师、我的
video editors, etc.
视频编辑等。
So what what jobs are going to be
那么，未来会有哪些工作呢？
impacted? Yeah, all of those. Uh so I I
受影响了吗？是的，所有这些。呃，所以我我
think and what do they do? You maybe
他们会想什么？他们会做什么？你或许
this is useful for for the audience. I
这对观众来说很有用。我
think if your job is as routine as it
想想你的工作是否像它一样单调乏味。
comes, your job is gone in the next
下一刻，你的工作就没了。
couple years. So meaning if you if in in
几年时间。所以意思是，如果你在……
those jobs for example uh quality
例如，那些工作，呃，质量。
assurance jobs data entry jobs you're
审计工作、数据录入工作，你是
sitting in front of a computer and
坐在电脑前
you're supposed to click uh and and type
你应该点击“呃”然后输入
things in a certain order operator and
按特定顺序操作的事物和
those technologies are coming on the
这些技术即将到来
market really quickly and those are
市场发展速度非常快，这些都是
going to displace a lot of a lot of uh
这将取代很多很多的呃
labor accountants accountants noise yes
劳动会计师 会计师 噪音 是的
I mean I've just pulled a ligament in my
我的意思是，我刚刚拉伤了韧带。
in my foot and they did an MRI scan and
他们给我的脚做了核磁共振扫描。
I had to wait a couple of days for
我等了两天时间。
someone to look at the MRI scan and tell
找个人看看核磁共振扫描结果并告诉
me what it meant. Yeah, I'm guessing
让我明白它的含义。是的，我猜是这样。
that that's gone. Yeah, I think I think
那件事已经过去了。是的，我觉得……
the healthcare ecosystem is hard to
医疗保健生态系统很难
predict because of regulation and and
预测是因为监管和
again there there's so many limiting
再次强调，这里有很多限制因素。
factors on how this technology can
影响这项技术如何运作的因素
permeates the economy because of
由于以下原因，它渗透到经济的各个方面：
regulations and and people's willingness
规章制度和人们的意愿
to to take it. But you know things
接受它。但你知道一些事
unregulated jobs uh that are
不受监管的工作，呃，就是那些
purely text in text out. if your job,
纯文本输入，纯文本输出。如果你的工作是，
you know, you get a you get a message
你知道，你会收到一条消息
and you produce some kind of artifact
然后你创造出某种制品。
that's like probably text or images that
那可能就像文字或图片一样。
that job is is at risk. So, just to give
那份工作岌岌可危。所以，只是为了给
you some stats here as well, about 50%
这里也给你一些统计数据，大约50%。
of Americans who have a college degree
拥有大学学位的美国人
currently use AI. The stats are
目前使用人工智能。统计数据如下：
significantly lower for Americans
美国人的情况要低得多。
without a college degree. So, you can
没有大学学位。所以你可以
see how a splinter might emerge there
看看那里可能会冒出一根木刺。
and that crack will write widen because
而那道裂缝会因为……而扩大。
people like us at this table are all
像我们这张桌子旁的人都是
messing around with it. But my mom and
摆弄它。但是我的妈妈和
dad in Plymouth in the southwest, rural
我爸爸住在西南部的普利茅斯，一个乡村地区。
England, haven't got like they just
英格兰，他们还没有像那样……
figured out iPhones. So like I got them
搞懂了iPhone。所以就像我得到了它们
an iPhone and now they're like texting
有了iPhone，现在他们就像在发短信一样
me back. AI is a million miles away. And
我回来了。人工智能还远在天边。和
if I start running off with my AGI, my
如果我开始带着我的AGI逃跑，我的
agents, that gap is going to widen.
经纪人们，这种差距将会扩大。
Women are disproportionately affected by
女性受到的影响尤为严重
automation, which is what you were
自动化，也就是你所处的时代
talking about there. with about 80% of
谈论那里。约占80%
working women in an at risk job compared
与从事高风险工作的职业女性相比
to just over 50% of men according to the
根据调查，超过50%的男性有此症状。
Harvard Business Review and jobs
《哈佛商业评论》和招聘信息
requiring only a high school diploma
只需高中学历
have an automation risk of 80% while
自动化风险为 80%，
those requiring a bachelor's degree have
那些需要学士学位的人有
an automation risk of just 20%. So we
自动化风险仅为 20%。所以，我们
can see again how how this will cause a
可以再次看到这将如何导致
sort of a it's also a huge risk um with
某种程度上来说，这也是一个巨大的风险。
business processor out outsourcing which
业务流程外包
is essentially western countries sending
本质上是西方国家发送
jobs to India to the Philippines like at
前往印度和菲律宾等地的工作机会
the moment millions of people have been
数百万人的时刻
lifted out of poverty through the
通过……摆脱贫困
ability to do those kind of business
具备开展这类业务的能力
process auto outsourcing jobs and those
流程自动化外包工作和那些
are all going to go but these they're
他们都要走了，但这些是
going to have a thousand employees but
将会有上千名员工，但是
but but uh also uh these people are
但是，呃，还有，呃，这些人是
actually already transitioning to
实际上已经开始过渡到
training AI eyes. Mhm. You know, so so
训练人工智能眼睛。嗯。你知道，就是这样
there's going to be a massive industry
这将是一个庞大的产业。
around training AI until they're
围绕训练人工智能，直到它们
trained. Well, no, you you have to
受过培训。不，你必须
continuously acquire new skills and this
不断获取新技能，而这
is what I'm talking about. I mean, this
这就是我所说的。我的意思是，这
is again if AI is a function of its
如果人工智能是其自身的一个函数，那么问题就再次出现了。
data, then you need increasingly more
然后你需要越来越多的数据
data. And by the way, we ran out of
数据。顺便说一句，我们的……用完了
internet data. I was actually thinking
互联网数据。我当时其实在想
interestingly that this might not be
有趣的是，这可能并非如此。
great for the United States or the UK,
非常适合美国或英国，
the Western world because it is going to
西方世界，因为它将会
be a leveler where now a kid in India
成为一个平等的人，现在印度的一个孩子
doesn't need a Silicon Valley office and
不需要硅谷办公室，
$7 million in investment to throw up a a
投资700万美元用于建造一个
software company basically. My yeah my
基本上是一家软件公司。我的，是的，我的
belief is that so I have a I have a more
我相信，所以我拥有一个，我拥有更多
broad definition of AGI and the
AGI 的广义定义及其
singularity and for me AGI is do we have
对我而言，奇点和通用人工智能（AGI）的问题在于我们是否拥有
artificial general intelligence in terms
就通用人工智能而言
of generally speaking can AI just do
一般来说，人工智能可以做什么？
stuff that humans used to be able to do
人类过去能够做的事情
and we've already crossed that point we
我们已经越过了那个点。
have this general intelligence that we
我们拥有这种普遍的智能
can now all access and 800 million
现在所有人都可以访问，而且有8亿人
people a week are now using uh chat GBT
每周都有人使用聊天 GBT
it's it's exploded in the last 3 months
它在过去三个月里爆发式增长。
and then to me a
然后对我来说
singularity Uh when the first tractor
奇点呃，当第一台拖拉机
went out onto a farm, for me that was a
我去了农场，对我来说，那是一次
singularity moment. Uh because everyone
奇点时刻。呃，因为每个人
who worked in farming, it used to take a
以前从事农业​​的人，需要花费一些时间
100 people to plow a field and now a
100 人耕地，现在
tractor comes along and two guys with
拖拉机开了过来，两个男人……
the tractor can now plow the field in
拖拉机现在可以耕地了。
just as much time and now 98 people out
时间一样长，现在有98人出局
of 100 are completely out of a job. We
其中100人完全失业。我们
also always underestimate a technology
也总是低估一项技术
if it does go on to change history. When
如果它真的能改变历史的话。什么时候
you look back through cars, horses,
你回头看向汽车、马匹，
planes, the Wright brothers just thought
莱特兄弟当时只是在想，飞机……
of a plane as being something that that
把飞机当作某种东西
army could use, we had no idea of the
军队可能会用到，我们对此一无所知。
application. So someone said to me
应用。有人对我说
recently, they said, "When it does
最近，他们说：“当这种情况发生时……”
change the world, we underestimate the
改变世界，我们低估了……
impact that it will change the world."
它将对世界产生影响。
And I see people now with their
我现在看到人们
estimations of AI and AI agents already
对人工智能和人工智能代理的估计已经
incredibly optimistic. And so if history
极其乐观。因此，如果历史
holds here, we're undershooting the
情况就是这样，我们低估了……
impact it's going to have. And I think
它将产生的影响。我觉得
this is the first time in my life where
这是我人生中第一次
the industrial revolution analogies seem
工业革命的类比似乎
to fall a little bit short. Yeah.
略有不足。是的。
Because we've never seen intelligent
因为我们从未见过聪明的
that's like you could I could think of
那就像你能想到的那样
this as a I'm not an intelligent person
因为我不是一个聪明人。
on this, but I could see that as like
关于这一点，但我可以理解为……
the disruption of muscles, whereas this
肌肉紊乱，而这
is the disruption of intelligence. That
这是对情报的干扰。那
that's that's exactly the thing is that
没错，问题就在这里。
what makes human beings special is our
人类的独特之处在于我们的
cognitive capacity and very specifically
认知能力，以及非常具体而言的认知能力
our ability to plug our minds into each
我们有能力将我们的思想接入每一个
other. So that the sum is is uh or the
其他。所以总和是呃或者
whole is greater than the sum of the
整体大于各部分之和
parts. That's what makes human cognition
部分。这就是人类认知能力的构成要素。
special. And what we are doing is we are
特别的。而我们正在做的就是……
creating a something that can
创造某种可以
technologically surpass it without any
技术上超越它，无需任何
of the preconditions that make that a
构成这一目标的先决条件
safe process. So yes, we've
安全过程。是的，我们已经
revolutionized the world how many
彻底改变了世界，有多少？
different times? It's innumerable. But
不同的时代？数不胜数。但
you know, we've we've made farming
你知道，我们已经发展农业了。
vastly more efficient. That's different
效率高得多。那不一样。
than taking our core competency as a
而不是将我们的核心竞争力视为
species and surpassing ourselves with
物种并超越我们自己
the product of our of our labor. I think
我们劳动的成果。我认为
your question is a good one. Then then
你的问题问得很好。然后
what does become? We only have one thing
最终会变成什么？我们只有一样东西
left. Um we have our muscles which we
左边。嗯，我们有肌肉，我们
got rid of in the industrial revolution
在工业革命中被淘汰了
and then we have our intellect which is
然后我们还有我们的智力，那就是
this digital revolution. Now we're left
这场数字革命。现在我们剩下
with emotions and agency. So we
有感情，有自主性。所以，我们
essentially the the the agency idea I
本质上，这就是我提出的代理理念。
think we used to judge people on IQ and
想想我们过去是如何根据智商来评判一个人的，
now IQ is the big leveler and now going
现在智商是最大的平等因素，现在开始
forward for the next 10 years we're
展望未来十年，我们将……
going to look at are you a high agency
打算看看你是不是个高级机构
person or a low agency person. Do you
个人或低能动性的人。你
have the ability to get things done and
有能力把事情做好
coordinate agents? Do you have the
协调代理人？你有吗？
ability to start businesses or give
有能力创办企业或给予
orders to digital armies? uh you know
向数字军队下达命令？呃，你知道的
and and essentially these high agency
以及这些高级机构
people are going to thrive in this new
人们将在这种新环境中蓬勃发展。
world because they have this other thing
世界因为他们还有别的东西
that's been bubbling under the service
这项服务一直暗流涌动。
surface which is really interesting when
表面非常有趣
you said agency is going to remain as an
你说过，该机构将继续作为……
important thing we're sat here talking
重要的事情是，我们坐在这里谈论这件事。
about AI agents and the crazy thing in a
关于人工智能代理和其中的疯狂之处
world of AI agents that have super
拥有超强人工智能代理的世界
intelligence is I can just tell my agent
情报就是我可以告诉我的经纪人
listen I'm going on holiday please build
听着，我要去度假了，请建楼
me a SAS company that spots a market
我是一家能发现市场的SAS公司
opportunity throw up the website post it
抓住机会，在网站上发布帖子。
on my social media channel I'll be in
我会在我的社交媒体频道上出现
Hawaii I and this new agentic world is
夏威夷一号和这个新的能动世界是
stealing that too cuz now it can take
也偷走它，因为现在它可以拿走
action in the same way that I can browse
操作方式与我可以浏览的方式相同。
the internet. I can call Domino's Pizza,
互联网。我可以打电话给达美乐披萨，
speak to their agentic agent, organize
与他们的代理人交谈，安排
my pizza to be there before I even wake
我的披萨在我醒来之前就送到了。
up. And in fact, predictability, you
向上。事实上，可预测性，你
know, OpenAI now learns and Sam Alman
知道，OpenAI 现在可以学习了，还有 Sam Alman
said that they've expanded the memory
他们说他们已经扩容了内存
feature. So, it knows every it's knowing
特征。所以，它知道它所知道的一切。
more and more and more and more about
越来越多，越来越多，越来越多关于
me. It'll almost be able to predict what
我。它几乎可以预测什么
I want when I want it. It'll know
我想要的时候就想要。它会知道
Steve's calendar. He's arriving at the
史蒂夫的日历。他正在抵达
studio. Make sure his cadence is on the
工作室。确保他的节奏正确。
side. Make sure his iPad has the brief
边。确保他的iPad上有这份简报。
on it. Do the brief. Do the research for
就在上面。完成简报。做些调查研究
me. And everything else say remember
我。其他一切都要记住
Brett's birthday so when I arrive
布雷特的生日，所以当我到达时
there'll be something. In fact, it's
总会有办法的。事实上，它是
removing my need for any agency. Yes.
使我不再需要任何机构。是的。
And you know again I don't know how to
你知道，我还是不知道该怎么做。
make this point so that it occurs to
强调这一点，以便人们能够想到
people what I'm really suggesting
各位，我真正想表达的是……
but today maybe it's not conscious but
但今天，这或许并非出于自觉，但
well let me put it to you this way.
那我换个方式说吧。
If you're
如果你是
conscious, you started out as a child
你从孩提时代就开始有意识地思考这个问题。
that wasn't. And although this may not
事实并非如此。虽然这可能并非
fully encapsulate it, you are
完全封装它，你就是
effectively an LLM, right? You go from
实际上就是法学硕士学位，对吧？你从
an unconscious infant to a highly
一个昏迷的婴儿到高度
conscious adult. And the process by
有意识的成年人。以及这个过程
which you do that has a lot to do with
你所做的与此有很大关系
being trained effectively on words and
接受有效的词汇训练
other things in an environment in
环境中的其他事物
exactly the way that we now train these
我们现在就是这样训练他们的。
AIs. So the idea that we can take
人工智能。所以，我们可以采取的想法是
consciousness off the table, it won't be
如果意识因素被排除在外，那就不会是……
there till we figure out how to program
就先这样吧，直到我们弄明白怎么编程为止。
it in and we're safe because we don't
把它放进去，我们就安全了，因为我们没有
know how consciousness works. I take the
了解意识是如何运作的。我接受
opposite lesson. We've created the exact
相反的教训。我们已经创造了精确的
thing that will produce that phenomenon
能够产生这种现象的事物
and then we can have philosophers debate
然后我们就可以让哲学家们展开辩论了。
whether it's real consciousness or it
无论是真正的意识还是……
just behaves exactly as if it were. And
表现得就像它本身就是那样。和
the answer is those aren't different.
答案是它们之间没有区别。
Doesn't matter. And the same thing is
没关系。同样的事情是
true for agency. you know, especially if
对代理机构而言确实如此。你知道，尤其是如果
you've created an environment in which
你创造了一个环境，在这个环境中，
these AIs are de facto competitors, what
这些人工智能实际上是竞争对手，这是什么意思？
you're effectively doing is creating an
你实际上是在创造一个
evolutionary environment in which they
它们所处的进化环境
will evolve to fill whatever niches are
将会进化以填补任何空白。
there. And we didn't spell out the
那里。我们没有明确说明……
niches. So, I have the sense we have um
细分市场。所以，我觉得我们……
we have invited we have we have created
我们已发出邀请，我们已创造
something that truly is going to
真正将会发生的事情
function like a new kind of life and
功能类似于一种新型生活方式，
it's especially troubling because it
尤其令人担忧的是，
speaks our language. So that leads us to
会说我们的语言。所以这就引出了……
believe it's more like us than it is and
相信它比实际情况更像我们，
it's actually potentially quite
实际上它可能相当
different. So but by the way, he's the
不同的。顺便一提，他是
optimist here, right? Like he's so
我是个乐观主义者，对吧？就像他那样
optimistic about LMS and how how they're
对LMS及其运作方式持乐观态度
going to they're going to evolve. Yes.
它们将会进化。是的。
It's amazing. It's amazing technology.
太神奇了。这项技术太神奇了。
Like I think it raised global IQ, right?
我觉得这提高了全球智商，对吧？
Like 800 million people like 800 million
就像8亿人一样，就像8亿人一样
people are that much more intelligent
人们因此变得更加聪明
and emotionally intelligent as well.
而且情商也很高。
Like I know people who previously were
我知道有些人以前是
very coarse and they kind of robbed
非常粗鲁，他们有点像是在抢劫。
people the the the wrong way. They they
人们以错误的方式行事。他们
would say things in not so polite way
说话方式不太礼貌
and then suddenly they started putting
然后突然他们开始……
their the you know what they're saying
你知道他们在说什么
through chat in order to kind of make it
通过聊天来达成某种目的
kinder and nicer and they're more liked
他们更友善、更和蔼，也更受人喜爱。
now. And so not only is it uh making us
现在。所以它不仅让我们……
more intelligent but also it allows us
它更智能，但也使我们能够
to be the best version of ourselves. And
成为最好的自己。和
the the scenario that you're talking
你所说的这种情况
about, I don't think I don't know what's
关于，我觉得我不知道那是什么。
wrong with that. Like, you know, you
这不对。你知道，就像你
know, the I would want less agency in
我知道，我希望我的自主权少一些。
certain places. Like, I would want
某些地方。比如，我想要
something to help me not, you know, open
一些能帮我不至于……你知道的……敞开的东西
up a peanut butter jar at night, right?
晚上偷偷吃一罐花生酱，对吧？
You know, there are places in my life
你知道，我生命中有些地方
where I need more control and I would
我需要更多控制权的地方，我会
rather seed it to some kind of entity
不如把它播种给某种实体
that could help me make better choices.
那可以帮助我做出更好的选择。
I mean unfortunately even if there is
我的意思是，不幸的是，即使有
some small group of elites that are able
一小群能够……的精英
to go to Hawaii while something else
去夏威夷，同时做其他事
does the mundane details of their
他们是否关注那些琐碎的细节？
business
商业
building. We are rather soon going to be
建筑。我们很快就会……
faced with a world that has billions of
面对一个拥有数十亿人口的世界
people who do not have the skills to
不具备以下技能的人
leverage AI. Some of them will be
利用人工智能。他们中的一些人将会是
necessary for a time. you're going to
暂时必要的。你要去
need plumbers. But this is
需要水管工。但这是
also not a long-term solution because
也不是长久之计，因为
not only are there not enough of those
不仅数量不够。
jobs,
工作，
um, but of course we have humanoid
嗯，当然我们有类人生物
robots that once imbued with AI capacity
曾经被赋予人工智能能力的机器人
will also be able to take, you know,
还可以采取，你知道，
they'll be able to crawl under your
它们可以爬到你的下面。
house into the crawl space and fix your
将房子搬到地下室，然后修理你的
plumbing.
水暖工程。
So what typically happens when you have
那么，当你有以下情况时，通常会发生什么呢？
a massive economic contraction that
大规模的经济萎缩
arises from the fact that a huge number
源于大量……这一事实
of people are out of work is that the
失业人数如此之多，是因为……
elites start looking at those people and
精英们开始关注这些人，
thinking well we don't really need them
想想我们其实并不需要它们
anyway. And so the idea that this AI
反正。因此，人工智能的概念就此产生了。
disruption doesn't lead us to some very
混乱并不会给我们带来一些非常
human catastrophe I think is overly
我认为把人类灾难说得太过了。
optimistic and that we need to start
乐观，我们需要开始
preparing right now. What are the rights
正在准备中。什么是权利
of a person who has had whatever it is
指经历过某件事的人
that they've invested in completely
他们已经完全投资了
erased from the list of needs? Is that
从需求清单中删除了吗？是吗？
person responsible for not having
负责不具备以下条件的人
anticipated AI coming? And is it their
期待人工智能的到来？那是他们的吗？
problem that that they are now starving
问题是他们现在正挨饿。
and they're being eyed by others as you
而且他们正被其他人注视着，就像你一样。
know a useless eater? I don't think so.
认识那种吃饭没劲儿的人吗？我不这么认为。
How is it different than uh when the uh
它和呃有什么不同？呃
uh what's it called the the looming
呃，那叫什么来着？迫在眉睫的危机
machine came and the textile workers you
机器来了，纺织工人……
know that the result of the in the lad
知道这小伙子的结果
sort of revolution? uh h how is it how
某种革命？呃，怎么样？
is it different than any time in history
它与历史上任何时期有何不同？
when uh technology uh automated a a lot
当科技自动化程度提高时，很多事情都变得自动化了。
of people out of out of jobs? I would
有多少人失业了？我会
say scale and speed that's how it's
规模和速度就是这样。
different and the scale and speed is
不同，规模和速度是
going to result in a an unprecedented
这将导致前所未有的局面。
catastrophe because the rate at which
灾难发生的速度
people are going to be simultaneously
人们将同时
sidelined not just in one industry but
不仅在一个行业被边缘化，而且
across every industry is just simply uh
各个行业都是如此，简直……
and it also did actually happen. There
而且这件事确实发生了。那里
was a there was an uh for the first 50
前50分钟有个“呃”
years of industrialization from like
多年来的工业化，例如
late 1700s to early 1800s, you actually
从18世纪末到19世纪初，实际上
the Charles Dickens novels are
查尔斯·狄更斯的小说是
essentially people coming from the farms
基本上都是来自农场的人
who are displaced arriving in cities,
流离失所者抵达城市后，
kids living on the streets. Uh the
流落街头的孩子们。呃
British decided to pick everyone up and
英国人决定接走所有人，
send them over to the over to Australia,
把它们送到澳大利亚去。
which is where I came from. um and uh
那是我出生的地方。嗯和呃
you know there there were this there was
你知道，那里有这个。
this massive issue of displacement. I
这场大规模的流离失所危机。我
think we're going to go into a high
我觉得我们会进入一个高……
velocity economy where rather than this
速度经济，而不是这种
long arc of career that lasts 45 years,
长达45年的职业生涯
we're going to have these very fast
我们将很快拥有这些
careers that last 10 months to 36
职业生涯持续10个月至36个月
months. and you invent something, you
几个月。你发明了什么东西，你
take it to market, you put together a
把它推向市场，你组装一个
team of five to 10 people who work
由五到十人组成的工作团队
together, you then get disrupted, you
然后你们一起，就会受到干扰，你们
come Can I mention a story here? Uh
我可以在这里讲个故事吗？呃
there's an entrepreneur that used Replet
有一位企业家使用了Replet
in a similar way. Uh his name is Billy
以类似的方式。呃，他的名字叫比利
Howell. You can find him on YouTube on
豪威尔。你可以在YouTube上找到他
the internet. He would go to Upwork and
互联网。他会去Upwork平台。
he would find what people are asking for
他会找到人们想要的东西。
different requests for certain apps,
针对特定应用程序的不同请求
technologies. Then he would take the
技术。然后他会拿走
what they're asking for, put it into
把他们要求的放进去
replet, make it an application, call
重复，将其变成一个应用程序，调用
them, tell them, "I already have your
告诉他们，“我已经有你的了
application. Would you pay $10,000 for
应用。你愿意花1万美元买
it?" And so, so that's sort of an
它？”所以，这算是一种
arbitrage opportunity that's that's
套利机会，那就是……
there right now. That's not arbitrage.
现在就在那里。那不是套利。
That's theft. How is no what is it? How
那是盗窃。怎么会没有它呢？它到底是什么？如何
is that theft? You have somebody who has
这是盗窃吗？你身边有个人……
an idea that can be brought to market
一个可以推向市场的想法
and somebody else is cryptically
而另一个人则神秘兮兮地
detecting it and then selling back their
检测到它，然后卖回他们的
own idea to them. Well, they're paying
把我自己的想法告诉他们。嗯，他们付钱了。
them to do that. They're saying, "I will
让他们这样做。他们说：“我会
give you $500 if you if someone makes
如果有人赚了，就给你 500 美元
this for me." Right? But this is what I
这对我来说是这样的。”对吧？但这就是我
more or less think is going to happen
大致认为这会发生
across the whole economy is that yes,
从整个经济层面来看，答案是肯定的。
from this perspective, we can see that
从这个角度来看，我们可以看到
everybody is suddenly empowered to build
突然间，每个人都被赋予了建设的权力。
a great business. Well, what do we think
一家很棒的企业。那么，我们怎么看？
about the folks who are going to be
关于那些即将……的人
displaced from the top? What are they
从顶端被挤下去了？这些是什么
going to think about all these people
我会好好想想这些人。
building all of these highly competitive
打造所有这些极具竞争力的设施
businesses? And are they going to find a
企业？他们会找到什么？
way to do, you know, what venture
你知道，该怎么做，什么样的冒险
capital has done or what record
资本已经做了什么，或者说，记录是什么？
producers have done? What they're going
制片人都做了些什么？他们要去哪里
to do is they're going to take their
他们要做的就是采取他们的
superior position at the top and they
他们处于顶端的优越地位。
are going to take most of the wealth
他们将攫取大部分财富
that is produced by all of these people
这是由所有这些人共同创造的
who have these ideas that in a proper
持有这些想法的人认为，在适当的
market would actually create businesses
市场实际上会创造企业。
for them and they're going to parasitize
对他们来说，他们会寄生于……
them. I think that we with this in
他们。我认为我们对此的看法是……
introduction of AI and AI
人工智能和人工智能的介绍
agents old value has moved and now it's
代理商的旧价值已经改变，现在是
not going to be the case that the idea
这个想法不会成为现实。
itself is the moat and it's not going to
它本身就是护城河，而且它不会
be the case that resources are the moat.
资源就是护城河。
So in such a scenario you still have to
所以，在这种情况下，你仍然需要……
figure out distribution. You still have
确定分布情况。你仍然拥有
to have for example like an audience. So
例如，拥有像观众一样的观众群。所以
if you're a podcaster now you have a
如果你现在是一名播客主播，那么你拥有……
million followers on Twitter. you're in
拥有数百万推特粉丝。你已进入
a prime position because you now have
因为你现在处于有利地位。
something that the the great guy with a
这位伟大的人拥有一些……
great idea with no audience has you have
好主意，可惜没有观众。
inbuilt distribution. So I now think
内置分发。所以我现在觉得
actually much of the game might be
实际上，游戏的大部分内容可能是
moving to like yeah still about taste
感觉还是关于口味的。
and idea but also the the mo is
以及想法，但最重要的是
distribution. Yeah. And speaking of
分配。是的。说到这……
adaptive systems um the one of the
自适应系统，嗯，其中之一
adaptation that will happen is people
将会发生的适应是人们
will seek uh humans and will seek proof
将会寻找人类，并会寻找证据
of humanity. Oh, I agree that uh
人类。哦，我同意……
authenticity is going to become the coin
真实性将成为流通货币。
of the realm and anything that can be
王国以及任何可能的东西
faked or cheated is going to be devalued
造假或欺诈所得将会贬值。
and things you know spontaneous jazz or
还有你知道的即兴爵士乐之类的东西
you know comedy that is interactive
你知道那种互动式喜剧吗？
enough that it couldn't possibly have
足以让它不可能……
been generated with the aid of AI those
借助人工智能生成的那些
things are going to become prioritized
事情将会被分清轻重缓急。
you know spontaneous oratory rather than
你知道即兴演讲比
speeches answers some of your questions
演讲解答了您的一些问题
no it answers it answers my question for
不，它回答了我的问题。
the tiny number of people who are in a
极少数人身处
position to do those things. Stephen,
具备做这些事情的能力。斯蒂芬
you use the mo word moat. Um, which I
你用了 mo 这个词 moat。嗯，我
think is a really important word for
“思考”这个词对……来说非常重要。
entrepreneurs. We like we like have to
企业家。我们喜欢我们喜欢必须
have a moat. We think a lot about moes
挖护城河。我们经常思考模子
and it's an industrial age. A lot of
现在是工业时代。很多
people don't even know what a moat what
人们甚至不知道什么是护城河
you mean by moat. It's just I often
你是说护城河吧。只是我经常
think about this idea of what are the
思考一下以下这个想法：什么是
moes that are left. So to define how I
剩下的那些。所以，为了定义我如何
define a mo, you've got a castle and
定义一个 mo，你就有了一个城堡，
it's got a like a small circle of water
它像有一小圈水一样。
around it. And once upon a time that
周围。很久很久以前……
circle of water defended the castle from
一圈水环绕着城堡，保护着它免受伤害。
attack and you can pull up the
攻击，你可以拉起
drawbridge so nobody could attack you
架起吊桥，这样就没人能攻击你了。
very easily. It's a de defense from
非常容易。这是来自……的防御
something. So it's your it's your
某物。所以这是你的，这是你的
shield. It's your your defense. And once
盾。这是你的辩护。而且曾经
upon a time as an entrepreneur, you
曾经作为一名企业家，你
know, I've got a software company in San
我知道，我在圣安东尼奥有一家软件公司。
Francisco called Third Webb and we
弗朗西斯科给Third Webb打了电话，我们
raised almost $30 million. We have a
筹集了近3000万美元。我们有一个
team of 50 great developers. And much of
由 50 位优秀开发人员组成的团队。还有很多
our moat was you can't compete with us
我们的护城河就是：你无法与我们竞争。
if you don't have the 50 developers and
如果你没有那50名开发人员，
the $30 million in the bank. How much of
银行里有3000万美元。多少
that 30 million went to coding? The vast
那3000万美元都用于编程了吗？广阔的
majority of it. I mean what else are we
其中大部分。我的意思是，我们还能是什么呢？
going to do? What else we do? So this is
打算做什么？我们还能做些什么？所以这是
a good thing. I think modes are a bad
这是件好事。我认为模式不好。
thing. Okay, let me make the argument
事物。好的，让我来阐述我的观点。
there. Uh so everyone is looking for
那里。呃，所以大家都在寻找
modes you know for example like one of
你知道的模式，例如其中一种
the more uh significant modes is network
更重要的模式是网络
effects. Yeah, you know, so you can't
效果。是啊，你知道，所以你不能
compete with Facebook or Twitter
与 Facebook 或 Twitter 竞争
because to move people from Facebook or
因为要把人们从 Facebook 转移出去，或者
Twitter, you need to it's the collective
Twitter，你需要它，它是集体的
action problem. You need to move them
行动问题。你需要把它们搬走。
all at once because if one of them
一次性全部发生，因为如果其中一个
moves, then it's the network is not
移动，然后网络就不是了。
valuable, they'll go back. So you have
有价值，他们会回去的。所以你有
this chicken and egg problem. Let's say
这是先有鸡还是先有蛋的问题。比如说
that we have a more decentralized way of
我们有一种更加去中心化的方式
doing social networks that will remove
建立社交网络会移除
the power of Twitter to kind of censor
Twitter 的某种审查能力
and I I think you're at the other end of
而我认为你处于另一端
of censorship, right? And so part of my
审查制度，对吧？所以，我的一部分
optimism about humanity is that um
对人性的乐观就是……
generally there's self-correction.
通常会有自我纠正机制。
Democracy is a self-correcting system.
民主是一个自我纠正的系统。
Uh free markets are largely
自由市场在很大程度上
self-correcting systems. There are
自纠正系统。有
obvious problems with with free markets
自由市场存在显而易见的问题
that that we can discuss. But take um
这是我们可以讨论的。但拿走它们
health, you know, there is obesity uh
健康方面，你知道，还有肥胖问题。
epidemic. This period of time when uh
流行性。这段时间，呃
companies, you know, ran loose kind of
你知道，有些公司管理比较松散。
making this sugary, salty, fatty kind of
制作这种甜腻、咸香、油腻的
snacks and everyone gorged on them and
大家狼吞虎咽地吃着零食。
everyone got very uh you know,
大家都变得非常……你知道的，
unhealthy. And now you have Whole Foods
不良。现在还有全食超市。
everywhere. Today, people in Silicon
到处。如今，硅谷的人们……
Valley, they don't go to bars at all.
山谷里的人根本不去酒吧。
They go to running clubs. That's how you
他们参加跑步俱乐部。就是这样
meet. That's how you go find a date. You
见面。这就是你找到约会对象的方法。你
go to running clubs. And so, there was a
加入跑步俱乐部。所以，就有了
shift that happened because there was a
发生这种转变是因为……
reaction. Obviously, cigarettes is
反应。显然，香烟是
another example. You know, you were
另一个例子。你知道，你曾经是
talking about phones and our addiction
谈谈手机和我们的沉迷
to phones. And I see a shift right now
到手机。我看到现在正在发生转变。
like in my uh friend circle like people
就像我朋友圈里的人一样
who are constantly kind of on their
他们总是有点……
phones is already kind of frowned upon
使用手机已经有点不受欢迎了。
and they don't want to hang out with you
他们不想和你一起玩
because you're you're constantly staring
因为你一直在盯着看
on on your phone. So there's always
在你的手机上。所以总会有办法的。
these reactions and and but the problem
这些反应，但是问题
is you you reference selfcorrection and
你指的是自我纠正和
I agree that there's actually an
我同意确实存在一个
automatic feature of the universe in
宇宙的自动特征
which the self-correction happens. You
自我纠正机制由此发生。你
can't have a positive feedback that
不能有正面反馈
isn't reigned in by some outer negative
并非受制于某种外部负面因素
feedback. But the corrections, the list
反馈。但更正和清单
of corrections involves things like you
纠正措施涉及诸如你之类的事情。
point to where people become enlightened
指出人们获得启蒙的地方
and they realize that they're doing
他们意识到自己正在这样做
themselves harm with either the sugar
糖类本身会对自己造成伤害。
that they're consuming or the dopamine
他们正在摄入的或多巴胺
traps on their phone and they get
他们的手机里有陷阱，他们会中招。
better. But also on the list of
更好的。但名单上还有
corrective patterns are genocide and war
纠正模式是种族灭绝和战争
and you know parasetism. And the problem
你也知道寄生虫病。问题
is these things are destructive of
这些东西具有破坏性吗？
wealth. And so you allude to
财富。所以你暗示了
the superior fact of an open market
开放市场的优越性
without moes. Presumably the benefit of
没有 moes。想必好处是
that is that more wealth gets created
也就是说，会创造更多财富。
because people aren't kept from doing
因为人们并没有被阻止去做某事。
things that are productive. I see that.
有益的事情。我明白了。
But then what is the product of all of
那么，所有这些的最终产物是什么呢？
this new wealth that is going to be
即将到来的这笔新财富
generated by a world empowered by AI?
由人工智能赋能的世界所创造？
Does it end up so highly concentrated
最终浓度会变得如此之高吗？
that you have a tiny number of ultra
你拥有极少量的超高纯度
elites and a huge number of people who
精英阶层和大量民众
are utterly dependent on them? What
完全依赖他们吗？什么
becomes of those people? The learning
这些人中会变成什么样？学习
process, the self-correction pro process
过程，自我纠正专业过程
goes through harm in order to get to
经历伤害才能到达
that more enlightened solution. There's
更明智的解决方案。有
nothing that protects us from the harm
没有什么能保护我们免受伤害
phase being so apocalyptically terrible
阶段性灾难如此可怕
that, you know, we get to the other side
你知道，我们最终会到达彼岸。
of it and we say, "Well, that was a hell
我们回忆起那段经历，然后说：“唉，那真是一场地狱般的噩梦。”
of a correction." Or maybe there's
或许需要纠正。”或者，也许还有……
nobody there to even say that. Those are
当时根本没人会说这话。那些是
also on the table. It reminds me of a
桌上也有。这让我想起……
mouse trap where you see the cheese and
捕鼠器，你会看到奶酪和
we're going, "Oh my god, my
我们当时就想，“我的天哪，我的
grandmother's going to be able to do
奶奶将能够做到
some research and oh my god, my life's
做了一些调查，我的天哪，我的人生……
going to get easier." So you head closer
会变得更容易的。”于是你走近了。
and closer to the cheese.
更靠近奶酪。
And historically, if we look at all of
从历史角度来看，如果我们回顾所有……
the last 10,000 years, it's a very small
过去一万年里，它非常小
number of elites who own absolutely
拥有绝对所有权的精英人数
everything and a very large number of
一切以及大量的
surfs and peasants who have a
冲浪者和农民
subsistence living. You know, if the
自给自足的生活。你知道，如果
elites are too greedy and they freeze
精英阶层太贪婪，他们会冻结一切。
out the peasants at too high a level and
把农民的水平定得太高了
they try to use brutality or Yeah.
他们试图使用暴力，或者，是的。
eventually it comes back to haunt them.
最终，这一切都会反过来困扰他们。
And so what you get is a recognition
因此，你得到的是一种认可。
that you you need a system that does
你需要一个这样的系统
balance these things and you know the
平衡好这些事情，你就知道了。
west has the best system that we've ever
西部拥有我们迄今为止最好的系统。
seen. It's one in which we agree on a
已阅。这是我们一致同意的一件事
level playing field. We never achieve it
公平竞争环境。我们永远无法实现它
but we agree that it's a desirable thing
但我们一致认为这是件好事。
and the closer we get to it the more
我们越接近它，就越
wealth we create. But again,
我们创造的财富。但是，再说一遍，
if AI empowers those with ill
如果人工智能赋予那些患病的人权力
intent at a higher rate that it empowers
意图以更高的频率赋予其力量
those who are wealth creating and
那些创造财富的人和
pro-social, we may be in for a massive
亲社会行为，我们可能即将迎来一场大规模的……
regression in how fair the the market
市场公平性的倒退
that the West is. Is that your top
西方就是这样。那是你的上衣吗？
concern versus economic displacement?
担忧与经济损失？
And I think they're the same thing. How
我认为它们是一回事。如何
are they the same thing?
它们是一回事吗？
because the economic displacement is
因为经济上的流离失所是
going to start. I don't know how
即将开始。我不知道该怎么做
many million people are going to be
数以百万计的人将会
displaced from their jobs in the US.
他们在美国失去了工作。
Suddenly, we're going to have a question
突然，我们就要问一个问题了。
about whether or not we have obligations
关于我们是否负有义务
to them. And you agree with that, don't
对他们来说。你同意这一点，对吧？
you? Yes. But but but again, it's it's
你？是的。但是，但是，但是，再说一遍，是它的
the no pain, no gain. I mean, we're
不经历痛苦，哪来收获。我的意思是，我们是
going to go through a period of of
将经历一段时期
disruption. And I think at the other
干扰。我认为另一方面
end, the old, you know, sort of
结束，旧的，你知道，有点像
oppressive systems will be broken and
压迫性的制度终将被打破，
we're going to create perhaps a fair
我们将创造一个或许公平的局面。
world, but it's going to have its own
它属于这个世界，但它将拥有自己的世界。
its own problems. And what's the scale
它自身的问题。规模是多少？
of that disruption in your estimation?
您认为这种干扰有多大？
It's hard to say because uh you know
很难说，因为你知道……
there's this concept of limiting factors
这里存在限制因素的概念。
like you know there is um regulation
你知道，这方面是有规定的。
there's the appetite of people to today
人们今天有这样的需求。
for example the health care system is
例如，医疗保健系统是
very resistant to innovation because of
由于以下原因，他们对创新非常抵触：
regulation you know and that's a that's
你知道，规章制度就是这样。
a bad thing on the regulation point it's
从监管角度来看，这是件坏事。
worth saying that when Trump came into
值得一提的是，当特朗普上台时
power he signed in a new law which is
他签署了一项新法律，赋予了他这项权力，该法律是
called removing barriers to American
称之为消除美国公民的障碍
leadership in AI which revokes previous
在人工智能领域，领导地位被推翻了之前
AI policies that were deemed to be
被认为符合以下条件的AI政策
restrictive. And obviously when you
限制性的。显然，当你
think about where the funding is going
想想这笔资金的去向。
in AI, it's going to two places. It's
在人工智能领域，它正走向两个方向。它是
going to America and it's basically
去美国，基本上就是
going to China. That's the the vast
去中国。那是广阔的
majority of investment. So with those
大部分投资。所以，有了这些
two in competition, any regulation that
两个竞争者，任何规定
restricts air in any way is actually
以任何方式限制空气流通实际上都是如此。
self-sabotage. Mh. And this is, you
自我破坏。嗯。这就是你
know, I live in Europe some of the time
我知道，我有时会住在欧洲。
and it's already annoying to me that
这让我很恼火。
when Sam Alman and OpenAI released the
当 Sam Alman 和 OpenAI 发布
03 model, this new incredible model,
03 型号，这款全新令人惊叹的型号，
it's not in Europe because Europe has a
它不在欧洲，因为欧洲有
regulation which prevents it from coming
阻止其到来的法规
to Europe. So, we're now at a
前往欧洲。所以，我们现在处于……
competitive disadvantage
竞争劣势
um which Sam Alman spoken about. And
嗯，萨姆·阿尔曼谈到的就是这个。和
more broadly on this point of
更广泛地说，关于这一点
disruption, it was I was quite unnerved
混乱让我感到非常不安。
when I heard that Sam Wolman's other
当我听说萨姆·沃尔曼的其他
startup was called
创业公司叫
Worldcoin. And Worldcoin was conceived
世界币。于是，Worldcoin诞生了。
with the goal of facilitating universal
以促进普遍性为目标
basic income,
基本收入
i.e. helping to create a system where
即，帮助创建一个系统，其中
people who don't have money are given
没有钱的人会得到帮助
money by the government just for being
政府仅仅因为存在就给钱
alive to help them cover their basic
活着是为了帮助他们支付基本生活费用
food and housing needs. Which suggests
食品和住房需求。这暗示
to me that the guy that has built the
对我来说，建造这座建筑的人
biggest air company in the world can see
世界上最大的航空公司可以看到
something that a lot of us can't see
这是我们很多人都看不到的东西。
which is there. Yeah. There's gonna need
它就在那里。是的。需要
to be a system to just hand out money to
成为一个仅仅用来发放金钱的系统
people because they're not going to be
人们，因为他们不会是
able to survive otherwise. I
否则就能生存。我
fundamentally disagree with that. Which
我根本不同意这种说法。哪个
part do you disagree with? I disagree
你不同意哪一部分？我不同意。
that first of all that humans would be
首先，人类将会是
happy with UBI. I I think that you know
对全民基本收入感到满意。我想你知道
uh you know core value of humans and be
呃，你知道人类的核心价值，并且是
curious about the evolutionary reasons
对此的进化原因感到好奇
is we want to be useful. It's really
我们想发挥作用。真是
important to know that a lot of the jobs
需要注意的是，很多工作
that are in at risk are the most high
那些处于风险之中的人风险最高
status, highly paid jobs in the world.
地位，世界上的高薪工作。
Let's take the highest paid job in
让我们来看看收入最高的工作……
America um which is an
美国嗯，这是一个
anesthesiologist. Uh this is the highest
麻醉师。呃，这是最高的
paid job and highest paid salary job.
有偿工作，高薪工作。
Salari job. Yeah. And the majority of
带薪工作。是的。而且大多数
that job is observing a patient, knowing
那份工作是观察病人，了解
which type of medication would work best
哪种药物效果最好？
with their body. um giving them the
用他们的身体。嗯，给他们
exact right amount, monitoring the
精确计量，持续监测
impact of that uh on the on the body and
那对身体的影响
then making slight adjustments, the
然后进行微调，
right technology and any nurse will be
合适的技术，任何护士都会……
able to do that job. And you might have
能够胜任那份工作。你可能拥有
one
一
anesthesiologist on on
麻醉师在
site supervising 10, 20, 30, 40 wards
现场监管10、20、30、40个病房
and the technology is, you know, doing
这项技术正在发挥作用。
the job, but that one person is there
这份工作，但那个人就在那里。
just to kind of supervise if something
只是起到监督作用，看看有没有什么事发生。
went wrong or if there was an ethical
如果出了问题，或者存在道德问题
dilemma. What's wrong with that? I mean,
困境。这有什么问题吗？我是说，
if if if the precision is better where
如果精度更高，那么
they are. No, there's nothing wrong with
没错。不，这没有任何问题。
that except for the fact that a lot of
除了很多……之外
people, hundreds of thousands of people
人，成千上万的人
have spent their entire life training to
他们一生都在接受训练
be that, they get an enormous amount of
即便如此，他们也获得了大量的
purpose and satisfaction about the fact
目的和对此的满足感
that that's their career, that's their
那是他们的事业，那是他们的
job. They have mortgages, they have
工作。他们有抵押贷款，他们有
houses, they have status, and that's
房子，它们代表着地位，就是这样。
about to go away. Well, if it's highest
即将离开。嗯，如果它最高的话。
paid jobs, maybe you should start
或许你应该开始找份有偿工作了。
saving.
保存。
Yeah. Well, I mean, but yeah, I I hear I
是的。嗯，我的意思是，是的，我听说我
hear you, but you're talking about
我明白了，但你指的是……
people who have done vital work. Mhm.
那些做了重要工作的人。嗯。
Highly specialized work and are
高度专业化的工作，并且是
therefore not in a great position to
因此，它处于不太有利的地位。
pivot pivot based on the invention of a
基于一项发明的枢轴枢轴
technology that they didn't see coming
他们始料未及的技术即将到来
because frankly, I mean, in the
坦白说，我的意思是，在
abstract, maybe we all saw AI coming
抽象地说，或许我们都预见到了人工智能的到来。
somewhere down the road, but we did not
后来某个时候，我们没有。
know that it was going to suddenly dawn.
我知道天会突然亮起来。
And we do have to figure out what to do
我们确实需要想办法解决这个问题。
with those people. It's not their fault
和那些人一起。这不是他们的错。
that they've suddenly become obsolete
它们突然就过时了。
and it's inconceivable that people will
人们会这样做是不可想象的。
accept this. It is not. It is
接受吧。它不是。这是
fundamentally incompatible with our
从根本上来说，这与我们的需求不相容。
nature. We have to have things to strive
自然。我们必须有奋斗的目标。
for and you know you can sustain life
因为你知道你可以维持生命
that way but you cannot um sustain a
那样做，但你不能……嗯……维持下去
meaningful existence and so it's a
有意义的存在，所以它是一种
short-term plan at best. Let's talk
充其量只是个短期计划。我们来聊聊吧。
about meaning. Um on that point of job
关于意义。嗯，关于那份工作。
displacement this is already happening.
人口迁移这种情况已经发生了。
Cler CEO who has been on this podcast
Cler 的首席执行官曾做客本播客节目。
before, a great guy, um said to on a
之前，一个很棒的人，嗯，对……说过
blog post that they published on Cler's
他们在 Cler's 上发表的博客文章
website saying that they now have AI
该网站称他们现在拥有人工智能。
customer service agents handling 2.3
客户服务人员处理 2.3
million chats per month, which is equal
每月百万次聊天，相当于
to having to hire 700 full-time people
不得不雇用700名全职员工
to do that. So, they've already been
这样做。所以，他们已经……
able to save on 700 customer service
能够节省 700 元的客户服务费用
people by having air agents to do that.
人们通过雇佣航空代理商来实现这一点。
And they actually they actually got rid
他们实际上真的摆脱了他们。
of those 700 jobs, right? I don't have
那700个工作岗位中，对吧？我没有
that information in front of me, but
我面前的信息就是这样，但是
I'll have a look. Um, I'll throw it up
我看看。嗯，我把它吐出来。
on screen for anyone that wants context
屏幕上会显示相关信息，供任何想要了解情况的人参考。
on that. But that's already happening.
就此而言。但这种情况已经发生了。
This isn't some antologist or something.
这不是什么昆虫学家之类的。
And these aren't high paid people in
而且这些人收入并不高。
every case. We've done something
每一种情况。我们做了一些事
similar, by the way. We've we internally
顺便说一句，情况类似。我们内部
we've
我们已经
we've replaced that function for 70%.
我们已经替换了 70% 的该功能。
Yeah. I mean, our company, we're 65
是的。我的意思是，我们公司，我们有65家分公司。
people and, you know, we um, you know,
人们，你知道，我们，嗯，你知道，
we make, you know, millions per per
你知道，我们每人赚数百万美元
head, you know. So, it's a Are you going
你知道，就是头部。所以，这是“你要去吗？”
to need to hire more people to get up to
需要雇佣更多的人才能达到
I think so, but we're we're hiring
我觉得是这样，但我们正在招聘
slowly, like, you know, we're we're
慢慢地，就像，你知道，我们……
using uh customer support, AI, and that
利用客户支持、人工智能等等
meant that we we need less uh customer
这意味着我们需要更少的客户
support, and we're trying to leverage AI
我们正在寻求支持，并尝试利用人工智能。
as much as possible. the the person in
尽量。那个人
HR at Replet writes software using
Replet公司的人力资源部门使用以下软件编写软件
Replet. So, I'll give you an example.
充盈。我举个例子。
She needed um Orc charts uh software and
她需要兽人图表软件，还有
she looked at a bunch of them, got a lot
她看了看其中很多，买了很多。
of demos and they're all very expensive
演示版很多，而且都很贵。
and they they're missing the kind of
他们缺少那种……
features that she want. For example, she
她想要的功能。例如，她
wanted like version control. She wanted
需要类似版本控制的功能。她想要
to know when when something changed and
知道某事何时发生变化以及
to go back in history. She went into
回到历史中去。她走进了
replet in 3 days she got exactly the
三天后她就回复了，而且回复的内容完全正确。
kind of software that she wanted and
她想要的那种软件
what was the cost you know perhaps $20
大概花了多少钱？大概20美元吧。
you know something like that $ 20 $30
你知道，类似20美元、30美元之类的东西。
once right and um how many employees in
一旦正确，嗯，有多少员工？
HR do we need right now we have two uh
人力资源部，我们现在需要什么？我们有两个……呃
if if they're highly levered like that
如果他们像这样高杠杆的话
maybe we do not need a 20 HR team on
或许我们不需要一个20人的人力资源团队。
this point of
这一点
meaning I've heard so many billionaires
意思是，我听说过很多亿万富翁
in AI describe this as the age of
在人工智能领域，这被描述为……时代
abundance and I'm not necessarily sure
丰富，但我并不一定确定
If abundance is always a great thing
如果富足总是件好事的话
because you know when we look at mental
因为你知道，当我们审视心理问题时，你会发现
health and we look at why how people
健康，我们探讨人们为什么会这样
derive their meaning and their purpose
从中找出它们的含义和目的
in life much of it is having something
人生很多时候都关乎拥有什么。
to strive towards and some struggle in a
努力追求，并在其中经历一些挣扎
meaningful direction to you and this is
对你而言，这是有意义的方向。
maybe adjacent but when there was a
或许相邻，但当有一个
study done I think it was in Australia
我认为这项研究是在澳大利亚完成的。
where they looked at suicide letters and
他们在那里查看了遗书。
in the suicide letters the sentiment of
在遗书中，人们流露出这样的情感：
men in those suicide letters was they
那些遗书中的男人是他们
didn't
没有
feel worthy they didn't feel like they
他们觉得自己有价值，而不是觉得自己不配。
were worth it. They didn't feel like
值得。他们没有这种感觉
they were needed by their families. And
他们的家人需要他们。和
this is much of what caused their
这在很大程度上导致了他们的
psychological state. And I wonder in a
心理状态。我不禁思考……
world of abundance where we, you know, a
这是一个富足的世界，在那里，你知道，我们……
lot of these AI billionaires are telling
很多人工智能亿万富翁都在说
us that we're going to have so much free
我们将会拥有如此多的自由时间
time and we're not going to need to
时间到了，我们也不需要……
work. If there is at all going to be a
工作。如果真的会有……
crisis of meaning, a mental health
意义危机，心理健康
problem. I mean, there already is. And
问题。我的意思是，其实已经有了。和
it doesn't require AI and it's going to
它不需要人工智能，而且它将……
get worse. I don't know what to do about
情况恶化。我不知道该怎么办
it because essentially as human beings
本质上，因为我们都是人类。
we are built like all organisms to find
我们和其他所有生物一样，天生就具有寻找的能力。
opportunity and figure out how to
抓住机会，想办法实现
exploit it. That's what we do. And the
利用它。这就是我们所做的。以及
world you're describing is really the
你所描述的世界实际上是
opposite of that. It's one where you're
相反的情况。这是一个你
effectively having your biological needs
有效满足您的生物需求
at the physiological level satisfied and
在生理层面上感到满意和
there isn't an obvious place for your
没有一个明显的地方可以放置你的
spare time if that's what you end up
如果你最终得到的是空闲时间的话
with to be utilized in something that
可用于某事
you know there's no place to strive and
你知道这里没有奋斗的空间，
I do imagine almost at best what would
我几乎可以想象，充其量会是什么样子。
happen is you have people who are being
发生的事情是，有些人正在……
sustained by a universal basic income
由全民基本收入维持
come and then parasetized
来，然后被寄生
uh you know whatever currency they have
呃，你知道，不管他们用什么货币。
to spend somebody will be targeting it
花钱的人会瞄准它
and they will be targeting it with a an
他们将以某种方式瞄准它
AI augmented system that spots their
人工智能增强系统可以发现他们
defects of character. I mean, again,
性格缺陷。我的意思是，再说一遍，
we're already living in this world, but
我们已经生活在这个世界上了，但是
it will be that much worse when the AI
人工智能出现后，情况会变得更糟。
is figuring out, you know, what kind of
弄清楚，你知道，是哪种
porn to target you with specifically.
专门针对你推送色情内容。
That's uh it's a nightmare scenario. And
那简直是噩梦般的场景。和
I do think it would be worth our time as
我认为这值得我们花时间。
a species to start considering if we are
我们是否应该开始考虑这个物种？
about to find ourselves in this
我们即将发现自己身处其中
situation and we find some way of
情况就是这样，我们想办法……
dealing with the basic needs of the
满足基本需求
large number of people who are going to
大量人员将要
be
是
sidelined. What would a world have to
被边缘化。一个世界将会拥有什么？
look like in order for them to have real
看起来像是为了让他们拥有真正的
meaning? Not pseudo meaning, not
意义？不是伪含义，不是
something that you know superficially,
你略知一二的事情，
you know, a video game is not meaning
你知道，电子游戏并不是……
even if it feels very meaningful in the
即使它感觉很有意义
moment. I I think that would be a a
片刻。我认为那会是一个
worthy investment for us to figure out
值得我们去研究的投资
how to produce it. But frankly, I'm not
如何生产它。但坦白说，我不是。
expecting us to either have that
期望我们要么拥有那种能力，要么拥有那种能力。
conversation or get very far down that
对话或者深入探讨这个问题。
road. I think it's much more likely that
路。我认为更有可能的是……
we will squander the wealth dividend
我们将挥霍财富红利。
that will be produced by by AI.
这将由人工智能产生。
Interestingly, you also see in Western
有趣的是，在西方世界也能看到这种情况。
countries that when we get more
当我们获得更多国家时，这些国家会变得更加
abundance, we start having less kids.
如果经济条件允许，我们就会开始少生孩子。
And we're already seeing this sort of
我们已经看到这种现象了。
population decline in the Western world,
西方世界人口下降
which is was kind of scary. I think it's
这有点吓人。我认为是
often associated with affluence like the
通常与富裕联系在一起，例如
more money someone makes the less likely
收入越高，这种可能性就越小。
they are to want to want to have
他们想要拥有
children the more they try and protect
孩子们越是努力保护自己
their freedoms. But also on this point
他们的自由。但就这一点而言
of
的
AI relationships are hard you know my
你知道，人工智能关系很难建立。
girlfriend is happy sometimes and not
女朋友有时开心，有时不开心
happy other times and I have to like you
其他时候都很开心，而且我必须喜欢你。
know go through that struggle with her
知道要和她一起经历那段挣扎。
of like working on the relationship.
就像努力维系这段关系一样。
Children are hard and if we are
养孩子很辛苦，如果我们
optimizing ourselves and you know much
我们不断优化自身，你也知道很多。
of the reason that I sustain the
我坚持下去的原因是
struggle with my girlfriend is I'm sure
我和女朋友之间的矛盾肯定是存在的。
from some evolutionary reason because I
出于某种进化原因，因为我
want to reproduce and I want to have kin
我想繁衍后代，也想拥有亲属。
but if I didn't have to deal with the
但如果我不用来处理……
struggle that comes with human
人类所面临的挣扎
relationships romantic or platonic
关系是浪漫的还是柏拉图式的
there's going to be a proportion of
将会有一部分
people that actually choose that outcome
那些选择这种结果的人
and I wonder what's going to happen to
我想知道接下来会发生什么……
birth rates in such a scenario because
在这种情况下，出生率会上升，因为
we're already struggling. We're already
我们已经很艰难了。我们已经
in a situation where we used to be
在过去我们身处的那种情况下
having five children per woman in the
平均每位女性生育五个孩子。
1950s to about two in
1950年代到大约两岁
2021. And we're seeing a decline. If you
2021年。我们看到的是下滑趋势。如果你
look at South Korea, their fertility
看看韩国，他们的生育率
rate has fallen to 72, the lowest
利率已降至72，为最低水平。
recorded globally. And if this trend
全球范围内均有记录。如果这种趋势
continues, the country's population
该国人口持续增长
could half by 20, 100.
可能减半，减至 20 或 100。
So yeah, relationships, connections, and
所以，是的，人际关系、联系，以及
and also I guess I guess we've got to
而且我想我们还得……
overlay that with the loneliness
再加上孤独感
epidemic, which
流行病，
is they promised us social connection
他们承诺给我们的是社交联系。
when social media came about, when we
社交媒体出现的时候，当我们
got Wi-Fi connections, the promise was
有了Wi-Fi连接，承诺是
that we would become more connected. But
我们将变得更加紧密联系。但
it's so clear that because we spend so
很明显，因为我们花费了这么多时间。
long alone, isolated, having our needs
长时间独处，与世隔绝，我们的需求
met by Uber Eats drivers and social
由 Uber Eats 司机和社交平台
media and Tik Tok and the internet, that
媒体、TikTok和互联网，就是如此。
we're investing less in the very
我们正在减少对这方面的投资。
difficult thing of like going and making
去制作这样的事情很难。
a friend and like going and finding a
和朋友一起去寻找
girlfriend. Young people are having sex
女朋友。年轻人正在发生性行为
less than ever before. Everything that
比以往任何时候都少。一切
is associated with the difficult job of
与以下艰巨的工作有关
making in real life connection seems to
在现实生活中建立联系似乎
be um falling away.
嗯，正在逐渐消失。
I I will make the case that everything
我将论证一切
that we've discussed here, all the
我们在这里讨论过的所有内容
negative things around loneliness, um
关于孤独的负面看法，嗯
around meaning, they're already here.
关于意义，它们早已存在。
And I don't think blaming technology for
我不认为应该把责任归咎于科技。
all of it is is the right thing. Like I
这一切都是正确的。就像我
think there are a lot of things that
我觉得有很多事情
happened because of existing human uh
发生的原因是因为人类的存在
you know, impulses and and motivations.
你知道，冲动和动机。
Um well I I wanted to go back to where
嗯，我想回到……
you started because I do think that this
你开始这么做是因为我确实认为这一点
maybe is the fundamental question. Why
也许这才是根本问题。为什么
is it that we are already living in a
难道我们已经生活在一个……
world that is not making us happy? And
一个无法让我们感到幸福的世界？和
is that the responsibility of
这是谁的责任？
technology? And I don't think it's
技术？我不认为这是……
exactly technology. Human beings uh
正是科技。人类呃
among our gifts are fundamentally
我们的天赋中，最根本的是
technological whether we're talking
无论我们谈论的是技术还是其他方面，
about quantum computing or
关于量子计算或
flintnapping an arrow
用燧石打制箭
head. What has happened to us that has
头。我们身上究竟发生了什么？
created the growing, spreading, morphing
创造了不断增长、蔓延、变化的
dystopia is a process that Heather and I
反乌托邦是我和希瑟共同探索的一个过程。
in our book, A Hunter Gather's Guide to
在我们的书《狩猎采集者指南》中
the 21st Century, call hyper
21世纪，称之为超高速
novelty. Hypern novelty is the fact of
新奇。 Hypern 的新颖之处在于……
the rate of change outpacing our
变化的速度超过了我们的速度。
capacity to adapt to change. And we are
适应变化的能力。我们是
already well past the threshold here
这里已经远远超过阈值了。
where the world that we are young in is
我们所处的世界，我们年轻时身处的世界是
not the world that we are adults in. And
不是我们成年人所处的世界。
that mismatch is making us sick across
这种不匹配正在使我们生病。
multiple different domains. So the the
多个不同的领域。所以，
question that I ask is is the change
我提出的问题是，这种变化是否真的存在？
that you're talking about going to
你说的要去的地方
reduce the rate of change in which case
在这种情况下降低变化率
we could build a world that would start
我们可以构建一个世界，它将会开始
meeting human needs better open
更好地满足人类需求
opportunities for pursuing meaningful
追求有意义的机会
work. or is it going to accelerate the
工作。或者它会加速这一过程？
rate of change which is in my opinion
变化率，在我看来
guaranteed to make us worse off. So if
只会让我们的处境更糟。所以如果
it was a one-time shift, right, AI is
那是一次性的转变，对吧，人工智能是
going to dawn. It's going to open all
直到黎明。它将开放一切
sorts of new opportunities. There's
各种新的机遇。有
going to be a tremendous amount of
将会有大量的
disruption, but from that we'll be able
虽然会造成混乱，但从中我们将能够
to build a world. Is that world going to
建设一个世界。那个世界将会怎样？
be stable or is it going to be just, you
会稳定吗？还是会像……一样？
know, one event horizon after the next?
你知道，一个接一个的事件视界？
If it's the latter, then it effectively
如果是后者，那么它实际上就……
says what it does to the humans, which
它说明了它对人类的影响，这
is it it's going to dismantle us. When I
它是不是要把我们拆散？当我
look out at society, I I go, okay, it's
看看这个社会，我想，好吧，就是这样。
having a negative impact. When I look at
产生负面影响。当我看着
um individual use cases, it's having a
嗯，具体到个别用例，它具有……
profoundly positive impact. Including
产生深远的积极影响。包括
for me, it's having a very positive
对我来说，这非常积极。
impact. So, it's it's one of these
影响。所以，它是其中之一。
things where I wonder what is that what
有些事让我疑惑，那是什么？
is it that we need to teach people at
我们需要教导人们……
school so that they understand the world
上学是为了了解世界
that we're going into? Because one of
我们要进入的那个领域？因为其中一个
the biggest issues that we're having is
我们面临的最大问题是：
that we're sending kids to school with
我们把这些东西送孩子去上学。
this blueprint, this template that
这份蓝图，这个模板
they're going to have this long arc
他们将经历一段漫长的弧线
career that no longer exists that
已经不存在的职业
essentially we're treating them like
本质上，我们把他们当作……
learning LLMs. And we're saying, "Okay,
学习法学硕士学位。我们说，“好吧，
we're going to prompt you. You're going
我们会提示您。你要走了
to give us the right answer. you're
给我们正确的答案。你是
going to hallucinate it if possible. And
如果可能的话，我要把它幻觉化。和
you know, and and then we go, "Okay, now
你知道，然后我们就说，“好了，现在
go off into the world." And they go,
“去往世界吧。”然后他们就走了。
"Oh, but wait a second. I don't know how
“哦，等等。我不知道该怎么做。”
money works. I don't know how society
金钱能解决问题。我不知道社会是怎样的
works. I don't know how my brain works.
作品。我不知道我的大脑是如何运作的。
I don't know how I meant to handle this
我不知道我原本打算如何处理这件事。
novelty problem. I'm not sure how to
新奇性问题。我不太确定该怎么做
approach someone in a in a social
在社交场合接近某人
situation and ask if they want to go on
了解情况，并询问他们是否想继续。
a date." Um so all the important things
约会。”嗯，所以所有重要的事情
that actually are the important
这些才是真正重要的
milestones that people want to be able
人们希望能够实现的里程碑
to hit and that technology can actually
击中目标，而这项技术实际上可以做到
have an impact on we get no user manual.
这会对我们获取用户手册产生影响。
So I think one of the biggest things
所以我觉得最重要的事情之一
that has to happen is we have to equip
必须要做的是，我们必须配备……
uh young people all through school that
呃，整个学生时代的年轻人都是如此。
to actually prepare them for the world
真正让他们为世界做好准备
that's coming or the world that's here.
那是即将到来之时，还是我们所处的这个世界。
Well on the one hand I think you you
一方面，我认为你
outline the problem very well.
请把问题描述得非常清楚。
effectively we have a a model of what
实际上，我们已经有了一个模型，展示了什么
school is supposed to do that you know
学校本来就应该这么做，你知道的。
at best was sort of a match for the 50s
充其量只能勉强与 50 年代的风格相提并论。
or something like that and it woefully
或者类似的事情，而且非常糟糕
misses the mark with respect to
在这方面未能达到预期效果
preparing people for the world they
培养人们适应世界的能力
actually
实际上
face if we were going to prepare them I
面对现实，如果我们要准备他们的话……
would argue that the only toolkit worth
有人会认为，唯一值得拥有的工具包
having at the moment is a highly general
目前拥有的是一种高度普遍的
toolkit the capacity to think on your
工具包，以及思考你的能力
feet and pivot as things change is the
随着情况变化，脚步和方向都会发生变化。
only game in town with respect to our
就我们而言，镇上只有我们一家公司。
ability to prepare you in advance. Maybe
能够提前为你做好准备。或许
the the other auxiliary component to
另一个辅助组件
that would be teaching you what we know
那将教会你我们已知的知识。
which is frankly not enough about how to
坦白说，这不足以说明如何
live a healthy life. Right? If we could
过健康的生活。正确的？如果我们能
if we could induce people into the kinds
如果我们能够引导人们进入那种状态
of habits of behavior and the
行为习惯和
consumption of food and then train them
消耗食物，然后训练它们
to think on their feet, they might have
他们或许能够随机应变。
a chance in the world that's coming. But
未来世界的一个机遇。但
uh the fly in the ointment is we don't
呃，美中不足的是我们没有
have the teachers to do it. We don't
让老师们去做。我们不
have people who know. And that is the
找些懂行的人。这就是……
question is could the AI actually be
问题是人工智能真的可能……
utilized in this manner to actually
以这种方式利用实际上
induce the right habits of mind for
培养正确的思维习惯
people to live in that world. I I I
生活在那个世界的人。我 我 我
spent a lot of time in education
在教育方面投入了大量时间
technology. One thing that is as we say
技术。正如我们所说，有一件事……
on the internet a black pill about
互联网上流传着一种关于“黑药丸”的说法。
education in general, education
一般意义上的教育，教育
intervention is there's a lot of data
干预措施在于要有大量数据
that shows that there are very little
这表明数量非常少。
interventions you can make in education
你可以在教育领域采取的干预措施
to generate better outcomes. Um and so
为了取得更好的结果。嗯，就是这样。
you know uh there's been a lot of
你知道，呃，发生了很多……
experiment around pedagogy around you
尝试运用你周围的各种教学方法。
know how to configure the the the
知道如何配置
classroom that have resulted in very
课堂产生了非常
marginal improvements. There's only one
微小的改进。只有一个
intervention and this this has been uh
干预，而这已经是……
reproduced many times that creates two
多次复制，产生两个
sigma two standard deviation
西格玛 2 标准差
uh positive outcomes in education
教育中的积极成果
meaning you're better than 99% of uh of
这意味着你比99%的人都强。
of everyone else and that is one-on-one
与其他所有人相比，这是一对一的。
tutoring I thought so I was going to say
辅导？我想是这样的，我正要说……
smaller classrooms and personalization
小班授课和个性化教学
one-on-one tutoring yeah and and but by
一对一辅导，是的，而且，但是通过
the way if you look someone also did a
如果你仔细观察，会发现有人也做了同样的事情。
survey of all the geniuses the
对所有天才的调查
understanders of the world and found
了解世界的人，并发现
that they all had one-on-one tutoring.
他们都接受了一对一辅导。
They all had someone in their lives that
他们生命中都有过这样的人。
took interest in them and tutored them.
对他们很感兴趣，并辅导他们。
So, what can create one-on-one tutoring
那么，什么能创造一对一辅导呢？
opportunity for every child in the
每个孩子都有机会
world? AI. AI. My kids use it and it's
世界？人工智能。人工智能。我的孩子用它，它很……
incredible. Yeah. As in like um they're
极好的。是的。就像……嗯，他们是
interacting and and it's adapting to
它正在互动并适应
their speed. Yes. And um it's giving
他们的速度。是的。而且，它正在给予
them different analogies to work with.
他们可以使用不同的类比方法。
So, like, you know, my son was learning
所以，你知道，我儿子当时正在学习
about division and it's asking him to
关于分裂，它要求他
smash glass and how many pieces he
他打碎了玻璃，他打碎了多少块？
smashes it into with this hammer and,
用这把锤子把它砸碎，
you know, and it's saying things like,
你知道，它还说了这样的话：
"No, Xander, go for it. Really smash
“不，赞德，放手一搏。全力以赴。”
it." And um and he's loving it, right?
“它。”嗯，他很喜欢，对吧？
Is that synthesis? Yeah. Yeah. I'm an
这是合成吗？是的。是的。我是一名
investor in this company. Oh, well, it
这家公司的投资者。哦，好吧。
was it was it's great to watch that
真是太棒了，看这个真好。
simulated one-on-one tutoring because
模拟一对一辅导，因为
it's talking to him. It's asking him
它在和他说话。这是在问他
questions. Brett, you're an educator.
问题。布雷特，你是一名教育工作者。
you uh spent much of your life teaching
你一生中大部分时间都花在了教学上。
people in universities. How do you
大学里的人。你如何
receive all of this? Well, on the one
收到所有这些吗？嗯，一方面
hand, I agree that the uh the closer to
手，我同意，呃，越接近
one to one you get, the better. But I
一对一的交流越好。但我
also personally believe that 0ero to one
我个人也认为 0ero 到 1
is best. And what I mean by that
最好。我的意思是……
is part of what's gone wrong with our
这是我们出现问题的原因之一。
educational system is that it is done
教育体系就是这样运作的。
through abstraction.
通过抽象。
And effectively the arbiter of whether
实际上，他是决定是否……的仲裁者。
you have succeeded or failed in learning
你在学习方面是成功还是失败了
the lesson is the person at the front of
这堂课的主角是站在最前面的人。
the room. And that's okay if the person
房间。如果这个人这样做也没关系。
at the front of the room is truly
房间前面确实是
insightful. And it's terrible if the
很有见地。如果……那就太糟糕了
person at the front of the room is
房间前面的那个人是
lackluster, which happens a lot. So what
平淡无奇，这种情况经常发生。所以呢
doesn't work that way is interaction
互动并非如此运作。
with the physical world in which nobody
在无人存在的物理世界中
has to tell you whether you've succeeded
它必须告诉你你是否成功了。
or failed. If you're faced with an
或者失败了。如果你面临一个
engine that doesn't start, you can't
发动机启动不了，你就没办法了。
argue it into starting. You have to
想方设法让它开始。你必须
figure out what the thing is that has
弄清楚那东西是什么
caused it to fail, and then there's a
导致它失败，然后还有
great reward when you alter that thing
当你改变那件事时，会有巨大的回报。
and suddenly it fires up. So, I'm a big
突然，它启动了。所以，我是一个大
fan of being as light-handed as possible
喜欢尽可能轻柔地处理事情
and as concrete as possible in teaching.
教学中要尽可能具体。
In other words, uh, when I've done it,
换句话说，呃，当我做完之后，
and not just with students, but with my
不仅是对学生，也对我
own children, I like to say as little as
我自己的孩子，我喜欢少说……
possible, and I like to let physical
有可能，而且我喜欢让身体自然发展。
systems tell the person when they've
系统会告诉用户他们何时……
succeeded or failed. And that creates an
成功或失败。这就产生了一种
understanding. You can extrapolate from
理解。你可以从中推断出来
one system to the next. And you know
从一个系统到另一个系统。你知道
that you're not just extrapolating from
你并非只是在进行推断
one person's misunderstanding. You're
一个人的误会。你是
extrapolating from the way things
从事物发展规律推断
actually work. So, I don't know if AI
确实有效。所以，我不知道人工智能是否真的存在。
can be leveraged in that context. My
在这种情况下可以利用。我的
sense is there's probably a way to do
感觉可能有办法做到这一点。
it, but one would have to be deliberate
但这需要刻意为之。
about it, especially with robotics and
关于这一点，尤其是在机器人领域
humanoid robots. Actually, that is that
人形机器人。实际上，就是这样。
is the place uh where where you can do
就是那个你可以做……的地方
this is with robotics that
这是机器人技术方面的问题。
um it seems to me. Yeah. Well, robotics
嗯，我觉得是这样。是的。嗯，机器人技术
will teach you the physical computing
将会教你物理计算
part of it. And then the question is how
其中一部分。然后问题是如何
do you infuse this with AI so that um it
你是否将人工智能融入其中，以便……
is that it you know it provokes you out
你知道，这会激怒你。
of some eddy where you're caught and
你被困在某个漩涡里，
moves you into the ability to solve some
使你具备解决某些问题的能力
next level problem uh that you you
下一个层次的问题，呃，你
wouldn't have found on your own. What do
你不可能自己找到答案。什么
what do you think should be taught in
你认为应该教些什么？
the classroom with everything that you
教室里有你所需的一切
now know? Well, you're all fathers here.
现在知道了吗？嗯，你们都是父亲。
You all have your own children. So, it's
你们都有自己的孩子。所以，就是这样。
a good question for you. How old are
问你个好问题。他们多大了？
your kids? How old are your kids? Uh
你的孩子？你的孩子多大了？呃
three and five. 19 and 21 and six,
三和五。 19、21 和 6，
seven, and 10. My children are very
七岁和十岁。我的孩子们非常
young, but uh we already do use AI and I
虽然年轻，但我们已经在使用人工智能了，而且
sit down with them in front of replet
和他们一起坐在丰盛的食物前。
and we generate ideas and make make
我们产生想法并进行创作
games. And um I would say, you know,
游戏。嗯，我想说，你知道，
what Brett said about generality is very
布雷特关于普遍性的论述非常
important. The ability to pivot and kind
重要的。能够灵活应变且友善
of learn skills quickly. Being
快速学习技能。存在
generative is very very important.
生成式编程非常非常重要。
Having a you know a fast pace of
你知道，快节奏的生活
generating ideas and iterating on those
产生想法并不断迭代
ideas. We sit down in front of Chad GPT
想法。我们坐在查德·GPT对面。
and my kid imagines scenario. Oh, what
我的孩子想象了一个场景。哦，什么？
if you know there's a there's a cat on
如果你知道那里有一只猫
the moon and then you know what if the
月亮，然后你知道如果
moon is made of cheese and what if
月亮是用奶酪做的，如果……
there's a mouse inside it or and so we
里面有只老鼠，所以我们
keep generating these um variations of
不断生成这些嗯……的变体
these different ideas and I and I find
这些不同的想法，以及我发现
that you know makes them more
你知道这会让他们更
imaginative and and creative. Uh rule
富有想象力和创造力。呃规则
number one that I tell my kids is stay
我告诉孩子们的第一件事就是：留下来。
away from porn at all costs. I'd rather
无论如何都要远离色情内容。我宁愿
you have a drug problem than a porn
你的问题与其说是色情，不如说是毒品。
problem. And I actually mean that. I
问题。我是认真的。我
think it's I think porn is more
我觉得色情片更……
dangerous to the to the human being as
对人类来说很危险
as bad as a drug problem is. But when we
就像毒品问题一样糟糕。但当我们
get to the question of how to confront
回到如何应对这个问题上来。
the world and uh the things that you're
这个世界，还有你所拥有的一切
going to be um expected to to do in the
预计会这样做
workplace and all of that, my point to
工作场所等等，我的观点是
them is you are facing the uh the
他们就是你面对的那个呃
dawning of the age of complex systems
复杂系统时代的曙光
that you are going to have to interact
你将不得不进行互动
with. And in the age of complex systems,
和。在复杂系统时代，
you have to understand that you cannot
你必须明白你不能
blueprint a solution. And you have to
制定解决方案蓝图。你必须
approach these systems with a upgraded
以升级后的方式对待这些系统
toolkit of humility because the ability
谦逊的工具包，因为这种能力
of the system to do something you don't
让系统去做你不想做的事情
predict is much greater than a highly
预测远大于高度
complicated system. So you have to
复杂的系统。所以你必须
anticipate that and be very sensitive to
预料到这一点，并对此保持高度敏感。
the fact that what you intended to
你的意图是
happen is not what's going to happen. So
发生的事情并不等于将会发生的事情。所以
you have to monitor the unintended
你必须监控意外情况
consequences of whatever your action is
你的行为所带来的后果是
and that there are really two tools
实际上有两种工具
which work. One of which you just
哪些方法有效？其中之一就是你刚刚
mentioned which is the prototyping. You
提到了原型制作。你
prototype things. You don't imagine that
制作原型。你不会想到这一点吧。
I know the solution to this and I'm
我知道解决办法，而且我是
going to build it. You imagine I think
准备建造它。你想象着我想
there's a solution down there. I'm going
下面肯定有解决办法。我要去
to make a proof of concept and then I'm
先做一个概念验证，然后我
going to discover what I don't know and
去发现我不知道的事情
I'm going to make the next version.
我打算制作下一个版本。
Discover what I don't know and
发现我不知道的事情
eventually you may get to something that
最终你可能会遇到一些事情
actually truly accomplishes the goal. So
实际上确实达到了目标。所以
prototyping is one thing.
制作原型是一回事。
And also instead of using the blueprint
而且，与其使用蓝图，不如直接使用蓝图。
as the metaphor in your mind uh navigate
正如你脑海中的隐喻一样，呃，导航
you can navigate somewhere. And you know
你可以导航到某个地方。你知道
that the way I think of it is a surfer
在我看来，他就像个冲浪者。
is in some ways mastering a complex
在某种程度上，掌握复杂
system but they're not doing it by
系统，但他们并没有这样做。
planning their days surfing down the
他们计划着每天冲浪的行程
waves. You can't do that. What you can
波浪。你不能那样做。你能做什么
do is you can be expert at absorbing
你要做的就是成为吸收方面的专家。
feedback and navigating your way down
反馈和向下导航
the wave. and that that's the right
波浪。而且那才是正确的
approach for a complex system. Nothing
复杂系统的方法。没有什么
else is going to work. And so I guess
否则就得上班。所以我想
the final piece is uh general tools
最后一部分是通用工具。
always no specialization. This is this
始终不进行专业化分工。这就是这个
is the age of generalists and um invest
现在是通才和投资的时代
in those tools and they will pay.
使用那些工具，他们会付出代价。
So the guiding philosophy for me is uh
所以，我的指导理念是……
to produce high agency generalists. So
培养高素质的通才型人才。所以
um ultimately I want them to be
嗯，最终我希望他们能
motivated self-starters and have a wide
积极主动、自我驱动力强，且拥有广泛的技能。
general toolkit. I imagine them very
通用工具包。我想象他们非常
much what you imagine which is
就像你想象的那样。
instructing robots, instructing agents,
指导机器人，指导代理，
coming up with ideas. Um, and I imagine
提出想法。嗯，我想
them having a very high velocity life
它们拥有非常高的寿命
where they may be writing a book,
他们可能正在那里写书，
organizing a festival, having a podcast,
组织节日活动，制作播客节目
starting a business, and being part of
创办企业，并成为其中的一员
somebody else's business all at once as
别人的事，一下子全都变成了
they are of the ADHD. Yeah. Right.
他们患有注意力缺陷多动障碍。是的。正确的。
Exactly. Um, so the high agency
确切地。嗯，所以，高层机构
generalist is the kind of guiding
通才是一种指导方式
philosophy. Some of the things that we
哲学。我们的一些事情
do is like we do chess, we do Brazilian
就像我们下国际象棋一样，我们玩巴西橄榄球。
jiu-jitsu, we do dancing, we do acting
我们练柔术，我们跳舞，我们演戏
classes, playing in nature, uh
上课、在大自然中玩耍，嗯
entrepreneurship, understanding that you
创业精神，理解你
can start a lemonade. We just did
可以开始做柠檬水了。我们刚刚就这么做了
lemonade stands which was amazing. U we
柠檬水摊真是太棒了。我们
sold lots of lemonade on the street. So
在街头卖了很多柠檬水。所以
those kind of things and jumping from
诸如此类的事情以及跳跃
one thing to the next thing, but also
一件事接着一件事，但也是
trying to avoid too many screens and
尽量避免使用过多屏幕
forcing them into making stuff from
强迫他们用……制造东西
what's going on around the house. Um,
家里发生了什么事？嗯，
some distinctions that we try and give
我们试图给出一些区别。
them is the difference between creating
它们之间的区别在于创造与否。
and consuming because I think AI has
而且我认为人工智能有
this superpower of making you a hyper
这种超能力让你变得超强
consumer or a hyper creator. Um, and if
消费者还是超级创作者？嗯，如果
you don't understand the distinction
你不理解其中的区别。
between creation and consumption, you
在创造和消费之间，你
end up falling into the consumption
最终陷入消费之中
trap, whether it be porn or just news or
陷阱，无论是色情内容还是新闻报道
um, thing, you know, things that feel
嗯，那种感觉，你知道，那种感觉
like you're productive, but you're
看起来你工作效率很高，但实际上你……
actually just consuming stuff. Won't
其实只是消费而已。惯于
that be the most successful AI? the one
那会是最成功的人工智能吗？那个
that plays with my dopamine the most.
最能刺激我多巴胺分泌的那个。
Yeah. And and makes you and makes you
是的。而且让你，让你
think that you're achieving something
你觉得自己正在取得一些成就。
when you're actually just consuming
当你实际上只是在消费时
something. So trying to give them the
某物。所以努力给他们
understanding that there is this
理解这一点
difference in their life between
他们生活中的差异
creation and consumption and to be on
创造和消费，以及存在
the creation side. I started my first
创作方面。我开始了我的第一个
business at 12 years old and I started
我12岁就开始做生意了。
more businesses at 14, 15, 16, 17 and
14、15、16、17 号及周边地区还有更多商家。
18. And at that time, what I didn't
18. 而那时，我却不知道
realize is that being a founder with no
意识到这一点就是，作为一名创始人，没有
money meant that I also had to be the
金钱意味着我也必须成为……
marketeteer, the sales rep, the finance
市场营销人员、销售代表、财务人员
team, customer service, and the
团队、客户服务和
recruiter. But if you're starting a
招聘人员。但如果你正准备开始一个
business today, thankfully, there's a
值得庆幸的是，如今的商业环境是……
tool that wears all of those hats for
一款集所有这些功能于一身的工具
you. Our sponsor today, which is
你。我们今天的赞助商是
Shopify. Because of all of its AI
Shopify。因为它的所有人工智能
integrations, using Shopify feels a bit
使用 Shopify 进行集成感觉有点
like you've hired an entire growth team
就像你雇佣了一整个增长团队一样
from day one, taking care of writing
从一开始，就负责写作。
product descriptions, your website
产品描述，您的网站
design, and enhancing your products
设计和改进您的产品
images, not to mention the bits you'd
图片，更不用说你会看到的其他部分了。
expect Shopify to handle, like the
预计 Shopify 会处理，例如
shipping, like the taxes, like the
运输，就像税收，就像
inventory. And if you're looking to get
存货。如果你想获得
your business started, go to
您的企业已经启动，请前往
shopify.com/bartlet and sign up for a $1
访问 shopify.com/bartlet 并注册，即可获得 1 美元奖励。
per month trial. That's
每月试用期。那是
shopify.com/bartlet.
shopify.com/bartlet。
The thing that we I think all agree on
我想我们都同意的一点是
is that this is inevitable. Do you agree
这是不可避免的。你同意
with that, Brett? I think it's sad that
就这样，布雷特？我觉得这很令人难过。
it is inevitable, but at this point it
这是不可避免的，但到了现在这个地步……
is. What part of it do you find sad?
是。你觉得其中哪一部分令人难过？
We have squandered a long period of
我们浪费了很长一段时间
productivity and peace in which we could
我们能够在生产力和和平的环境中工作和生活。
have prepared for this moment. and our
我已经为这一刻做好了准备。以及我们的
narrow focus on competition
专注于竞争
has created
已创建
a a fragile world that I'm afraid is not
一个脆弱的世界，恐怕并非如此。
going to survive the disruption that's
能够挺过这场动荡吗？
coming. And it didn't have to be that
未来。事情原本不必如此。
way. This was foreseeable. I mean,
方式。这是可以预见的。我是说，
frankly, the movie 2001, which came out
坦白说，电影《2001太空漫游》上映时……
the year before I was born, anticipates
在我出生前一年，预示着
some of these problems. And you know we
其中一些问题。你知道我们
treated it too much like education. I
把它当成教育来对待了。我
mean like entertainment and not enough
意思是像娱乐，但不够。
like education. So we are now you know
例如教育。所以我们现在知道了
we've had the AI era opened without a
我们已经开启了人工智能时代，却没有……
discussion about its implications for
讨论其对……的影响
humanity. There is now for game
人类。现在游戏开始了
theoretic reasons no way to slow that
理论上讲，没有办法减缓这种情况。
pace because as you point out if we
速度，因为正如你所指出的，如果我们
restrain ourselves we simply put the AI
我们克制住自己，简单地说，人工智能
in the hands of our competitors. That's
落入竞争对手手中。那是
not a solution. So, I don't advocate it,
这不是解决办法。所以，我不提倡这样做。
but there's a lot more preparation we
但还有很多准备工作要做。
could have done. We could have
本来可以做到的。我们本可以
recognized that there were a lot of
意识到有很多
people in jobs that were uh about to be
那些即将失业的人
obliterated and we could have thought
被彻底摧毁，我们本可以这样想。
deeply about what the moral implications
深入探讨其道德含义
were and what the solutions at our
我们当时的解决方案是什么？
disposal might have been. And having not
处置方式可能如此。而且没有
prepared, it's going to be a lot more
做好准备，将会更加……
carnage than it needed to be. Amjad, I
这场屠杀远比原本应该的要惨烈得多。阿姆贾德，我
heard you say a second ago that what we
刚才我听到你说我们
should be talking about is how we deal
我们应该讨论的是我们如何应对
with job displacement. Do you have any
导致工作岗位流失。你有吗？
theories if you were prime prime
如果你是质数，那么你的理论是什么？
minister or president of the world and
世界部长或总统
you your job was to deal with job
你的工作是处理工作
displacement let's just say in the
位移，我们姑且说是在……
United States how would you go about
美国，你会怎么做？
that the first thing I would do is uh
我首先要做的事情是……
teach people about these systems whether
无论是否向人们讲解这些系统
it's um programs on on the TV or
嗯，是电视节目，或者
outreach or or what have you just trying
外联或其他什么，你只是在尝试什么？
to get people to understand how chat GBT
让人们了解聊天 GBT 的运作方式
works how these algorith algorithms work
这些算法的工作原理是什么？
and as the new jobs arrive um I think
随着新工作的到来，嗯，我想
you know there's going to be an
你知道将会出现一个
opportunity for people to be able to
让人们有机会能够
detect that you know the this job
检测到你了解这份工作
requires this set of skills and I I I
需要这套技能，而且我
have this this kind of experience and
拥有这种经验
although my experience are potentially
尽管我的经验可能
outdated I can repurpose that experience
虽然经验已经过时，但我可以重新利用这些经验。
to do that job I'll give you an example
为了完成这项工作，我举个例子。
a teacher his name is Adil Khan you know
你知道吗？一位名叫阿迪尔·汗的老师。
he started using at the time GPT3 and uh
他当时开始使用GPT3，呃……
felt like it does amazing work as a
感觉它作为一款产品表现出色
tools for teachers or even potentially a
教师工具，甚至可能是
teacher itself. So he learned a little
教师本身。所以他学到了一点东西。
bit of coding and he he went to
写了一点代码，然后他就去了
Unreallet and he built uh this company
Unreallet 和他创建了这家公司
and um just two years later they're
仅仅两年后，他们就……
worth hundreds of millions of dollars.
价值数亿美元。
Obviously, not everyone will be able to
显然，并非所有人都能做到这一点。
create businesses of that scale, but
创建如此规模的企业，但是
because you have an experience in a
因为你在这方面有经验
certain domain, you'll be able to build
在特定领域，您将能够构建
the next iteration of of of that using
下一次迭代使用该
technology. So, even if your job was
技术。所以，即使你的工作是
displaced, you'll be able to figure out,
即使流离失所，你也能想办法解决。
you know, what's what's potentially what
你知道，什么是潜在的……
potentially comes after that. So, so I I
可能在此之后。所以，所以我我
I think people's expertise that they
我认为人们的专业知识
built, I don't think they're all for
建造的，我不认为它们都是为了
waste. Even if your job went away,
浪费。即使你失去了工作，
you can never really predict what jobs
你永远无法真正预测哪些工作会是什么样的。
are coming. I mean, I think of this
即将到来。我的意思是，我想到这一点
crazy situation where I tell my
情况很疯狂，我告诉我
grandfather, what is a personal fitness
爷爷，什么是个人健身？
trainer? And he would his mind would be
教练？而他的心思会是……
blown by this idea that well, okay, I
这个想法让我震惊，好吧，我
don't really want to go to the gym, so I
我其实不太想去健身房，所以我
have to make an appointment and pay
需要预约并付费
someone to go to the gym and meet with
找个人一起去健身房见面
me there. And then he stands there and
我在那儿。然后他就站在那里，
tells me to lift heavy things that I
让我举起重物
don't really want to lift. And then he
我其实不太想举重。然后他
counts them and tells me that I've done
他数了数，然后告诉我我已经做完了
a good job and then I put the heavy
干得好，然后我把重物放上去。
things down and then at the end of that
事情进展顺利，然后到了最后……
I feel really good and I pay him a bunch
我感觉非常好，我付给他一大笔钱。
of money. My grandfather would be like
钱。我祖父会是这样的
what on earth have you been scammed? Is
你到底被骗了什么？是
this so we can never predict what what
这样我们就永远无法预测会发生什么。
this uh future of jobs would look like.
这就是未来就业的大致样貌。
Even just 20 30 40 years apart the jobs
即使仅仅相隔20、30、40年，这些工作
rapidly and convincingly just morph into
迅速而令人信服地变成
something else. I think it's very
别的什么。我觉得非常
dangerous the idea that we need to focus
认为我们需要集中精力的想法很危险
on skills. I think the future is not in
关于技能。我认为未来不在于……
skills. Skills are being replaced. It's
技能。技能正在被取代。它是
this idea that the education system has
这种认为教育系统已经存在的想法
to stop being compartmentalized and has
不再被割裂，并且已经
to be a lifelong learning approach. The
养成终身学习的习惯。这
department of education needs to be
教育部门需要
seeing people as lifelong learners who
将人们视为终身学习者
are constantly disrupted and need
不断受到干扰，需要
re-education. Interesting. That that's
再教育。有趣的。那就是
going to be a thing. The Department of
将会成为一种现象。该部门
Education needs to start as a kid and go
教育需要从孩提时代开始，并持续到成年。
right through to maybe 70. Does the
一直到可能70岁。
Department of Education have a role
教育部门发挥着作用
anymore at all? Depends on your
还有吗？这取决于你的
definition of education. I think if
教育的定义。我认为如果
you're trying to teach kids or if you're
你是想教孩子，还是想……
trying to teach kids to, you know,
试图教孩子们，你知道，
remember facts and figures from a
记住来自 A 的事实和数据
history book, then no. But if it's about
历史书上没有。但如果是关于
coaching, mentoring, being displaced,
指导、辅导、失业、
finding the next thing, and maybe if
寻找下一个目标，也许如果
it's AIdriven and all of those kind of
它是人工智能驱动的，等等。
things, then it's a different paradigm
如果情况不同，那就属于另一种范式了。
shift around what education is and what
转变对教育的理解和态度
its purpose is. And if we see it as a
它的目的是。如果我们把它看作是一个
fluid thing where we wave into an
流动的东西，我们挥手进入其中
opportunity and then wave back into
机会，然后挥手告别。
education, spotting a new opportunity
教育，发现新机遇
and then back here. If we're learning
然后又回到这里。如果我们正在学习
rather than skills, but we're learning
与其说是技能，不如说是我们正在学习的东西
tools. So it's a tools-based education
工具。所以这是一种以工具为基础的教育
as opposed to a skills-based education.
与技能型教育相对。
The the purpose of education for most of
对大多数人来说，教育的目的是
human history was about virtue, about
人类历史是关于美德的，是关于
becoming a great person who had good
成为一个伟大的人，一个有良好品格的人
judgment and who had good values. And we
判断力强，且具有良好价值观。我们
don't really do much of that anymore.
现在很少做那种事了。
But I think if we essentially said if we
但我认为，如果我们基本上说如果我们
get back to what is if we ask the
如果我们问“什么是……”，请回到正题。
question what is the purpose of
问题：其目的是什么？
education and where does it fit in our
教育以及它在我们的生活中扮演什么角色
lives and at what time frame does it go
生命以及它在什么时间段内会持续存在
for and then we just trust that people
然后我们就只能相信人们
are going to come up with weird and
他们会想出一些奇怪的办法，而且
wonderful jobs. You know this is sounds
很棒的工作。你知道这听起来很悦耳。
crazy but also and this is a weird
疯狂，但同时，这也很奇怪
analogy. My cat is incredibly happy. How
类比。我的猫咪非常开心。如何
do you know? Well, it it demonstrates
你知道吗？嗯，这说明了很多问题。
all the characteristics of of being a
作为一个人的所有特征
happy cat and it lives in a world of
一只快乐的猫，它生活在一个……的世界里
super intelligence as far as it's
就其而言，超级智能
concerned. So, there's this house and
担心的。所以，这里有一栋房子，
food just magically happens. It has no
食物就像变魔术一样出现了。它没有
idea that there's this Google calendar
想到谷歌日历
that runs a lot of things that happen
它运行着很多事情。
around it. The food gets delivered. The
周围。食物已经送到了。这
money is magically made by something
金钱仿佛凭空而来。
that is inconceivably more intelligent
那简直智能得不可思议。
than the cat. And yet the cat has
比猫还不如。然而，这只猫却……
evolved to be living this life of
逐渐演变成过着这样的生活
purpose and meaning inside the house.
房屋内部的用途和意义。
And as far as it's aware, it it's got a
据它所知，它有一个
great life. But you have the power at
美好的生活。但你拥有这种力量
any moment if you're having a bad day to
如果你今天过得很糟糕，任何时候都可以
do something not so pleasant to that
对那个人做些不太愉快的事。
cat. And it can't really reciprocate
猫。而且它也无法真正互惠。
that. Exactly. But but what's in it for
那。确切地。但是，这样做有什么好处呢？
me to hurt the cat?
让我伤害猫？
Because the in this analogy, you might
因为在这个类比中，你可能会
want to move house and the landlord
想搬家，房东
doesn't allow cats. So you've got a
不允许养猫。所以你有一个
decision to make. Yeah, that there are
需要做出决定。是的，确实有
things that the cat is highly disrupted
猫咪极度不安的事情
by due to no fault of the cat. I get it.
这并非猫的过错。我得到它。
But as far as cat existence goes and the
但就猫的生存而言，
and the history of cats, if you were to
以及猫的历史，如果你要……
ask that cat, do you want to tra trade
问问那只猫，你想交换吗？
places with any of the other cats that
和其他猫待在一起的地方
came before you? It would probably say,
在你之前？它可能会说：
I don't want to take the risk because
我不想冒这个险，因为
all the other cats had to fend for
其他所有猫都得自己想办法。
themselves in a way that I don't have
他们以我所不具备的方式展现自己。
to. It's very possible that we live end
到。我们很有可能活到最后。
up living in a life a lot like the house
过着与房子非常相似的生活
cat in the sense that from our
从某种意义上说，猫就是我们
perspective we're extremely like we're
从某种角度来看，我们和我们非常相似
having very interesting lives and
拥有非常有趣的生活
purpose meaning and just there's this
目的、意义，以及仅此而已
massive higher intelligence that's just
巨大的更高智能，那只是
running stuff and we don't know how it
运行程序，但我们不知道它是如何运行的。
works but it doesn't really matter
有效，但其实无关紧要。
whether how it works. We we we are the
它是如何运作的。我们，我们，我们是
beneficiaries of it and it it's doing
它的受益者以及它正在做的事情
important things and we're enjoying
重要的事情，我们很享受。
being house cats in in its in its life.
成为家猫，在它的一生中。
I have a few things to say about this.
关于这一点，我有几点要说。
One, I'm pretty sure your cat's not as
第一，我很确定你的猫没那么……
impressed with your capacity as you are
你的能力给我留下了深刻的印象。
or as you think he is. Um I just know
或者像你认为的那样。嗯，我只是知道
cats well enough to be pretty sure of
猫咪们状况良好，足以让我相当肯定
that. But oh, it looks down on me. Yeah,
那。但是，它却居高临下地看着我。是的，
you're right. I think it I think it's a
你说得对。我认为，我认为这是一个
fair it's a fair point that there is an
公平地说，确实存在这样一个合理的观点：
existence and actually, you know, pets
存在，以及，你知道的，宠物
really do have it. If they have loving
确实有。如果他们有爱
owners, they really do have it pretty
业主们，他们的确拥有非常漂亮的房子。
great. And I would also point out that
伟大的。我还想指出，
there's a way in which we already are
我们已经以某种方式存在了
this way. Most of us do not understand
这边走。我们大多数人都不明白
the process that results in electricity
产生电的过程
coming out of the walls of our house or
从我们家的墙壁里冒出来，或者
the water that comes out of the tap. And
从水龙头里流出来的水。和
we're pretty much okay with the fact
我们基本能接受这个事实
that somebody takes care of that and we
有人会处理这件事，而我们
can busy ourselves with whatever it
我们可以忙于任何事情。
might be. But the place that I find
有可能。但我发现的地方
something troubling in your description
你的描述中有些令人不安的地方。
is that you say that the nature of what
也就是说，你认为……的本质是什么？
we do is to deal with the fact that jobs
我们要做的是应对就业问题。
are always being upended. That's a very
总是不断被颠覆。那是一个非常
new process. That is the hypern novelty
新流程。这就是超新奇之处
process. It used to be that it was only
过程。过去只有
very rarely that a population had a
极少情况下，一个群体会出现这种情况。
circumstance where you didn't
你没有遇到的情况
effectively do exactly what your
有效地完成你所做的事情
immediate ancestors did. Right? Um, in
直系祖先确实如此。正确的？嗯，在
general, you took what the jobs were,
总的来说，你接受了那些工作。
you picked something that was suited to
你选择了一件适合……的东西
you, and you did that thing
你，你做了那件事
intergenerationally.
代际之间。
Intergenerationally. And the point is,
代际差异。关键在于，
we've now gotten to the point where even
我们现在已经到了即使
within your lifetime, what is possible
在你的一生中，可能发生的事情有哪些
to get paid for is going to shift
获得报酬的方式将会发生变化
radically in ways that nobody can
以任何人都无法企及的方式进行彻底的变革
predict. And that is a dangerous
预测。那很危险
situation. Like probably every two
情况。大概每两个
years, like two or three years, right?
比如两三年，对吧？
And so maybe there's some model by which
所以或许存在某种模型，可以以此为指导。
we can surf that wave and you can learn
我们可以乘风破浪，你也可以学习
a generalist toolkit and you know that
一个通用工具包，你知道的。
your survival doesn't depend on your
你的生存并不取决于你
being able to you know switch up every
能够随时切换
two years and never miss a beat or maybe
两年了，从未间断，或者也许
we can't but I do think it is worth
我们做不到，但我认为这是值得的。
asking the question if the rate of
问：利率是否
technological change has taken us out of
技术变革使我们摆脱了
the normal human circumstance of being
人类正常的生存状态
able to deduce what you might do for a
能够推断出你可能会做什么
living based on what your ancestors did
按照祖先的做法生活
and put us in a situation where what
并将我们置于这样的境地：
your ancestors did is going to be
你的祖先所做的事将会是
perfectly irrelevant no matter what. But
无论如何，这都完全无关紧要。但
that is effectively a choice that has
这实际上是一种选择，它有
been made for us. And we could choose to
专为我们而造。我们可以选择
slow the rate of change so that we would
减缓变化速度，以便我们能够
live in some kind of harmony where our
我们生活在某种和谐之中。
developmental environment and our adult
发展环境和我们的成人
environment were a match. Now, as a
环境很匹配。现在，作为
biologist, I would argue if we don't do
作为一名生物学家，我认为如果我们不这样做……
something like that, this is a matter of
类似的事情，这是个问题。
time. Yeah. How would we change? How do
时间。是的。我们会如何改变？如何
we slow the rate of change? Well, I I
我们减缓变化的速度吗？嗯，我
mean, you can you can you can be the
意思是，你可以，你可以，你可以成为
Amish, right? You can be the Amish and
阿米什人，对吧？你可以成为阿米什人，
live in your own communities and and I
生活在你们自己的社区里，而我
would assume some people would would
会认为有些人会
want that. Well, I'm you know, when
想要那个。嗯，你知道，当
Heather and I wrote our book, I wanted
我和希瑟合写了我们的书，我想要
the first chapter to be, are the Amish
第一章要介绍的是阿米什人。
right? And the answer is they can't be
正确的？答案是他们不可能……
exactly right because they picked an
完全正确，因为他们选择了一个
arbitrary moment to step off the
随意选择下车的时机
escalator. But are they right that
自动扶梯。但他们的说法正确吗？
there's something dangerous about this
这其中有些危险之处。
continuing pattern of technological
技术持续发展模式
change? Clearly they are. What do the
改变？显然他们就是。什么
Amish do for anyone that doesn't know?
阿米什人是做什么的？（给不了解的人解释一下）
The Amish live as if it was what 1850 or
阿米什人的生活方式仿佛还停留在1850年或更早时期。
something. So they live in a they don't
某物。所以他们生活在一个他们不
use cars. They I think they do have
使用汽车。我认为他们确实有
phones but they do not have electricity.
他们有手机，但是没有电。
Basically they they voluntarily accept a
基本上，他们是自愿接受的
techn they're basically a lite community
技术方面，他们基本上是一个轻量级的社区。
and they uh have turned out to fare
而他们最终的结果却令人失望。
surprisingly well against many of the
出人意料地，对很多……
things that have upended modern one of
颠覆现代社会的事物
them right yeah co they did beautifully
对，他们做得非常出色。
quite happy people very low autism rates
相当快乐的人们，自闭症发病率很低。
they they have all sorts of advantages
他们拥有各种各样的优势
so anyway I'm not arguing that we should
总之，我并不是说我们应该……
live like the Amish I don't see that but
我不认为可以像阿米什人那样生活。
I do think the idea that they had an
我确实认为他们拥有……的想法
insight which was you need to step off
领悟到你需要停下来
that escalator because you're just going
因为你正要去坐那部自动扶梯。
to keep making yourselves sicker is
不断地让自己病情加重是
probably right now. Maybe this is a
可能就是现在。也许这是
one-time shift. We've stepped over the
一次性轮班。我们已经跨过了
event horizon. We are going to be living
事件视界。我们将要生活
in the AI world. And maybe if we're
在人工智能领域。也许如果我们
careful about it, we can figure out how
小心点，我们就能想办法了。
to turn that landscape of infinite
将那无限的风景变成
possibility that you're describing into
你所描述的这种可能性
a place that doesn't change. That you
一个不变的地方。那个你
always have the opportunity to decide
始终有机会做出决定
what needs to be done. But that none
需要做什么。但那并非
that the that living over that event
那件事的发生
horizon is not an everchanging process.
视野并非一成不变的过程。
It's just the next frontier. I do want
这只是下一个前沿领域。我确实想要
to also propose or ask the question when
同时提出或询问这个问题
we talk about our hyperchanging world.
我们谈论的是我们这个瞬息万变的世界。
Isn't it harder for older people to
老年人是不是更难……
learn because of the the way that the
学习的方式
brain works in terms of processing speed
大脑的运作方式体现在处理速度方面。
and memory flexibility?
内存灵活性如何？
So I was wondering if you're going to
所以我想知道你是否打算
get a situation where like my father h
遇到像我父亲那样的情况
because of his brain and the reduced
因为他的大脑和减少
memory flexibility and processing speed
内存灵活性和处理速度
that happens when you're older is going
年纪大了之后就会发生这种情况：
to struggle significantly more than my
比我困难得多
niece who can seem to learn I mean my
我侄女似乎能学会，我的意思是……
niece knows five languages and she's
侄女会说五种语言，而且她
seven or something crazy like that five
七个或者类似那样疯狂的五个
languages but I mean the brain is much
语言，但我的意思是，大脑远不止如此。
more plastic isn't it? So the it's and
是不是又多了些塑料？所以，它是和
that's goes back to our evolutionary
那要追溯到我们的进化史
psychology which you know much
你很了解心理学。
evolutionary history which you know much
你对进化史了解甚多。
more than I do about of we're meant to
我比我更了解我们注定要做什么
learn our lessons when we're young. use
年轻的时候就要吸取教训。使用
that information for a lifetime. But if
这些信息将终身受益。但是如果
that information is changing quickly,
信息变化很快。
well, that's I mean this is exactly what
嗯，我的意思是，这正是……
I'm pointing to. It is not normal for
我指的是。这不正常
your developmental environment to fail
你的开发环境失败
to prepare you for your adult
让你为成年做好准备
environment. The normal thing is as a
环境。正常情况是这样的
young person, you take on ever more of
年轻人，你承担了越来越多的责任
the responsibilities of the adult
成年人的责任
environment. And then at some point, you
环境。然后，在某个时刻，你
know, in a properly functioning culture,
要知道，在一个运转良好的文化中，
there's a right of passage. You go into
这是一种成人礼。你进入
the bush for 10 days, you come back
在丛林里待了十天，你回来了
with, you know, a large uh, you know,
你知道，一个很大的，呃，你知道，
game animal and now you're an adult and
猎物，现在你已经成年了。
you take that program that you've been
你参加了那个项目。
building and you activate it. And that
建造并激活它。而那
is normal. And, you know, you're a lot
这是正常的。你知道，你很……
happier person. You're a lot more
更快乐的人。你比他们强得多
fulfilled if your life has that kind of
如果你的生活拥有那种体验，你就会感到满足。
continuity to it. And you know, I'm not
保持其连续性。你知道，我不是
against the idea that we have enabled
反对我们已经促成的观点
ourselves to do things that can't be
我们自己去做那些不可能的事情
done if that's the the limit, but we
如果这就是极限，那就结束了，但是我们
have also harmed ourselves gravely. And
我们也对自己造成了严重的伤害。和
I would like to somehow pry apart our
我想尽办法拆散我们
ability to improve our well-being from
改善我们福祉的能力
our self-inflicted wounds that come from
我们自残造成的伤口源于
this
这
neverending pace of change. And I don't
变化的步伐永不停歇。我没有
know if it's possible, but I think it's
我不知道是否可行，但我认为可行。
a worthy goal. Something amusing. I
这是一个值得追求的目标。一件有趣的事。我
don't know if it's exactly a
不知道它是否完全是
counterpoint, but um during co
对位，但是嗯，在合作期间
especially and you know through the the
尤其是，你知道，通过
recent technological change uh some
最近的技术变革，嗯，一些
people have started living closer to the
人们开始居住在离……更近的地方。
more ancestral environment. Um so uh
更接近祖先的环境。嗯，所以……
people whose jobs are online, some of my
那些工作与网络相关的人，我的一些
friends like went and built communities
朋友们像其他人一样，建立了社区
like collectives where they you know
就像你知道的那些集体一样
live and they they create farms and they
他们生活在那里，他们开垦农场，他们
they eat and then they eat and they have
他们吃啊吃啊，他们有
like an email job. They do their email
就像一份电子邮件工作。他们发送邮件
jobs for five hours and and go out and
工作五小时，然后出去玩
they all have children and it's it's a
她们都有孩子，而且这是一个
fascinating life. And there was so much
精彩的人生。而且还有很多
rethinking in in Silicon Valley about
重新思考硅谷的
how we live. And there's a bunch of
我们的生活方式。而且还有很多
startups that are trying to create um
试图创造的初创公司
cities where they're like, okay, we know
有些城市的人会说：“好吧，我们知道了。”
that we've we're suffering because our
我们正在遭受痛苦，因为我们
cities are not really walkable. And
城市其实并不适合步行。和
there's so many reasons why we're
我们有很多原因……
suffering. First, we're not getting the
痛苦。首先，我们没有得到
movement. Second, there's a social
移动。其次，还有社交方面的问题。
aspect of walkable city where you're
步行友好型城市的一个方面，你在这里
able to interact with people. You'll
能够与人交流。你会
make uh friends by just happening to be
碰巧认识朋友
in the same place as others. let's
和其他人一样，在同一个地方。我们来吧
actually build uh walkable cities and if
实际上，要建造适宜步行的城市，而且如果
we want to you know uh transport faster
我们想让你知道，呃，运输速度要快。
we'll have these self-driving cars on
我们将拥有这些自动驾驶汽车
the perimeter of the city that are going
城市周边地区正在前往
around and I think there are ways in
周围，​​我认为有办法。
which technology can afford us to uh to
哪些技术能够让我们……
live uh in a way that
以一种方式生活
reverses I I guess in a more local way.
我想，这在某种程度上是逆转的。
I I like that vision, but I also am
我喜欢这种愿景，但我同时也是
aware that there's a different vision,
意识到存在不同的观点，
right? You see people in Palo Alto, for
正确的？你会看到帕洛阿尔托的人们，因为
example, actually exerting, you know,
例如，实际上付出努力，你知道，
very strong controls on how much their
对他们的消费额度有着非常严格的控制。
children are exposed to, uh, you know,
孩子们会接触到，呃，你知道的，
to phones. And I live in Palo Alto.
到手机。我住在帕洛阿尔托。
Yeah. So, so you see that. On the other
是的。所以，你看到了吧。另一方面
hand, what I am worried about is that
说实话，我担心的是……
the the elites of PaloAlto don't realize
帕洛阿尔托的精英们没有意识到这一点
that what they're doing is they're
他们正在做的是……
figuring out how to reduce the harm to
想办法减少对……的伤害
their own families as they're exporting
他们把自己的家人也带走了，因为他们正在出口
the harm to the world of these
这些对世界的危害
technologies that for everybody else are
对其他人来说都是技术
unregulated. And so the question is, can
不受监管。所以问题是，能否
we bring everybody along? If the AI
我们带所有人一起去吗？如果人工智能
revolution is going to alter our
革命将会改变我们
relationship to work and everything
与工作及其他一切的关系
else, can we bring everybody along so
否则，我们能把大家都带上吗？
that at the end of this process instead
而是在这个过程的最后阶段
of saying well you know it's a shame
说“唉，真是可惜”
that uh you know three billion people
你知道，那可是30亿人
were sacrificed to this transition but
为了这一转变而牺牲，
progress is progress we can really say
进步就是进步，这一点毋庸置疑。
well we figured it out and everybody now
我们已经想明白了，现在每个人都明白了。
is living in a style that is closer to
生活方式更接近于
their programming and closer to the
他们的节目制作和更接近
expectations of their physical bodies.
对他们身体的期望。
You know, if that were true, then I
你知道，如果那是真的，那么我
would I would be I would love to be
我愿意吗？我非常乐意成为……
wrong in my fears about what's coming.
我对即将发生的事情的担忧是错误的。
Um, but unfortunately, the market is not
嗯，但很遗憾，市场并非如此。
going to solve this problem without our
我们将在不采取任何措施的情况下解决这个问题
being deliberate about forcing it to.
故意强迫它这样做。
What's your biggest fear? Like when you
你最害怕的是什么？就像当你
say my fears about what's coming, what
说出我对未来事物的恐惧，什么
do you like what's what's the picture
你喜欢这张照片吗？
that comes in your mind? Oh, it's a
你脑海里浮现的是什么？哦，这是一个
whole different topic actually. Um my my
其实这是完全不同的话题。嗯，我的天
fear coming stemming from technology
恐惧源于科技
uh and AI is that this is a runaway
呃，人工智能就是失控了。
process and that that runaway process is
过程，以及那个失控的过程是
going to interface very badly with some
与某些设备交互会非常糟糕
latent human programs. that in effect
潜在的人类程序。实际上
the need for
需要
workers largely disappears and the
工人大多消失了，
people who are at the head of the
那些处于领导地位的人
processes that result in that
导致这种情况的过程
elimination for the need for workers
消除对工人的需求
start talking about useless eaters.
开始讨论那些无用的食客。
Maybe they come up with a new term this
或许他们会想出一个新术语
time. Thin the herd. Yep. Or they allow
时间。减少牛群数量。是的。或者他们允许
it to be thinned or something. Right.
需要把它稀释一下之类的。正确的。
I've heard you talk about the five key
我听你谈过五大关键要素。
concerns you have or the five key
您有任何疑问或五个关键点
threats you have before. Could you name
你之前发出的威胁。你能说出……
those five? So the first one is the one
那五个人？所以第一个就是那个
I worry least about. I don't worry zero
我最不担心的就是这个。我一点也不担心
about it, but I worry least about it,
虽然我对此有些担忧，但我最不担心的就是这件事。
which is the malevolent AI uh that the
就是那个邪恶的人工智能……
doomers are so focused on. The second
悲观主义者们如此关注。第二
one is the idea that you know an AI can
一种观点认为，你知道人工智能可以
be misaligned not because it has
错位并非因为它有
divergent interest but because it just
利益分歧，但正因为如此
misunderstands what you've asked it.
它误解了你的问题。
these autonomous agents. You know, the
这些自主代理。你知道，
famous example is you ask them to
一个著名的例子是你要求他们
produce as many paper clips as possible
尽可能多地生产回形针
and they start liquidating the universe
他们开始清算宇宙
to make paper clips and you know, it's a
用来制作回形针，你知道，这是一种
it's a sorcerer apprentice kind of
它有点像魔法学徒的故事。
issue. The third one I would say
问题。第三个我想说
is actually all of the remainder of them
实际上就是剩下的所有部分。
I would say are guaranteed and
我会说是有保障的，而且
um the third of them is the derangement
嗯，第三个是精神错乱。
of human intellect that we are already
我们已经拥有的人类智力
living in a world where it's very
生活在一个非常……的世界
difficult to know what the facts even
很难知道事实究竟如何。
mean. Right? We the facts are so
意思是。正确的？我们知道事实如此
filtered and we are so persuaded by
经过筛选，我们如此确信
algorithms that it's you know our
你知道，我们的算法就是我们的算法。
ability to be confident even in the
即使在以下情况下也能保持自信
basic facts even within our own
即使在我们自身内部，基本事实也是如此。
discipline sometimes is uh at an
纪律有时是呃……
all-time low and it's getting worse and
历史最低点，而且情况还在恶化。
that problem takes a giant leap forward
这个问题向前迈出了一大步。
at the point that you have the ability
当你具备这种能力的时候
to generate undetectable deep
生成无法检测的深度
fakes. Right? that's going to alter the
假货。正确的？这将改变……
world very radically when the fact that
世界格局发生了非常剧烈的变化，因为……
you're looking at videotape of somebody
你正在看某人的录像带。
robbing a bank doesn't mean that they
抢银行并不意味着他们
robbed a bank or that a bank was even
抢劫银行，或者说银行甚至
robbed. Um, so anyway, I call this we
被抢劫了。嗯，总之，我把这称为我们
deal with this a lot by the way. I I
顺便说一句，我经常要处理这类事情。我 我
think every single week, every single
每周都要思考，每个
week I send my I have a chat people that
这周我发了我的信息，我和一些人聊天。
just are now basically spending I'd say
我觉得他们现在基本上就是在花钱。
30% of their time dealing with deep
他们30%的时间都在处理深层问题。
fakes of me doing crypto scams, inviting
有人冒充我进行加密货币诈骗，并邀请我参与。
people to Telegram groups, and then
人们加入 Telegram 群组，然后
asking them for credit card details. We
要求他们提供信用卡信息。我们
had one on X. I think you probably saw
X 上有一个。我想你可能也看到了。
it, Dan, didn't you of me? But that
丹，你是不是也这样想过我？但是……
someone was running ad deep fake ads on
有人在投放深度伪造广告
X of me. And it wasn't just one ad. It
X 是我的。而且这还不止一个广告。它
was like there were it was like swatting
感觉就像在那里被拍打一样
flies. There was 10 of them. And I
苍蝇。他们一共10个人。我
messaged them to X and there was 10
我给他们发了消息给 X，一共 10 个。
more. Then the day after there was 10
更多的。第二天就有了10个。
more. Then it started happening on on
更多的。然后，这种事就开始发生了。
Meta. So it's a video of me basically
元。所以，这基本上就是一段关于我的视频。
asking you to come to a Telegram group
邀请你加入一个 Telegram 群组
where people are being scammed and
人们在那里被诈骗，
audience members of mine are being
我的观众正在
scammed. And when I send them to Meta,
被骗了。当我把它们发送给 Meta 时，
they thankfully remove them. But then
幸好他们把它们移走了。但是后来
there's five more. And I went on
还有五个。然后我继续说道
LinkedIn yesterday and my DMs are,
昨天我在LinkedIn上发了私信，内容如下：
"Steve, by the way, there's this new
“史蒂夫，顺便说一下，有个新的……”
scam." And I actually at this point I c
骗局。”而实际上，在这一点上，我……
I'd need someone fulltime just sending
我需要有人全职负责发送。
this over to Meta. I'm the I'm the same
交给 Meta 处理。我还是我。
but on a smaller scale. Every week it's
但规模较小。每周都是
did you really message me on Facebook
你真的在Facebook上给我发消息了吗？
asking me for my crypto wallet and blah
问我要我的加密货币钱包地址等等
blah blah. My my least favorite ones are
巴拉巴拉。我最不喜欢的有
when the the single mother messages me
当那位单身母亲给我发信息时
saying that she just paid £500 of her
她说她刚刚支付了500英镑。
money and how devastated she is and I
钱，还有她有多么伤心欲绝，以及我
feel this moral obligation to give her
感到有道义上的责任给予她
her money back um because she's fallen
把钱还给她，因为她摔倒了
for some kind of scam. That was me. It
似乎是某种骗局。那是我。它
was my voice. It was a video of me
那是我的声音。那是一段我的视频。
telling her something. Yeah. And I don't
告诉她一些事。是的。我没有
know I don't know how you deal with that
我知道我不知道你是如何处理这件事的。
but sorry do continue. Well, I mean
但很抱歉，请继续。嗯，我的意思是
that's actually on the list here. the
实际上，它就在这份清单上。这
massive disruption to the way things
对事物运作方式的巨大冲击
function both because people are going
之所以能发挥这种作用，是因为人们正在前往
to be unemployed in huge numbers and
大量人员失业，
because those who are not abiding by our
因为那些不遵守我们规定的人
social contract are going to find
社会契约将会发现
themselves empowered more than the
他们自己比其他人更有权力
people who do. So in this case, not only
这样做的人。所以，在这种情况下，不仅
is this poor woman, you know, now out
你知道，这位可怜的女人现在已经出狱了
500 bucks for whatever the scam was, but
不管骗局是什么，我都赔了500美元。
you've also been robbed whether or not
无论你是否被抢劫，你也都被抢劫了。
you pay her back for the thing that she
你要把她欠你的钱还给她。
thought she purchased. your credibility
她以为她买了。你的信誉
is being stolen by somebody and you have
东西被人偷了，而你……
no capacity to prevent it. This has
没有办法阻止它。这有
happened to me also and it is profoundly
我也经历过类似的事情，这给我留下了深刻的印象。
disturbing and it is only one of a dozen
令人不安，而这只是十几个案例中的一个。
different ways that AI enables those who
人工智能以不同的方式赋能于那些
are absolutely willing to shrink the pie
他们完全愿意缩小蛋糕。
from which we all derive in order to
我们都由此而来，以便
enlarge their slice. you know, there
扩大他们的份额。你知道，那里
there are innumerable ways that this can
这可以通过无数种方式实现。
happen and um I think people do not see
事情发生了，嗯，我觉得人们看不到。
it coming. They don't understand how
它来了。他们不明白为什么
many different ways they are going to be
它们将以多种不同的方式出现
robbed every bit as surely as if
被抢劫的程度丝毫不亚于……
somebody was printing money. Um and then
有人在印钞票。嗯，然后
the last one is that this just simply
最后一点就是，这简直太简单了。
accelerates demographic
人口结构加速变化
uh processes that do potentially result
呃，可能导致以下结果的过程
in the unleashing of technologies that
在技​​术释放方面
pre-existed AI. you know, this this can
已存在的AI。你知道，这个可以
easily result in an escalation
很容易导致事态升级
uh into wars that turn nuclear. Um, so
呃，演变成核战争。嗯，所以
anyway, I think that list could probably
总之，我认为那份清单可能
be augmented at this point now that
此时可以进行补充了
we've, you know, spent a little time in
你知道，我们已经花了不少时间在
the AI era. We can begin to put a little
人工智能时代。我们可以开始投入一些
more flesh on the bones both of what is
更详细地描述一下两者的本质
possible in this era and what we should
在这个时代，这既是可能的，也是我们应该做的。
fear. One of those you you mentioned uh
害怕。你提到的那些人之一，呃……
truth, you know, the problem of truth.
你知道，真相，也就是真相的问题。
Would you say just a thought experiment,
你觉得这只是一个思想实验吗？
someone today like an average person,
如今像普通人一样的人，
college educated say
受过大学教育的人说
person, are they more
人，他们是否更
propagandized or led astray
被宣传或误导
than someone in Soviet Russia?
比苏联俄罗斯人还不如？
Well, I don't know because I didn't live
嗯，我不知道，因为我没在那里生活过。
in Soviet Russia, but my understanding
在苏联时期，但我的理解是这样的
from people who did was that there was a
那些参与过的人表示，确实存在这种情况。
wide awareness that the propaganda
普遍意识到宣传
wasn't true. Doesn't mean they knew what
并非事实。但这并不意味着他们知道什么
to believe, but there was a cynicism,
虽然心存疑虑，但也有愤世嫉俗的一面。
which is one of my fears here, is that
而这正是我所担心的，那就是……
the, you know, you're really stuck
你知道，你真的被困住了。
choosing between two bad options in a
在两个糟糕的选项中做出选择
world where you can't tell what is true.
这是一个真假难辨的世界。
You can either be overly credulous and
你可以过于轻信，
be a sucker all the time, or you can
你可以一直当个傻瓜，或者你可以
become a cynic and you can be paralyzed
变得愤世嫉俗，你可能会寸步难行。
by the fact that you just don't believe
因为你根本不相信
anything. But neither of those is a
任何事物。但这两种都不是
recipe for do you think Google search
你认为谷歌搜索的食谱是什么？
first and maybe now chat GPT has helped
首先，也许现在聊天 GPT 也起到了作用。
people more or
更多的人或
less to find truth? I
寻找真相的动力更少？我
think it's not chat GPT exactly but all
我觉得它不完全是聊天 GPT，但都是
of the various AI engines that we're
我们正在使用的各种人工智能引擎中……
starting with Google have briefly
从谷歌开始，简要地
enhanced our capacity to know what's
增强了我们了解事物的能力
true because in fact they allow us to
没错，因为它们实际上允许我们
see through the algorithmic manipulation
看穿算法操纵
because the AI is not well policed. you
因为人工智能缺乏有效的监管。你
can get it to recognize patterns that
可以使其识别模式
people will swear are not true. Um, and
人们会信誓旦旦地说这不是真的。嗯，还有
so anyway, a lot of us have found it
总之，我们很多人都发现了这一点。
useful in just simply unhooking the
只需简单地解开连接即可。
gaslighting. Um, so that's been very
煤气灯效应。嗯，所以那段时间非常
positive. But I also remember the early
积极的。但我也记得早期
days of search and search used to be a
搜索的日子，以及曾经的搜索……
matter of there are some pages out
问题是，有些页面已经售罄了。
there. I don't know where they are.
那里。我不知道他们在哪里。
Here's a mechanized something that's
这是一个机械化的东西，它是
looked through this stuff and just point
我翻阅了这些东西，然后就说……
me at the direction of things that
按照我的指示，事情就是这样发生的。
contain these words. right before the
包含这些词语。就在之前
algorithmic manipulation started
算法操控开始
steering us into believing pure nonsense
诱导我们相信纯属无稽之谈
because somebody who controlled these
因为有人控制了这些
things decided it was useful for us to
种种迹象表明，这对我们来说是有用的
believe those things. So my guess is at
相信这些事。所以我猜是
the moment AI is enhancing our ability
人工智能正在增强我们的能力
to see more clearly but that really
为了看得更清楚，但那真的
depends on some kind of agreement to
取决于某种协议
protect that capacity that I'm not aware
保护我所不了解的那种能力
of us having are you implying there that
你这话的意思是说我们之间……
AI will protect us from AI i.e. the
人工智能将保护我们免受人工智能的侵害，即……
woman that got scammed in my audience,
我观众席上有一位被骗的女士，
the platforms would have a tool built in
这些平台将内置一个工具。
which would be able to identify shortly
很快就能识别出来
that that is not me and the ad is been
那不是我，广告已经失效了。
launched by someone in another country
由另一个国家的人发起
potentially and then also when she
有可能，而且当她
starts being asked for her credit card
开始有人向她索要信用卡信息
details in such a way on Telegram 10
详情请见 Telegram 10
minutes later the system will able to
几分钟后，系统将能够
understand there that this is probably a
明白这很可能是一个
scam at that touch touch point too and
那个接触点也是骗局，而且
it will also be the defense not just the
这也将是防御，而不仅仅是
offense.
罪行。
First thing uh question is Meta
首先，呃，问题是元认知。
incentivized to solve this problem? Yes.
是否有动力解决这个问题？是的。
Yes. And so Meta is probably actively
是的。因此，Meta 可能正在积极运作。
working on AIs and again it's going to
正在研究人工智能，而且它又将……
be a cat and mouse game like every abuse
就像所有虐待行为一样，这是一场猫捉老鼠的游戏。
that happens out there. So I I think
这种事确实会发生。所以我觉得
that the market will naturally respond
市场自然会做出反应
to things like that in the same way that
对类似的事情也采取同样的方式
you know we installed antiviruses as you
你知道我们安装了杀毒软件，因为你
know annoying as they are. I think we'll
我知道它们很烦人。我认为我们会
install uh AIS on our computers that
在我们的电脑上安装AIS
will allow us to at least help us kind
至少能让我们善待彼此。
of sort the the fake from from the
某种程度上，来自假货
truth. Well, but let's let's take the
真相。好吧，但我们还是来看看……
example you say. Is Meta incentivized to
举例子？ Meta是否有激励措施
solve this problem? Superficially, it
解决这个问题了吗？表面上看，它
seems that it should be, but how many
看起来应该是这样，但究竟有多少个呢？
times in recent history have we watched
在近代史上，我们目睹了……
a corporation cannibalize its own
一家公司会蚕食自己的员工。
business over what at best is the
商业至上主义
bizarre desires of its shareholders,
股东们的古怪愿望，
right? Why was X throwing off people
正确的？为什么X要误导人们
with large accounts or Facebook or
拥有大量账户或 Facebook 或
Google? It would seem that you would
谷歌？看来你会
expect based on the market choosing
预期基于市场选择
search engines or social media sites,
搜索引擎或社交媒体网站，
you would expect these companies to be
你可能会认为这些公司会是
absolutely mercenary and say, you know,
完全唯利是图，你知道，
if Alex Jones has a big audience, who
如果亚历克斯·琼斯拥有大量观众，那么谁会……
are we to say? That's what I would have
我们该怎么说呢？那就是我想要的。
expected. Instead, you had these
预期的。相反，你却拥有了这些
companies policing the morality of
公司监管道德
thought even though it reduced the size
虽然它缩小了尺寸
of the population using the platforms. I
使用这些平台的人群。我
have a hard time explaining why that
很难解释为什么会这样
happened, but I have every reason to
事情已经发生了，但我完全有理由
expect the same thing will happen with
预计同样的事情也会发生在……
AI. What are you excited about with AI?
人工智能。你对人工智能的哪些方面感到兴奋？
What's your your optimistic take?
你乐观的看法是什么？
Because at the start of this
因为在这一切的开始
conversation, you said that there's
对话中，你说过有
infinite ways that it could improve our
它可以通过无数种方式来改善我们
lives and there's 10 times more ways
生命，而且方式要多十倍。
that it could hurt our lives. But let's
这可能会危及我们的生命。但我们……
investigate some of those ways that it
探究其中的一些方法
could drastically improve our lives.
可以极大地改善我们的生活。
There's a couple of different ways. One,
有好几种方法。一，
we have, as we mentioned before, a der
正如我们之前提到的，我们有一个 der
of competent teachers and professors.
拥有优秀的教师和教授。
And that is a problem that will take
而这个问题需要时间才能解决。
three generations at least to solve if
至少需要三代人的时间才能解决
what we're going to do is start tomorrow
我们明天就开始。
and start educating people in the right
并开始对人们进行正确的教育
way that would make them competent to
这种方式能让他们胜任
stand at the front of a room and
站在房间前面，
educate. But if we can augment that
教育。但如果我们能加强这一点的话
process, if we can leverage a tool like
流程，如果我们能够利用类似这样的工具
AI so that you know a small number of
人工智能让你了解少量信息
competent teachers can maybe reach a
优秀的教师或许能够达到
larger number of pupils, that's
学生人数更多，那就是
plausible I think. Second thing is we
我觉得有可能。第二件事是我们
have a tremendous number of problems
存在大量问题。
that are obstacles to us living well on
这些都是我们过上美好生活的障碍。
this planet that AI might be able to
这个星球，人工智能或许能够……
manage that human intellect alone
仅凭人类的智力就能掌控一切。
cannot. Right? Just in the same way that
不能。正确的？就像这样
you know compute power can calculate
你知道计算能力可以计算
things at a rate that human beings can't
以人类无法承受的速度发展
keep up and there are certain things you
跟上步伐，还有一些事情你需要做。
want calculated very well. There are
想要计算得非常精确。有
also some reasoning problems. You could
还有一些推理问题。你可以
imagine that instead of having um static
想象一下，如果不是有静电干扰，而是有静电干扰。
laws that govern behavior poorly because
规范行为的法律之所以无效，是因为
they get gamed that you could have a
他们被骗了，以为你可以……
dynamic interaction. You could specify a
动态交互。您可以指定一个
an objective of something like a law and
法律之类的目标
then you could monitor whether or not a
这样你就可以监控是否
particular intervention successfully
特定干预措施的成功
moved you in the direction that you were
把你推向了你原本的方向
hoping to go or did something
希望去或做了某事
paradoxical which happens all the time
这种情况屡见不鲜，但却自相矛盾。
and you could have you could basically
而且你基本上可以拥有
have governance that is targeted to
拥有针对性的治理
navigation and prototyping rather than
导航和原型设计，而不是
to specifying a blueprint for how we are
为我们如何……制定蓝图
to live. So we wouldn't need
活着。所以我们就不需要
politicians. Um, at the moment we're
政客们。嗯，目前我们
stuck with, you know, constitutional
被宪法问题困扰着，你知道的
protections that are as good as has been
保护措施与以往一样有效
constructed and still inadequate to
已建成但仍不足以
modern realities.
现代现实。
Dan, what are you excited about with AI
丹，你对人工智能最感兴趣的是什么？
from an individual level, but also from
从个人层面来说，也从
a societal level? Yeah. Well, the big
社会层面？是的。嗯，大的
ones are healthcare and education. I
其中之一是医疗保健和教育。我
mean, it's ridiculous that you uh are
我的意思是，你这简直太荒谬了。
sitting there in pain, having had an
痛苦地坐在那里，刚刚经历了一场
MRI, and there just hasn't been someone
核磁共振成像，但一直没有人做过。
to look at that MRI yet. and and tell
还没看过那张核磁共振图像。并告诉
you what to do. Um and that could easily
你该怎么做。嗯，这很容易
be solved there's all sorts of
可以解决，有各种各样的
healthcare issues where um and also not
医疗保健问题，嗯，还有不是
only that throughout the entire world
只是在整个世界范围内
there are places that just don't have
有些地方就是没有
general practitioners and they don't
全科医生，他们不这样做。
have you know medical advisers and and
你认识医疗顾问吗？
you know the breakthroughs in global
你知道全球范围内的突破
healthcare will be phenomenal and the
医疗保健将非常出色，而且
breakthroughs in global education could
全球教育领域的突破可能
be transformational um on the planet. I
对地球而言，这将是一场变革。我
I'm excited at an individual level that
我个人感到非常兴奋。
I think the industrial age created a
我认为工业时代创造了
bunch of jobs that are very dehumanizing
很多工作都非常不人道
and we've just kind of gotten used to
我们已经渐渐习惯了。
them and put up with them. The idea that
忍受他们。这种想法
work should be repetitive and you know
工作应该是重复性的，你知道的
you just repeat the same loop over and
你只需重复同样的循环即可。
over and over over again and over a
一遍又一遍，一遍又一遍
10-year period of time you might get you
10 年的时间里，你可能会得到你
know graduated up one gear and all that
知道已经升级到更高一级等等
kind of stuff. I don't think that's very
诸如此类的事情。我觉得那不是很……
human. Um the idea that you could be
人类。嗯，你有可能……的想法
simultaneously writing a book, launching
同时撰写书籍，并推出
a business, running a team, launching a
一家企业，管理一个团队，推出一项业务
festival, having an event. Um that that
节日，举办活动。嗯，就是那个
that you could actually be doing this
你实际上可以这样做
kind of like mini kingdom work where
有点像小型王国的工作，
you've got this little, you know, uh
你还有这个小小的，你知道，呃
ecosystem around you of fun things that
你周围充满乐趣的生态系统
you're involved in that is actually made
你参与的那部分实际上是制作出来的。
possible for a vast majority of people
对绝大多数人来说都是可能的
if they embrace these kind of tools. um
如果他们接受这类工具。嗯
you can live an incredibly fulfilling
你可以过上无比充实的生活。
and amazing and impactful existence or I
以及令人惊叹且影响深远的存在，或者我
know that I do as a result of having
我知道，我之所以知道，是因为我曾经拥有过。
these tools in my life. Like I'm I'm
这些工具在我生活中扮演着重要的角色。就像我一样
doing things that I could have only
做我只能……的事情
dreamed about uh as a kid. And what
小时候梦到过。还有什么
would you say to entrepreneurs? I know
你会对创业者们说些什么？我知道
you you work with thousands of
你与成千上万的人一起工作
entrepreneurs. What are you telling them
企业家。你跟他们说了什么？
in terms of their current businesses or
就他们目前的业务而言
business opportunities that you're
你的商业机会
foreseeing? So I think that small teams
预见？所以我认为小团队
have infinite leverage now and that when
现在拥有无限的杠杆，将来也是如此
you have a team of say five to 10 people
你的团队大概有五到十个人。
who share an incredible passion for a
他们对……有着无比的热情
meaningful problem in the world and they
这是世界上一个有意义的问题，他们
want to see that meaningful problem
想看到那个有意义的问题
solved and they come together in the
问题解决了，它们汇聚到了一起。
spirit of entrepreneurship to solve that
运用企业家精神解决这个问题
problem. That little 5 to 10 person team
问题。那支5到10人的小团队
armed with the technology that we now
凭借我们现在所拥有的技术
have available, you can have a a big
如果条件允许，你可以拥有一个大
impact. You can make a lot of money. You
影响。你可以赚很多钱。你
can have a lot of fun. you can solve
可以玩得很开心。你可以解决
meaningful problems in the world. You
世界面临的有意义的问题。你
can scale solutions. You can probably do
可扩展的解决方案。你大概可以做到
more in a three-year window than most
在三年时间内，这种情况比大多数情况都要普遍。
people did in a 30-year career. Uh and
在长达 30 年的职业生涯中，有人做到了这一点。呃，还有
then that little band of 5 to 10 people
然后就是那支由5到10人组成的小乐队
could either go together onto a new
可以一起进入一个新的阶段。
meaningful problem or they could disband
有意义的问题，或者他们可能会解散
and you know work on other meaningful
而且你还可以从事其他有意义的工作。
problems with different teams. In such a
不同团队之间存在问题。在这种情况下
world where you have this sort of
在这个世界里，你会遇到这样的情况
infinite leverage but everyone else has
无限杠杆，但其他人却只有
access to the same infinite leverage.
获取同样的无限杠杆。
What becomes the USP? Going back to this
什么是独特卖点？回到这一点
idea of the moat, like what is the thing
护城河的概念，就像它到底是什么一样。
of value when we've all got access to
当我们都能获得价值时，它就具有价值
$20 infinite leverage? Well, first of
20美元无限杠杆？嗯，首先是
all, the first thing you need to do you
首先，你需要做的第一件事是……
need to understand is that this moment
需要明白的是，此刻
of time is the least competitive uh
时间是最不具竞争力的因素。
moment. Like if you understand how to
片刻。比如，如果你明白该怎么做的话
use these tools, you can start making
使用这些工具，你就可以开始制作了。
money tomorrow. like we, you know, I see
明天就能拿到钱了。就像我们，你知道，我看到
countless examples of people making
人们创造了无数这样的例子。
thousands of dollars with these hustles
通过这些套路赚到数千美元
that I that I talked about or building
我谈到的或建造
businesses that generates millions of
创造数百万美元收入的企业
dollars in the first couple of months of
头几个月的美元
existence. So, I would say start moving
存在。所以，我建议你开始行动。
now. Start building things. So, it's an
现在。开始动手制作东西。所以，这是一个
unprecedented time of of of wealth
前所未有的财富时代
creation. Clearly at some point as the
创建。显然在某个时候，
market gets more efficient as people
随着人们的增多，市场效率会越来越高，市场也会变得更加高效。
more and more people understand how to
越来越多的人明白了如何
use these tools um there's less
使用这些工具，嗯，数量较少。
potential for uh you know creating these
有可能创造这些
massive businesses quickly and we've
迅速发展壮大企业，我们已经
seen this like the dawn of the internet
就像互联网的黎明时期一样。
or dawn of the web you know it was a lot
或者说，互联网的黎明时期，你知道，那段时间很漫长。
easier to create Facebook than it is now
创建Facebook比现在容易多了
then we had mobile and for three four
然后我们有了手机，而且用了三四年。
five years it was very easy to create
五年内创建这个平台非常容易。
massive businesses and then it became
庞大的企业，然后它变成了
harder. Being just at the edge of what's
更难。恰好处于边缘地带
possible is going to be very very
可能性将非常非常
important over the next couple years.
在未来几年内至关重要。
And that's that gets me really excited
这让我非常兴奋。
because the entrepreneurs who are paying
因为那些付费的企业家
attention are going to are going to be
注意力将会集中在……
having the most amount of fun, but
玩得最开心，但是
they're also going to be able to make a
他们也将能够制造一个
lot of money. How many applications have
很多钱。有多少份申请
been built on Replet to date? So, you
目前为止，基于 Replet 构建的项目有哪些？所以，你
know, I can talk about the millions of
我知道，我可以谈谈数百万美元
things that have been built since the
自那时以来建造的东西
since we started the company, but just
自从我们创办公司以来，但只是
since uh September when we launched
自九月份我们推出以来
Replent, there's been about 3 million
据称，大约有300万个
applications built purely in natural
完全用自然语言构建的应用程序
language with no uh with no coding at
语言无需呃，无需编码
all, purely natural language. uh of
全部都是纯自然语言。呃
those I think uh 300 400,000 of them
我想，大概有30万到40万吧。
were deployed in a real um in the site
已在现场实际部署
was deployed and it is having people are
已部署完毕，并且有人正在执行任务。
using it some kind of business some kind
用它来做某种生意
of internal tool. I built one last night
内部工具。我昨晚建了一个
by the way an internal tool or I uh
顺便说一下，一个内部工具或者我呃
built an application to track um how my
开发了一个应用程序来跟踪我的……
kids earn pocket money. Amazing. So, I
孩子们赚零花钱。惊人的。所以，我
just told it that I wanted to track the
我只是告诉它我想追踪
tasks that are happening around the
周围正在发生的任务
house and put an assign a value to them
房子，并给它们赋予价值
and I want to be able to at the end of
我希望在最后能够做到这一点
the week push a button and get a summary
本周只需按一下按钮即可获得摘要
of how much to pay each child um for
关于应该给每个孩子多少钱
their pocket money. we are so screwed.
他们的零花钱。我们完蛋了。
And within 15 minutes, it had created
15分钟之内，它就创造了
this application and it was amazing.
这个应用程序太棒了。
Like you could toggle between like
就像你可以切换“喜欢”之类的选项
here's the place where you have the kids
这里是孩子们待的地方
and here's the weekly reports and here's
以下是每周报告，以下是……
the um how much per task and you can
嗯，每项任务多少钱？你可以
tick off the tasks or remove tasks or
勾选任务或删除任务
add tasks. So then I now have this
添加任务。所以我现在有了这个
application for which took 15 minutes of
申请过程耗时15分钟。
just talking about what I wanted and now
只是说说我想要什么，现在
I have an application to run the pocket
我有一个运行 Pocket 的应用程序。
money uh situation in the in the house.
家里的钱的情况。
And this by the way it's something
顺便说一句，这是……
having run an IT agency years ago.
多年前曾经营过一家IT公司。
That's something that we would have
那是我们会拥有的。
charged five to10,000 pounds to create
收费五千至一万英镑用于制作
or5 to 10,000 US dollars to to create
或5000至10000美元用于创建
and how much time probably talking
以及可能要花多少时间谈论
something that would have been a three
本来应该是三
four week project and we're at the start
为期四周的项目，我们才刚刚开始。
of the S-curve now that you're
现在你已经了解了S曲线
describing and it's already if you if
描述，而且已经是了，如果你……
it's a $20 replet's roughly $20 a month
每次补货大约需要 20 美元，每月大约 20 美元。
25 for the for the base case you did one
25，对于基本情况，你做了一个
day of usage let's say it's a dollar it
假设使用当天花费一美元，
cost you and it cost you minutes and a
这不仅花费了你金钱，还浪费了你几分钟的时间。
dollar now and we're at the start of the
美元现在正处于……的开端
scurve and and you talk to it like
坏血病，你跟它说话就像
you're chatting to a developer. So one
您正在与一名开发人员聊天。所以一个
of the things that slows down the
减缓速度的因素之一
development process is you have to send
开发过程是您需要发送
the information to a developer and they
将信息提供给开发人员，他们
need to understand it and then they need
需要理解它，然后他们需要
to create something and then come back
创造一些东西，然后再回来
to you. This just happens in front of
给你。这事就发生在……面前
your eyes uh while you're watching it
你的眼睛，呃，当你观看的时候
and it's actually showing you what's
它实际上是在向你展示什么
being built and it's it's really wild.
正在建设中，真是太疯狂了。
This one change has transformed how my
这一个改变彻底改变了我的
team and I move, train and think about
我和我的团队一起行动、训练和思考
our bodies. When Dr. Daniel Lieberman
我们的身体。丹尼尔·利伯曼博士
came on the DEO. He explained how modern
加入了 DEO。他解释了现代社会是如何运作的。
shoes with their cushioning and support
鞋子具有缓冲和支撑作用
are making our feet weaker and less
正在使我们的双脚变得虚弱和乏力
capable of doing what nature intended
能够完成自然赋予它的意义
them to do. We've lost the natural
让他们去做。我们失去了自然
strength and mobility in our feet and
脚部的力量和灵活性
this is leading to issues like back pain
这会导致背痛等问题。
and knee pain. I'd already purchased a
以及膝盖疼痛。我已经买了一个
pair of Viva barefoot shoes. So, I
一双Viva赤足鞋。所以，我
showed them to Daniel Lieberman and he
把它们拿给丹尼尔·利伯曼看，他
told me that they were exactly the type
他们告诉我，他们正是那种人。
of shoe that would help me restore
一双能帮助我恢复原状的鞋子
natural foot movement and rebuild my
自然的足部运动和重建我的
strength. But I think it was
力量。但我认为是
plantficitis that I had where suddenly
我患上的植物性炎症突然
my feet started hurting all the time.
我的脚开始一直疼。
And after that I decided to start
之后我决定开始
strengthening my own foot by using the
通过使用以下方法增强我的脚部力量：
Vivo barefoot. And research from
Vivo 赤脚。以及来自的研究
Liverpool University has backed this up.
利物浦大学也证实了这一点。
They've shown that wearing Vivo barefoot
他们已经证明，赤脚穿着 Vivo 鞋
shoes for 6 months can increase foot
穿鞋6个月可能会增加脚部
strength by up to
强度提升至
60%. Visit vivo
60%。访问 vivo
barefoot.com/doac and use code diary 20
barefoot.com/doac 并使用代码 diary 20
from my sponsor for 20% off. A strong
通过我的赞助商可享受 20% 的折扣。强大的
body starts with strong feet. This has
强健的双脚是身体健康的基础。这有
never been done before. A newsletter
前所未有。简讯
that is ran by 100 of the world's top
由全球100位顶尖人士运营
CEOs. All the time people say to me,
首席执行官们。人们总是对我说：
they say, "Can you mentor me? Can you
他们说：“你能指导我吗？你能……”
get this person to mentor me? How do I
让这个人来指导我？我该怎么做？
find a mentor?" So, here is what we're
找个导师？”所以，这就是我们要做的是……
going to do. You're going to send me a
准备去做。你要给我发一个
question. And the most popular question
问题。最热门的问题
you send me, I'm going to text it to 100
你发给我，我会转发到100。
CEOs, some of which are the top CEOs in
首席执行官们，其中一些是顶尖的首席执行官们
the world running a hundred billion
世界运转着一千亿
dollar companies. And then I'm going to
美元公司。然后我打算
reply to you via email with how they
他们会通过电子邮件回复您，告知他们的情况。
answered that question. You might say,
回答了这个问题。你可能会说，
"How do you hold on to a relationship
如何维系一段关系
when you're building a startup? What is
当你创建一家初创公司时？什么是
the most important thing if I've got an
如果我有一个……，最重要的事情是……
idea and don't know where to start?" We
有想法但不知道从何入手？
email it to the CEOs. They email back.
通过电子邮件发送给各位CEO。他们会回复邮件。
We take the five, six top best answers.
我们选取前五、六个最佳答案。
We email it to you. I was nervous
我们会通过电子邮件发送给您。我当时很紧张
because I thought the marketing might
因为我认为市场营销可能会
not match the reality. But then I I saw
与实际情况不符。但后来我看到
what the founders were replying with and
创始人们是如何回应的？
their willingness to reply and I thought
他们愿意回复，我想
actually this is really good and all
实际上这真的很好。
you've got to do is sign up completely
你必须做的就是完全注册。
free. I don't think we've spent a lot of
自由的。我认为我们并没有花费很多钱
time talking about autonomous weapons.
是时候谈谈自主武器了。
This is the thing that really worries
这才是真正令人担忧的事情。
me. And the thing that worries people
我。而令人们担忧的是……
about AI is this idea is that it is uh
关于人工智能，这个想法是……
this you know emergent system and
这就是你所知的涌现系统
there's no one thing behind it and it
背后并非只有一件事，而且
can be it can act in a way that's uh
它可以以某种方式发挥作用，呃……
unpredictable and not really guided by
不可预测且并非真正受……指导
humans. also think it's true of
人类。我也认为这是真的
corporations of governments and so I
政府机构等等
think individual people uh can often
认为个人通常可以
have the best intentions but the
出发点是好的，但是
collective can land on doing things in a
集体可以决定在某个方面做事
way that's harmful or morally irrepant
有害的或不道德的方式
and I think um we talked about China
我想我们当时也谈到了中国。
versus the US and that creates a certain
与美国相比，这就造成了某种局面。
race dynamics where um they're both
种族动态，嗯，他们俩
incentivized to cut corners and
有动机偷工减料和
potentially do do harmful things and in
可能会做有害的事情，并且在
the world of geopolitics
地缘政治的世界
um and wars, you know, what really
嗯，还有战争，你知道，到底是什么
scares me is is autonomous weapons. And
最让我感到害怕的是自主武器。和
why does it scare you? Because
它为什么让你感到害怕？因为
uh you know you can imagine
呃，你知道你可以想象
uh autonomous drones being trained on
呃，正在接受训练的自主无人机
someone's face and you can send a a
某人的脸，你可以发送一张
swarm of of drones and they can be this
成群的无人机，它们可以这样
um sort of autonomous killing
嗯，某种自主杀戮
assassination machine and it can sort of
暗杀机器，而且它某种程度上可以
uh function as a you know country verse
呃，就像一首乡村诗歌一样。
country technology in in the world of
国家科技在世界范围内
for which is still crazy but it can also
这仍然很疯狂，但它也可能
become a tool for governments to
成为政府的工具
subjugate the citizens and and people
征服公民和人民
think we're we're safe in the west but I
我觉得我们在西部很安全，但是……
think the experience with co showed that
我认为与公司合作的经验表明
even the systems in the west can very
即使是西方国家的制度也可能非常复杂。
quickly become draconian. Yeah.
很快变得严苛。是的。
Apparently, I've heard in um Iran that
我好像在伊朗听说……
uh they have facial recognition cameras
呃，他们有面部识别摄像头。
that detect where the women are wearing
可以检测女性穿着的服装位置。
hijabs in their own cars and it
她们在自己的车里戴着头巾，而且
automatically detains the car. If you're
自动扣押车辆。如果你是
driving and you're not wearing a hijab
开车时你没戴头巾
and if you're certainly if you're
如果你确定的话，如果你确定的话
walking down the street, it just picks
走在街上，它就这么挑着。
that up and immediately you're you're in
那样一来，你立刻就进入状态了。
trouble. uh you can like it acts as a
麻烦。呃，你可以把它当作……
police officer and a judge and you know
一名警官和一名法官，你知道的
a law m lawmaker it's the judge jury and
法律、立法者、法官、陪审团和
executioner essentially and it's just
本质上就是刽子手，仅此而已。
happens instantaneously what happened in
瞬间发生发生了什么
Canada with the truckers uh uh sort of
加拿大和卡车司机们，嗯嗯，有点像
protest where they froze their bank
他们在抗议活动中冻结了银行账户。
account by virtue of just being there
仅仅因为身处那里就拥有了某种身份。
just by being in that location and just
仅仅身处那个位置，就
to confirm that Iran has implemented a
确认伊朗已实施
comprehensive surveillance system to
综合监控系统
enforce its mandatory hijab laws
强制执行其头巾法
utilizing various ious technologies, one
利用各种技术，一种
of which is cameras and facial
其中就包括摄像头和面部识别系统
recognition. So they've put cameras in
认出。所以他们安装了摄像头。
public spaces to identify women who are
在公共场所识别女性
not adearing to the hijab dress code.
不喜欢戴头巾的着装规定。
Yeah. And just on that, London has just
是的。仅就这一点而言，伦敦刚刚
put those face cam facial recognition
把那些面部识别摄像头放上去
systems into London and also all
通往伦敦的系统以及所有
throughout Wales. um and they're being
遍布威尔士。嗯，他们正在
rolled out at speed
高速滚动
and like all you would need is a change
而你所需要的仅仅是改变。
of government that wanted to implement
想要实施的政府
something similar and all the base layer
类似的东西，以及所有基础层
technologies already in there. It gets a
技术已在其中应用。它获得了
little bit worse in Iran because they
伊朗的情况稍微糟糕一些，因为他们
have this new app called the Nazar app
有一款名为 Nazar 的新应用
where the government has introduced the
政府已引入
Nazar mobile application which allows
Nazar 移动应用程序允许
you as a citizen to report another
作为公民，您有权举报他人。
citizen who is not wearing their hijab
未佩戴头巾的公民
and it it logs their location, their
它会记录他们的位置和他们的
time um when they weren't wearing it and
嗯，就是他们没戴的时候。
the vehicle license plate with the
带有该车牌的车辆
crowdsource data. It can then go after
众包数据。然后它就可以继续追击
that individual. I would also just point
那个人。我也会指出这一点。
out that I think we're not being
我认为我们没有被……
imaginative enough. I agree with you. I
足够有想象力。我同意你的看法。我
have the same concern about these
对此也有同样的担忧。
autonomous weapons, but I also think
自主武器，但我认为
this doesn't have to occur in the
这不一定会在……发生
context of war or even governmental
战争或政府的背景
oppression that it is perfectly
压迫，这完全是
conceivable that effectively this allows
可以想象，这实际上允许
this drops the price of a an
这会降低一个的价格。
undetectable or an unprosecutable crime.
无法侦查或无法起诉的犯罪行为。
And maybe economic moes return in the
或许经济模式会回归。
form of people taking out their
人们拿出他们的
competitors or anybody who attempts to
竞争对手或任何试图
compete with them using an autonomous
利用自主系统与他们竞争
drone that can't be traced back to them.
无法追溯到他们的无人机。
You know, that follows facial
你知道，这是面部护理之后的事。
recognition. And you know, you don't
认出。你知道，你并不
have to kill very many people for others
为了他人，不得不杀害很多人。
to get the message that uh this is a a
传达的信息是，呃，这是一个a
zone that uh you shouldn't mess around
那个区域，呃，你不应该胡闹
in. So, I could imagine, you know,
所以，我可以想象，你知道，
effectively a new high-tech organized
实际上，这是一个全新的高科技组织
crime that uh protects rackets and makes
保护不法分子并制造犯罪
tons of money and subjugates people who
拥有大量金钱并奴役人民
haven't done anything wrong. I had
我没做错任何事。我曾
Mustafa Sullivan on the podcast in 2023
穆斯塔法·沙利文在2023年的播客节目中
when this all of this stuff started
这一切是从什么时候开始的
kicking off and he is the CEO of
启动，他是首席执行官
Microsoft AI. You're familiar with
微软人工智能。你熟悉
Mustafa? Of course. Yeah. Um and he one
穆斯塔法？当然。是的。嗯，他一个
of the things he said to me at the time
他当时对我说的话
was one of my fears is a tiny group of
我担心的其中一点是，这是一个很小的群体。
people who wish to cause harm are going
那些意图作恶的人正在……
to have access to tools that can
能够使用以下工具
instantly destabilize our world. That's
瞬间动摇我们的世界。那是
the challenge. How to stop something
挑战。如何阻止某事发生
that can cause harm or potentially kill.
可能造成伤害甚至致人死亡。
That's where we need containment. And it
这就是我们需要遏制的地方。而且它
sounds a little bit like what you're
听起来有点像你说的
saying amad that we will now have these
愤怒地说，我们现在将拥有这些
these tools. you were talking in the
这些工具。你当时正在说话
context of the military, but as Brett
就军事背景而言，但正如布雷特所说
said there, even smaller groups of
在那里，甚至更小的群体也表示
people that might have been, I don't
那些可能成为的人，我不认识。
know, cartels or gangs can do similar
要知道，贩毒集团或帮派也能做类似的事情。
harm. And at the moment, in terms of
伤害。而就目前而言，
autonomous weapons, both the US and
美国和美国的自主武器
China are investing heavily in AI
中国正在人工智能领域投入巨资。
powered weapons, autonomous drones, and
动力武器、自主无人机和
cyber warfare because they're scared of
网络战，因为他们害怕
the other one getting it first. And we
另一个人先拿到了。我们
we talked about how much of our lives
我们谈到了我们生活中有多少时间是怎样的
run on the internet, but cyber weapons
在互联网上运行，但网络武器
and cyber AI agents that could be
以及可能存在的网络人工智能代理
deployed to take down China's X, Y, or
部署以击垮中国的X、Y或
Zed or vice versa are real concern.
Zed 或反之亦然，这才是真正令人担忧的问题。
Yeah. Yeah. I I think all of that is is
是的。是的。我认为所有这些都是
um is a real concern. You know, unlike
嗯，这确实是个令人担忧的问题。你知道，不像
Mustafa, I I don't think containment is
穆斯塔法，我不认为遏制是
is possible. Part of the reason why this
有可能。部分原因在于此
game theoretic system uh of competition
博弈论系统竞争
between the US, China, corporations,
美国、中国、企业之间，
individuals makes it so that this this
个人使得这一点
technology is already, you know, is
科技已经，你知道，是
already out and really hard to put it
已经发布了，而且很难发布。
back in the in the bag. I did ask him
放回袋子里。我问过他。
this question and I remember the answer
这个问题，我还记得答案。
because it was such a stark moment for
因为那是一个如此鲜明的时刻
me. I said to Mustafa, "Do you think
我。我对穆斯塔法说：“你觉得
it's possible to contain it?" And he
“有可能控制住它吗？”他
replied, "We must." So I asked him
回答说：“我们必须这样做。”所以我问了他
again. I said, "Do you think it's
再次。我说：“你觉得是吗？”
possible to contain it?" and he replied
“有可能控制住吗？”他回答道。
we must and I asked him again I said do
我们必须这样做，我又问了他一遍，我说去做。
you think it's possible we must so the
你认为有可能，我们就必须这样做。
problem with that uh uh chain of
那条呃呃链子有问题
thinking is that it might lead to an
认为这可能会导致
oppressive system
压迫性的制度
uh there is uh one of the say doomers or
呃，其中一位是末日论者，或者说……
philosophers of of AI which I I respect
我尊重的那些人工智能哲学家们
his work his name is Nick Bostonramm and
他的作品，他的名字是尼克·波士顿拉姆，
he he uh he's he was trying to think of
呵呵，呃，他……他正在努力想……
ways in which we can contain AI and the
我们可以采取哪些措施来遏制人工智能和
thing that he came up with is perhaps
他想出的办法或许是
more oppressive than something that the
比某些东西更令人压抑
AI would come up with is like total
人工智能会得出的结果就像是完全的
surveillance state. You need total
监控国家。你需要总计
surveillance on compute on people's
对人们的计算机进行监控
computers on people's ideas to not
计算机对人们想法的影响并非如此
invent AI or AGI. It's like taking the
发明人工智能或通用人工智能。这就像服用
guns or something or Right. Exactly. I
枪支或其他什么东西，对吧。确切地。我
mean there's always there's always this
意思是总会有这种情况。
problem of containing any sort of
包含任何类型的问题
technology is that you do need um
技术就是你需要……
oppression and draconian policies to do
压迫和严苛的政策是为了……
that. Are you scared of anything else or
那。你还害怕其他什么吗？
concerned about anything else as it
担心其他任何事情，因为它
relates to AI outside of autonomous
涉及自主性之外的人工智能
weapons? You know, we talked at the
武器？你知道，我们当时谈过
about
关于
the birthight crisis and I think a more
出生权危机，我认为还有更多
generalized problem there is creating
普遍存在的问题正在产生
virtualized environments
虚拟化环境
uh via VR where everyone is living in
呃，通过虚拟现实技术，每个人都生活在其中。
their own created universe and uh it's
他们自己创造的宇宙，呃，是
so enticing and even create simulates
如此诱人，甚至可以模拟
work and simulates struggle uh such that
工作并模拟挣扎，例如
you don't really need to leave this this
你其实没必要离开这里
world and so every one of us will be
世界，所以我们每个人都将是
solopcystistic, you know, similar to the
solopcystistic，你知道，类似于
Matrix. Ready Player One. Ready Player
矩阵。头号玩家。准备就绪玩家
One. We're all kind of uh plug even
一。我们都算是……呃，插电式连接
worse than Ready Player One. At least
比《头号玩家》还糟糕。至少
that's a massivelyworked
这是一个耗费大量精力的项目
environment. I'm talking about AI
环境。我指的是人工智能。
simulating everything uh for us and
为我们模拟一切
therefore you're literally in the
因此，你实际上就身处其中。
matrix. You know, maybe that this is I
矩阵。你知道，也许这就是我
was about I had that same thought. I've
我当时也有过同样的想法。我已经
enjoyed this great simulation. Yes. and
非常喜欢这个模拟游戏。是的。和
and and so I mean are you familiar with
所以我的意思是，你熟悉吗？
the Fermy's paradox? No, I'm not. So
费米悖论？不，我不是。所以
Fermy's paradox is um the question uh
费米悖论就是这个问题……
the you know professor his name is uh
你知道，那位教授，他的名字是……
Fermy he asked the question uh if the
费米问了这个问题，呃，如果
universe is is that vast then where are
宇宙如此浩瀚，那么它们在哪里呢？
the aliens? the fact that humans exist,
外星人？人类存在这一事实，
you can deduce that other civilizations
由此可以推断，其他文明
exist. And if they do exist, then why
存在。如果它们真的存在，那么为什么？
don't we see them? And then that spurred
我们难道没看到他们吗？然后，这促使
a bunch of Fermy solutions. So there's
一系列费米解。所以，就是这样。
uh I don't know, you can find hundreds
呃，我不知道，你可以找到成百上千个。
of solutions on the internet. One of
互联网上的解决方案。之一
them is the uh sort of house cat on a
它们就是那种家猫。
thought experiment where actually aliens
一个关于外星人的思想实验
exist, but they kind of put us in an
它们确实存在，但它们某种程度上把我们置于一种……
environment like the Amish in a certain
类似阿米什人那种环境
time and do not expose us to what's
时间，不要让我们接触到……
going on out there. So they we're pets.
外面正在发生什么。所以它们是宠物。
Maybe they're watching us and kind of
也许他们在监视我们，而且有点……
enjoying uh what we're doing, stopping
享受我们正在做的事情，停下来
us from hurting ourselves, stopping us
我们不会伤害自己，阻止我们
from hurting ourselves. There are so
避免伤害自己。有这么多
many things, but one of the things that
很多事情，但其中一件是……
I think is potentially a solution to the
我认为这或许是解决问题的办法
phrases paradox and one of the saddest
短语悖论和最悲伤的之一
outcomes is that civilizations progress
结果是文明的进步
until they invent technology that will
直到他们发明出能够实现的技术
lock us into infinite pleasure and
让我们沉浸在无限的快乐中
infinite simulation such that we we
无限模拟，以至于我们
don't have the motivation to go into
没有动力进入
space to seek out the explor
探索的空间
exploration, potentially other alien
探索，可能还有其他外星生物
civilizations. And perhaps that is a
文明。或许这就是……
determined outcome of humanity or like a
人类的既定结局，或者像……
highly likely outcome of any species
任何物种都极有可能出现的结果
like humanity. We like pleasure.
就像人类一样。我们喜欢享乐。
Pleasure and pain is the main
快乐和痛苦是主要
motivators. And so if you create an
激励因素。所以，如果你创建了一个
infinite pleasure machine, does that
无限享乐机器，就是这样
mean that we're just at home in our VR
这意味着我们在虚拟现实中感觉就像在家一样自在。
environment with everything taking care
环境舒适，一切都井然有序。
for us and literally like the matrix and
对我们来说，这简直就像《黑客帝国》一样。
the world the real world would suck in
现实世界会吞噬一切。
such a scenario? Yes. Be terrible. I
这种情况？是的。糟糕透顶。我
mean the other simpler explanation of
意思是另一种更简单的解释
the Fermy paradox is that you generate
费米悖论是指你产生
sufficient technology that you can end
足够的技术，你可以结束
your species and it's only a matter of
你的物种，这只是一个问题。
time from that point which you know we
从你知道的那个时间点开始的时间
can have that discussion about nuclear
可以就核能问题进行讨论。
weapons. We can have it about AI, but
武器。我们可以讨论人工智能，但是……
does some technology, if if we stay on
有些技术，如果我们继续下去的话……
that escalator, does some technology
那部自动扶梯运用了一些技术
that we generate ultimately whatever
我们最终会创造出什么呢？
allows you to get off the planet allows
允许你离开这个星球
you to blow up the planet? There you go.
你想把地球炸掉吗？好了。
I want to get everyone's closing
我想了解每个人的收尾情况。
thoughts and closing remarks. And
想法和总结发言。和
hopefully in your closing remarks, you
希望在您的总结发言中，您
can capture something actionable for the
可以获取一些可操作的信息。
individual that's listening to this now
现在正在听这段音频的这个人
on their commute to work or the single
在他们上下班的路上，或者单身人士
mother, the average person who maybe
母亲，一个普通人，也许
isn't as technologically advanced as
在技​​术上不如……先进
many of us at this table, but is trying
我们桌上的许多人，但他正在努力
to navigate through this to figure out
要弄清楚如何通过这种方式
how to live a good life over the next
如何在接下来的日子里过上美好的生活
10, 20, 30 years. Yeah. Take as long as
10年、20年、30年。是的。耗时尽可能长
you need. I think we live in the most uh
你需要。我认为我们生活在最……
interesting time in human history. So
人类历史上一个有趣的时期。所以
for the single mother that's listening,
致正在收听的单身母亲：
for someone who wouldn't be the
对于一个不会是的人来说
stereotype of a tech row, don't assume
不要以科技行业的刻板印象来看待这个问题。
that you can't do this stuff. It's never
你不能做这些事。从来没有
been more accessible today within your
今天，在您的生活中更容易获取信息。
work. You can be an entrepreneur. You
工作。你可以成为一名企业家。你
don't have to take massive risk to go
不必冒巨大的风险就能去
create a business um by you quit your
创建一个企业，嗯，通过你辞职
job and go create a business. There are
找份工作，然后去创业。有
countless examples. We uh we have a user
例子不胜枚举。我们呃，我们有一个用户
who's a product manager at a larger real
他是大型房地产公司的一名产品经理
estate business and he built something
他经营房地产生意，并建立了一些东西。
that created 10% lift in conversion
这带来了 10% 的转化率提升。
rates which generated millions and
产生了数百万美元的利率
millions of dollars of that business and
该业务的数百万美元和
that person became celebrity at that
那个人当时成了名人。
company and became someone who is
公司，并成为了一名……
lifting everyone else up and teaching
提升其他人的能力并进行教学
them how to use these tools and
告诉他们如何使用这些工具
obviously that that is like a really
显然，那就像一个真正的
great for for anyone's career and you're
这对任何人的职业生涯都很有帮助，而且你
going to get a promotion and your
即将升职，你的
example of building a piece of software
软件构建示例
for your family for your kids to to
为了你的家人，为了你的孩子
improve and and to learn more to be
改进并学习更多
better kids uh as an example of being
更好的孩子，例如……
entrepreneur in your family. So I really
你家有企业家吗？所以我真的
want people to break away from this
希望人们摆脱这种状态。
concept of entrepreneurship being this
创业精神的概念是这样的
is your podcast a diary of a CEO. You
你的播客是CEO的日记吗？你
started this podcast by talking to CEOs
这个播客最初是通过与首席执行官们对话而开始的。
I assume right and over time uh it
我猜对了，随着时间的推移，嗯……
changed to everyone can be a CEO
改为人人都可以成为首席执行官
everyone is some kind of CEO in their
每个人都是自己人生中的某种CEO。
life and so uh I think that we
生活，所以，嗯，我认为我们
have unprecedented access to tools for
拥有前所未有的工具使用权限
that vision to actually come to reality.
让这一愿景成为现实。
Well, it is obviously a moment of a kind
显然，这是一个特殊的时刻。
of human phase transition. Something
人类相变。某物
that I believe will be the equal of a
我相信这将与……相当
discovery of farming or writing or
农业或文字的发现
electricity. And the darkness that I
电。以及我所感受到的黑暗
think is valid in looking at all of the
认为在审视所有方面都是有效的
possible outcomes of this scenario is
此情景可能出现的结果是：
actually potentially part of a different
实际上可能是另一个部分的一部分
story as well. In evolutionary biology,
故事也很精彩。在进化生物学中，
we talk about an adaptive landscape in
我们谈论的是一种适应性景观
which a niche is represented as a peak
其中一个生态位被表示为一个峰
and a higher niche, a better niche is
更高的细分市场，更好的细分市场是
represented as a higher peak. But to get
表现为更高的山峰。但要得到
from the lower niche to the higher
从较低的生态位到较高的生态位
niche, you have to cross through what we
细分市场，你必须跨越我们所处的领域
call an adaptive valley. And there's no
称之为适应性山谷。而且没有
guarantee that you make it through the
保证你能顺利完成
adaptive valley. And in fact, the
适应性山谷。事实上，
drawing that we put on the board, I
我们画在黑板上的图，我
think, is overly hopeful because it
认为这是过于乐观，因为它
makes it in two dimensions. It looks
将其转换为二维图像。看起来
like you know exactly where to go to
就像你知道该去哪里一样
climb that next peak. And in fact, it's
攀登下一座山峰。事实上，正是如此。
more like the peaks are islands in an
更像是山峰是岛屿。
archipelago that is in fog where you
雾气弥漫的群岛，你
can't figure out what direction that
搞不清楚那条路是哪条路。
peak is and you have to reason out it's
巅峰就是巅峰，你需要推理出来。
probably that way and you hope not to
很可能就是这样，而你希望不是这样。
miss it by a few degrees. But in any
差了几度。但在任何情况下
case, that darkness is exactly what you
在这种情况下，那种黑暗正是你所拥有的。
would expect if we were about to
如果我们即将……，我们会预期
discover a better phase for humans. And
探索更适合人类的阶段。和
I think we should be very deliberate
我认为我们应该非常谨慎。
about it this time. I think we should
这次是关于这件事的。我认为我们应该
think carefully about how it is that we
仔细思考一下我们是如何做到这一点的。
do not allow the combination of this
不允许将这两种情况结合起来。
brand new extremely powerful technology
全新超强技术
and market forces to turn this into some
以及市场力量将其转化为某种
new kind of enslavement. And I don't
新型奴役。我没有
think it has to be. I think the
我认为肯定是这样。我认为
potential here does allow us to refactor
这里蕴含的潜力允许我们进行重构
just about everything. Maybe we have
几乎所有东西。或许我们有
finally arrived at the place where
终于到达了目的地
mundane work doesn't need to exist
枯燥乏味的工作并非必要存在。
anymore and the pursuit of meaning can
不再如此，对意义的追求可以
replace it. But that's not going to
替换它。但这不会发生
happen automatically if we don't figure
如果我们不考虑，它就会自动发生。
out how to make it happen. And I hope
找出实现方法。我希望
that we can recognize that the peril of
我们能够认识到这种危险
this moment is best utilized if it
如果能充分利用这一刻……
motivates us to confront that question
这激励我们直面这个问题。
directly.
直接地。
Each one of us has two parents, four
我们每个人都有两个父母，四个
grandparents, eight great-grandparents,
祖父母，八位曾祖父母，
16, 32, 64. You've got this inc like
16、32、64。你已经掌握了这些信息，就像……
this long line of ancestors who all had
这一长串祖先都曾拥有
to meet each other. They all had to
见面。他们都必须
survive wars. They all had to survive
在战争中幸存下来。他们都必须活下去
illness and disease. Everything had to
疾病。一切都必须
happen for us. One, each individual, all
发生在我们身上。一，每个人，所有
of this this stuff had to happen for us
这一切事情的发生对我们来说是必然的。
to get here. And if we think about all
来到这里。如果我们考虑所有因素
the people in those thousands and
那成千上万的人
thousands of people, every single one of
成千上万的人，每一个人
them would trade places in a heartbeat
他们俩会毫不犹豫地交换位置。
if they had the opportunity to be alive
如果他们有机会活下来的话
at this particular moment. They would
在这一刻。他们会
say that their life was struggle,
他们说他们的生活充满艰辛，
disease, that their life was a lot of
疾病，他们的生活充满了……
mundane and meaningless work. It was
枯燥乏味、毫无意义的工作。那是
dangerous. You know, every single one of
危险的。你知道，每一个
us has probably got ancestors that were
我们可能有一些祖先是
enslaved, probably got ancestors that
被奴役的人，可能他们的祖先是这样的。
died too young, uh, probably got
死得太年轻了，呃，可能……
ancestors that worked horrific
祖先们从事着可怕的工作
conditions. We all have that. And they
状况。我们每个人都有这种情况。他们
would all just look at this moment and
所有人都会注视着这一刻
say, "Wow." So, are you telling me that
说：“哇。”所以，你的意思是说……
you have the ability to solve meaningful
你有能力解决有意义的问题。
problems, to come up with adventures, to
问题，构思冒险，到
travel the world, to pick the brains of
环游世界，汲取智慧
anyone on the planet that you want to
地球上任何你想去的地方
pick the brains of? You can just listen
向谁请教？你可以直接听。
to a podcast. You can just watch a
到播客节目中。你可以观看
video. You can talk to an AI. Like, are
视频。你可以和人工智能对话。比如，是
you telling me that you're alive at this
你告诉我你现在还活着
particular moment? Please make the most
某个特定的时刻？请充分利用
of that. Like, do something with that.
就是那件事。比如，利用它做点什么。
You know, you can sit around
你知道，你可以坐着
pontificating about society and how
大谈社会及其运作方式
society might work. But ultimately, it
社会或许能够运转起来。但归根结底，它
all boils down to what you do with this
这一切都取决于你如何利用它。
moment. and solving meaningful problems,
片刻。解决有意义的问题，
being brave, having fun, making your
勇敢一点，玩得开心一点，创造你的
little dent in the universe. You know,
宇宙中微不足道的凹痕。你知道，
that's that's what it's all about. And I
这就是问题的关键所在。我
feel like there's an obligation to your
感觉自己对你负有义务
ancestors to make the most of the
祖先们充分利用了
moment.
片刻。
Thank you so much to everybody for being
非常感谢大家！
here. I I've learned a lot and I've
这里。我学到了很多，而且我
developed my thinking, which is much the
培养了我的思维能力，这非常重要
reason why I wanted to bring us all
这就是我想把我们所有人带到这里的原因
together because I know you all have
聚在一起，因为我知道你们都有
different experiences, different
不同的经历，不同的
backgrounds in education. and you're
教育背景。而你是
doing different things, but together it
做着不同的事情，但在一起
helps me sort of pass through all of
这让我能够顺利度过所有难关。
these ideas to figure out where I land.
这些想法是为了弄清楚我最终会落脚在哪里。
And I I I ask a lot of questions, but I
我问了很多问题，但是
am actually a believer in humans. I'm I
其实我还是相信人性的。我是我
I was thinking about this a second ago.
我刚才还在想这件事呢。
I was thinking, do I am I optimistic
我在想，我算乐观吗？
about humans ability to navigate this
关于人类应对这种情况的能力
just because I have no other choice?
就因为我别无选择吗？
Because as you said, the alternative
正如你所说，另一种选择是……
actually isn't worth thinking about. And
其实根本不值得考虑。和
so I do have a optimism towards how I
所以我对我的未来抱有乐观态度。
think we're going to navigate this in
我认为我们将通过以下方式解决这个问题
part because we're having these kinds of
部分原因是，我们正在经历这类事情
conversations and we in history haven't
对话，以及我们在历史上的种种经历，都表明我们从未有过这样的经历。
always had them at the birth of a new
每次新生儿出生时都会有它们
revolution when we think about social
当我们思考社会革命时
media and the implications that had.
媒体及其影响。
We're playing catchup with the with the
我们正在努力追赶……
downstream
下游
consequences. And I am hopeful. Maybe
结果。我抱有希望。或许
that's the entrepreneur in me. I'm
这就是我身上的企业家精神。我是
excited. Maybe that's also the
兴奋的。或许那也是……
entrepreneur in me. But at the same
我内心深处住着一个企业家。但与此同时
time, to many of the points Brett's
时间，对布雷特的许多观点来说
raised and Amjud's raised and Dan's
举起了，Amjud 举起了，Dan 的
raised, there are serious considerations
提出这个问题，需要考虑一些重要因素。
as we swim from one island to another.
我们从一个岛屿游到另一个岛屿。
And because of the speed and scale of
正是由于速度和规模
this transformation that Brett
布雷特的这种转变
highlights and you look at the stats of
精彩集锦，然后你查看统计数据
the growth of this technology and how
这项技术的发展及其
it's spreading like wildfire and how
它像野火一样蔓延，而且蔓延速度如此之快。
once I tried Replet, I walked straight
我试过Replet之后，就径直走​​了。
out and I told Cozy immediately I was
出去后，我立刻告诉了科齐我
like, "Cussie, try this." And she was on
比如，“库西，试试这个。”她当时就在
it and she was hooked. And then I called
她被迷住了。然后我打电话
my girlfriend in Bali who's the breath
我在巴厘岛的女朋友，她就是我的呼吸
work practitioner and I was like, "Type
工作实践者，我当时就想，“类型
this into your browser. R E P L I T."
将此内容粘贴到您的浏览器中。复制。
And then she's making these breath work
然后她开始做这些呼吸练习
schedules with all of her clients
安排与所有客户的日程
information ahead of the retreat she's
她提前获悉了静修的信息
about to do. It's spreading like
即将开始。它正在像这样蔓延
wildfire because we're internet native.
因为我们是互联网原住民，所以野火才会蔓延。
We were native to this technology. So
我们天生就熟悉这项技术。所以
it's not a new technology. It's
这不是一项新技术。它是
something on top of something that's
在某物之上还有另一物
intuitive to us. So that transition, as
我们觉得这很直观。因此，这种转变，作为
Brett describes it, from one peak to the
布雷特这样描述它，从一个山峰到
other or one island to another, I think
我觉得，从一个岛屿到另一个岛屿，或者说从一个岛屿到另一个岛屿。
is going to be incredibly destabilizing.
这将造成极大的不稳定。
And I've having interviewed so many
我已经采访过很多人
leaders in this space from Reed Hoffman
里德·霍夫曼是该领域的领导者之一
who's the founder of LinkedIn to the CEO
从LinkedIn创始人到首席执行官
of Google to Mustafa who I mentioned
谷歌向我提到的穆斯塔法表示感谢。
they don't agree on much but the thing
他们在很多事情上都意见不合，但这件事例外。
that they all agree on and that Sam
他们都同意这一点，而且是山姆
Alman agrees on is that the long-term
阿尔曼同意的一点是，从长远来看……
future the long-term way that our
我们未来长期发展的方式
society functions is radically
社会功能从根本上来说是
different. People squab squabble over
不同的。人们为此争吵不休。
the short term. They sometimes even
短期。他们有时甚至
squabble over the midterm or the
关于中期考试的争吵或
timeline but they all agree that the
时间线，但他们都同意
future is going to look completely
未来将会完全不同
different. Amjud, thank you for doing
不同的。 Amjud，谢谢你这么做
what you're doing. you're what we didn't
你在做什么。你是我们曾经没有的
get to spend a lot of time on it today
今天有很多时间可以花在这上面。
and this is typically what I do here but
这就是我在这里通常的做法，但
your story is incredibly inspiring
你的故事非常鼓舞人心。
incredibly inspiring from where you came
你来自的地方真是太鼓舞人心了
from what you've done what you're
从你所做的一切来看，你是什么
building and you are democratizing and
建设，你正在实现民主化，
creating a level of playing field for
为……创造公平的竞争环境
entrepreneurs in Bangladesh to Cape Town
孟加拉国的企业家前往开普敦
to San Francisco to be able to turn
前往旧金山以便能够转向
their ideas into reality and I do think
将他们的想法变成现实，而且我确实这么认为
just on the surface that that's such a
仅仅从表面上看，这真是……
wonderful thing that you know I was born
你知道我出生是多么美好的一件事
in Botswana in in Africa and that I
在非洲的博茨瓦纳，我
could have the same access to turn my
可能拥有同样的权限来改变我的
imagination into something to change my
将想象力转化为改变我的东西
life because of the work that you're
因为你的工作而拥有了生活
doing at Replet. And I highly recommend
在 Replet 上进行。我强烈推荐
everybody go check it out. You you
大家都去看看。你你
probably won't sleep that night because
那天晚上可能睡不着，因为
it's so it's so for someone like me it
对像我这样的人来说，确实如此。
was so addictive to get to be able to do
能够做到这一点真是太让人上瘾了。
that because it's been the barrier to
因为它一直是阻碍
creation my whole life. I've always had
我毕生都在创造。我一直都有
to call someone to build something. Dan,
打电话给某人来建造某物。担，
thank you again so much because you
再次非常感谢你，因为你
represent the voice of entrepreneurs and
代表企业家的声音
you've really become a titan as a a
你真的已经成为一位泰坦了
thought leader for entrepreneurs in the
企业家的思想领袖
UK and that perspective that balance is
英国以及那种认为平衡的观点是
incredibly important. So, I really
极其重要。所以，我真的
really appreciate you being here as
非常感谢您能来这里。
always and you're a huge fan favorite of
一直都是，而且你深受粉丝喜爱
our show and Brett, thank you a
我们的节目和布雷特，谢谢你们。
gazillion times over for being a a human
身为人类，值得无数次的感激。
lens on complicated challenges and you
聚焦复杂挑战，你
do it with a fearlessness that I think
以我认为的无畏精神去做这件事。
is imperative for us finding the truth
这对于我们找到真相至关重要。
in these kind of situations where some
在这种情况下，一些
of us can run off with optimism and we
我们中的一些人可能会被乐观情绪冲昏头脑，而我们
can be hurtling towards the mouse trap
可能正飞速冲向捕鼠器
because we love cheese and I think
因为我们喜欢奶酪，而且我认为
you're an important
你很重要
counterbalance and voice in the world at
在世界上的制衡和发声
this time. So, thank all of you for
这次。所以，谢谢大家。
being here. I really really appreciate
身处此地。我真的很感激
it and um we shall
它，嗯，我们将
see. These things live forever.
看。这些事物将永存。
So, this has always blown my mind a
所以，这件事一直让我感到震惊。
little bit. 53% of you that listen to
一点。 53% 的听众
this show regularly haven't yet
这个节目经常还没有播出。
subscribed to the show. So, could I ask
已订阅该节目。那么，我可以问一下吗？
you for a favor? If you like the show
能帮个忙吗？如果你喜欢这个节目
and you like what we do here and you
你喜欢我们在这里做的事情，你
want to support us, the free simple way
想支持我们吗？免费又简单的方式！
that you can do just that is by hitting
你可以通过点击来做到这一点。
the subscribe button. And my commitment
订阅按钮。我的承诺
to you is if you do that, then I'll do
对你来说，如果你那样做，那么我也会那样做。
everything in my power, me and my team,
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
to make sure that this show is better
为了确保这个节目更好
for you every single week. We'll listen
每周都为您准备。我们会听的。
to your feedback. We'll find the guests
感谢您的反馈。我们会找到客人。
that you want me to speak to, and we'll
你想让我跟谁谈谈，我们就会
continue to do what we do. Thank you so
继续做我们正在做的事情。非常感谢
much.
很多。
[Music]
[音乐]